[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
大卫·马兰：好的，这是 CS50。
And this is already week nine.
这已经是第九周了。
And this means this is the week where we synthesize
这意味着，本周我们将整合
the past several weeks, from Python to SQL to HTML to CSS to JavaScript.
过去几周学习过的知识，从 Python 到 SQL，从 HTML 到 CSS，再到 JavaScript。
Each of those languages that we've rather looked at in isolation
我们之前单独学习的每一种语言
now rather come together toward an end of just making
现在将结合在一起，最终目标是创建
more modern applications, be them web based or be they mobile based as well.
更多现代化的应用程序，无论是基于 Web 的还是基于移动设备的。
So, up until now, we've been using, to serve all of the web stuff
所以，到目前为止，我们一直在使用一个名为 HTTP server 的程序来处理所有的 Web 内容
that you've done, this program called HTTP server.
你所做的所有 Web 工作。
Now, this isn't a CS50 thing.
现在，这不是 CS50 的东西。
It's just a standard program that we've installed into Codespaces.
它只是一个我们安装到 Codespaces 的标准程序。
So it's a Linux program that just runs your own web server.
所以它是一个 Linux 程序，它可以运行你自己的 Web 服务器。
And it allows you to run it on nonstandard ports.
它允许你在非标准端口上运行它。
For instance, you've been using it on port 80, 80
例如，你一直在端口 80 上使用它，80
only because Codespaces is using 80 and 443, recall, which were the defaults.
仅仅是因为 Codespaces 使用了 80 和 443，你还记得吧，那是默认的。
But, up until now, this program's purpose in life
但是，到目前为止，这个程序存在的意义
was just to serve static content, so like web pages written in HTML,
只是提供静态内容，比如用 HTML 编写的网页，
maybe some CSS, maybe some JavaScript that you wrote in advance
可能还有一些 CSS，一些你事先写好的 JavaScript 代码
that just never really changes until such time
这些代码在你不登录服务器并保存文件进行编辑之前，都不会改变。
as you log back into the server, save the file after making some edits,
直到你登录回服务器，修改完文件后保存它。
and then someone reloads their page.
然后有人重新加载他们的页面。
But, of course, the web that we all use today, be it Gmail or any website,
但是，当然，我们今天使用的网络，无论是 Gmail 还是任何网站，
is so much more interactive.
都是更加交互式的。
When you search for something on Google, there's
当你搜索一些东西时，谷歌上
no Google engineer that, in advance, has written up an HTML
没有谷歌工程师事先编写好一个 HTML 页面
page containing a list of 10 cats or 10 dogs
包含 10 只猫或 10 只狗的列表
or 10 birds just waiting for someone to search for that particular keyword.
或 10 只鸟，仅仅等待着有人搜索那个特定的关键字。
Rather, there's some database involved.
相反，这里涉及到一个数据库。
The HTML's being dynamically generated.
HTML 页面是动态生成的。
And it's all indeed very dynamic.
而且，它确实是动态的。
So whereas, last week, we focused on websites,
所以，上周，我们专注于网站，
this week we'll focus really on web applications.
本周我们将重点关注 Web 应用程序。
And, really, the key difference is just that applications
实际上，关键区别在于，应用程序
take input and produce output whereas websites are really generally thought
接收输入并产生输出，而网站通常被认为是
of as static.
静态的。
But it's a blurry line.
但这是一个模糊的界限。
It's not necessarily a technical distinction.
这并不一定是一个技术上的区别。
But today things start to get much more interactive.
但今天，事情开始变得更加交互式。
So we're not going to be able to use HTTP server alone.
所以我们不能仅仅使用 HTTP 服务器。
We're going to need something a little smarter that knows how
我们需要一些更智能的东西，它知道如何
to take input from users via the URL.
通过 URL 接收用户的输入。
So, in fact, let's look at some sample URLs that we looked at last week
实际上，让我们看看上周我们看过的几个示例 URL
just to remind ourselves of some of the jargon and really the syntax.
来提醒我们一些术语，以及语法。
So here's a standard URL and Flask, recall,
所以这是一个标准的 URL，你还记得 Flask 吗？
is just the default page on the server.
它只是服务器上的默认页面。
And, usually, the file is called index.html by convention.
通常，根据约定，这个文件被称为 index.html。
But, depending on the operating system or web server you're using,
但是，这取决于你使用的操作系统或 web 服务器，
it could be a different file.
它可能是一个不同的文件。
But index.html is probably the most common default.
但 index.html 可能是最常见的默认文件。
So you could explicitly state the file name on most web servers
因此，你可以在大多数 web 服务器上明确指定文件名
like file.html, index.html, whatever it is.
例如 file.html、index.html 等等。
You can have folders or directories on a web server.
你可以在 web 服务器上创建文件夹或目录。
And this would imply that your index.html file is
这意味着你的 index.html 文件位于
in a folder called folder in this case.
在本例中，一个名为 folder 的文件夹中。
Or you can have a folder/file or even folder/folder/folder/file and so forth.
或者，你可以创建文件夹/文件，甚至是文件夹/文件夹/文件夹/文件，等等。
So this is a very direct mapping from the URL to the file system,
所以这是一种从 URL 到文件系统的直接映射，
so to speak, like the hard drive on the server.
可以这样说，就像服务器上的硬盘驱动器一样。
But, today, we're going to do, like most computer scientists tend to do,
但是，今天我们将做大多数计算机科学家通常做的事情，
is more of an abstraction of this.
对它进行更抽象的处理。
This is how URLs look.
这就是 URL 的外观。
But it turns out, once you control the web server with code,
但事实证明，一旦你用代码控制 web 服务器，
you don't need things to line up with actual file names and files.
你就不需要将它们与实际的文件名和文件对齐。
You can really put your content wherever you want.
你可以将内容放在任何你想要的地方。
And so, in general, we're going to focus today
因此，总的来说，我们今天将重点关注
on just thinking of everything after the domain name as a path,
将域名后面的所有内容视为路径，
generally speaking.
一般来说。
And a synonym for this, in the context of the web, would also just be a route.
在 web 环境中，这个的同义词就是路由。
So a route is just some number of letters, maybe some slashes, maybe
因此，路由只是一些字母，可能是一些斜杠，也可能
a file extension that refers to some part of your application.
是一个文件扩展名，它指向你应用程序的一部分。
But, more interestingly-- and this is what makes things an application
但更有趣的是，这使得它们成为一个应用程序，
and not just a static website--
而不仅仅是一个静态网站。
recall, that this is how websites can take input
回想一下，这就是网站接受输入的方式，
in the form of URLs, a question mark, then key equals value pair.
以 URL 的形式，一个问号，然后是键值对。
Or if you want two or maybe three or four,
或者如果你想要两个、三个或四个，
you separate them with ampersands.
你就用 "&" 符号将它们隔开。
But that's kind of it.
但就是这样了。
The web today is going to work just like it did last week,
如今的 web 工作方式和上周一样，
but we're going to start leveraging these primitives in a much
但我们将开始以更强大的方式利用这些基本元素，
more powerful, more interactive way.
更具互动性。
So here, recall, is what might be inside of the virtual envelope
所以，回想一下，当你搜索 google.com 上的东西时，虚拟信封里可能包含什么。
when you search for something on google.com.
当你搜索 google.com 上的东西时，
It's going to request of the web server/search, which
它将向 web 服务器/搜索发出请求，它
is the name, by convention, of Google's search application
根据惯例，是 Google 搜索应用程序的名称
because they've got a lot of businesses running on their servers.
因为他们在服务器上运行着许多业务。
And if you have ?q=cats, this is essentially the message,
如果你有 ?q=cats，这本质上就是消息，
the HTTP message that would've been in last week's virtual envelope when I
上周我搜索 cats 时，那个虚拟信封中包含的 HTTP 消息。
searched for cats.
搜索 cats 时，
Hopefully, you get back a response from the server
希望你能收到服务器的回复
containing those actual cats.
包含那些实际的猫。
But, again, there's probably a lot more logic going on with a database
但再次强调，可能还有更多逻辑与数据库一起运作
and somehow generating that HTML that Google is doing for us.
并以某种方式生成 Google 为我们生成的 HTML 代码。
So we, today, are going to introduce really
因此，今天我们将真正介绍
what's called a framework or technically a microframework, which
一种名为框架，或者更准确地说，微框架的东西，它
means it's relatively small versus alternatives that are out there.
这意味着它相对较小，与市面上的其他替代方案相比。
And it's called Flask.
它被称为Flask。
So Flask is really a third-party library--
所以Flask实际上是一个第三方库——
and it's popular in the Python world-- that's
它在Python世界中很流行——就是说
just going to make it easier to implement web applications using
它将使使用Python实现web应用程序变得更容易。
Python.
Python。
There are alternatives.
还有其他替代方案。
A very popular one is called Django, which some of you
一个非常流行的叫做Django，你们中有些人
might've heard of before.
可能之前听说过。
And there's dozens of others in decreasing popularity daresay.
还有几十个其他，按照流行度递减。
But Flask is among the most popular microframeworks,
但是Flask是最流行的微框架之一，
which means you can really just solve a few problems pretty
这意味着你实际上可以非常简单地解决几个问题
simply without feeling like you're learning some third-party library
简单地，而不会感觉自己在学习一些第三方库
as much as you are learning concepts that transcend
就像你在学习超越
one particular implementation.
特定实现的理念一样。
So we're going to introduce you to a framework called Flask.
所以我们将向大家介绍一个名为Flask的框架。
And that's going to allow us, ultimately,
这将最终让我们
to start web applications not by running HTTP server today
启动web应用程序，不是通过运行今天的HTTP服务器
but literally running flask space run.
而是通过运行flask run。
So this framework literally gives you a command,
所以这个框架实际上给你一个命令，
on your Mac, your PC, your codespace once it's installed,
在你的Mac、PC或codespace上，一旦安装好，
that allows you to start a web server by running
就可以通过运行命令启动web服务器
flask run instead of HTTP server.
flask run，而不是HTTP服务器。
So, again, last week, it was all about static websites.
所以，再说一次，上周，我们谈论的都是静态网站。
This week, it's all about dynamic websites instead.
本周，我们谈论的是动态网站。
And, by framework, we really generally mean-- not just
而框架，我们通常指的是——不仅仅是
using some third-party code but third-party conventions
使用一些第三方代码，而是第三方约定
that just some human or humans decided is the way
一些人或人们认为是构建应用程序的方式
you will build your applications.
你将构建你的应用程序。
Usually, this is just based on lessons learned after making application
通常，这只是基于在构建应用程序之后吸取的教训
after application.
之后得出的教训。
Humans around the internet realized, you know what?
互联网上的开发人员意识到，你知道吗？
We should probably standardize the names of our files, the names of our folders,
我们应该将文件和文件夹的名字进行规范化，
and how things are laid out.
以及如何布局。
And so, even though this is not the only way to do things,
所以，即使这不是唯一的做法，
the way that Flask prescribes that we programmers do things is this.
Flask 规定程序员应该按照以下方式进行操作。
We'll, starting today, always have a Python program called app.py
从今天开始，我们将始终有一个名为 app.py 的 Python 程序
by convention, like in our folder.
按照约定，就像在我们的文件夹中一样。
And we're going to have a folder called templates, inside of which
我们还将有一个名为 templates 的文件夹，里面包含
is any of the actual HTML, maybe CSS, maybe JavaScript that we write.
我们编写的任何实际的 HTML、CSS 或 JavaScript 代码。
But you can actually put some of that content elsewhere.
但是你实际上可以将其中一些内容放在其他地方。
And, in fact, you'll see there's going to be generally
事实上，你会看到通常
two other files or folders you'll see me create or me use today.
还有两个其他文件或文件夹你会看到我今天创建或使用。
One is called requirements.txt, which is literally just a simple text
一个是 requirements.txt，它实际上只是一个简单的文本
file wherein you specify one per line what third-party libraries
文件，你可以在其中一行一行地指定要使用的第三方库
you want to use.
你想要使用。
This file just makes it easy to install those libraries with a command.
这个文件使用命令安装这些库变得容易。
And then, lastly, a static folder.
然后，最后，还有一个静态文件夹。
And it's in this folder that you put images or .css files or .js files,
在这个文件夹中，你可以存放图片或.css文件、.js文件，
literally files that are meant to be static that you might change them once
字面意思是，这些文件是静态的，你可能偶尔会修改它们
in a while, but they're not changing every day.
但它们不是每天都在变化。
And so you just want to isolate them to a particular folder.
所以你只需要将它们隔离到一个特定的文件夹中。
Why is it this way?
为什么是这样呢？
Eh, a bunch of humans decided this feels like a clean solution.
嗯，很多人都认为这是一个干净的解决方案。
But reasonable people will disagree and different frameworks lay things out
但是，明智的人会不同意，不同的框架会有不同的布局
differently.
方式。
So, when using a framework for the first time, you take a class or read a book
所以，当你第一次使用一个框架时，你可以参加一个课程或者阅读一本书
or read the documentation.
或者阅读文档。
And it will essentially guide you to how you should lay out your application.
它基本上会指导你如何布局你的应用程序。
So let's go ahead and do exactly that and make an application that quite
让我们继续做，并创建一个应用程序，它相当
simply and, by design, underwhelmingly implements Hello, world.
简单，并且按设计，平淡地实现了 Hello, world。
But, rather than do this statically, let me
但与其静态地实现，不如让我
do it in a way that starts to use this framework so
用一种开始使用这个框架的方式来实现，这样
that, in the next version of it, we can actually take user input
在它的下一个版本中，我们就可以真正地获取用户的输入
and have it say not Hello, world but maybe Hello,
并让它说，不是 Hello, world，而是 Hello,
David, or Hello, Yulia or anyone else.
David，或 Hello, Yulia，或者其他人。
All right, so let me go over here to VS Code.
好的，让我去 VS Code 上。
And let me go ahead, and, initially, let me start with the familiar.
让我继续，首先，让我从熟悉的开始。
And let me go ahead and start by simply creating the HTML page that I really
让我继续，并从简单地创建一个 HTML 页面开始，这个页面是我真正
want to show to my visitors when they visit my application.
想展示给我的访问者，当他们访问我的应用程序的时候。
So I'm going to go ahead and, somewhat incorrectly, initially,
所以，我将继续，虽然最初有点不正确，
but just to make a point, I'm going to go ahead and do
但为了说明一点，我将继续
code index.html to open up a new tab.
输入代码 index.html 来打开一个新的标签页。
I'll hide my terminal window just to give myself some more room.
我会隐藏我的终端窗口，给自己腾出更多空间。
And then really fast I'm going to type out some boilerplate HTML.
然后，我将快速地输入一些 HTML 模板。
So DOCTYPE html, just like last week, open bracket html Lang equals en just
所以 DOCTYPE html，就像上周一样，打开括号 html Lang 等于 en 仅仅
to tell the VS Code that I'm--
告诉 VS Code 我正在使用...
to tell the web that I'm largely using English here.
告诉网络我在这里主要使用英语。
In the head of my page, I'm going to have, of course, the title of the page.
在我的页面的头部，当然，我会加上页面的标题。
And I'll keep it simple and just say something like hello.
我会保持简单，只写一些类似 hello 的东西。
But just so that this website actually renders nicely on mobile devices,
但为了让这个网站在移动设备上正常渲染，
I'm going to use one of those meta tags we talked briefly
我会使用我们上周简要谈论过的一种元标签
about last week whereby if I say meta name equals viewport--
上周，如果我说 meta name 等于 viewport...
and viewport refers to just the big rectangular region of your browser--
而 viewport 指的是浏览器中那个大的矩形区域...
the content of this meta tag is going to be initial scale
这个元标签的内容将是 initial scale
equals 1 and width equals device width.
等于 1 并且 width 等于 device width。
I always have to copy-paste this or look it up myself.
我总是不得不复制粘贴它或者自己查找。
But this line here essentially tells the browser
但这一行本质上告诉浏览器
that, no matter how wide the device is, whether it's
无论设备有多宽，无论是
a laptop or desktop or maybe a vertical cell phone or tablet,
笔记本电脑、台式电脑，还是垂直的手机或平板电脑，
size the viewport to that device.
将视窗大小调整到该设备的大小。
Otherwise, your website might look super small on mobile devices
否则，您的网站在移动设备上可能会看起来很小
if you don't use this tag to tell the browser, take into account
如果您不使用此标签来告诉浏览器，请考虑
the actual device width rather than shrinking the 12-point font
实际设备宽度，而不是缩小 12 点字体
to something that's hard for folks to read.
使字体难以阅读。
So, for now, I'm just going to generally copy-paste that or type it out
所以，现在，我将一般地复制粘贴或键入它
from my printout here.
从我的打印内容中。
All right, beyond that, we need the body of the page.
好的，除此之外，我们需要页面的主体。
We'll keep that simple.
我们会保持简单。
So body, and then, in here, hello comma world.
所以是主体，然后在里面，hello, world。
So that's it for my website thus far.
到目前为止，我的网站就是这样。
It's static.
它是静态的。
Nothing about this is going to incorporate my name or anyone else's.
这方面不会包含我的名字或任何其他人的名字。
So I could technically use HTTP server to serve up this web page,
所以理论上我可以使用 HTTP 服务器来提供此网页，
open it in a browser, and I would see the actual contents.
在浏览器中打开它，我就可以看到实际内容。
But let's instead create a bit of work for us
但是，让我们为我们自己创造一些工作
and sort of overengineer this problem but to set the stage for actually
并且对这个问题进行过度设计，但为了为实际情况做好准备
taking in dynamic input like a user's name.
接收动态输入，比如用户的姓名。
So let me go ahead and to do this.
所以让我继续做这件事。
I'm going to go ahead and open my terminal window again.
我将继续打开我的终端窗口。
I'm going to close the index.html file.
我将关闭 index.html 文件。
I'm going to make a new directory called templates,
我将创建一个名为 templates 的新目录，
which, again, was the default folder name I
再次，这是我使用的默认文件夹名称
mentioned that this framework expects.
提到的这个框架期望的。
And I'm going to move index.html into that templates folder using mv, a Linux
我将使用 mv（一个 Linux 命令）将 index.html 移动到 templates 文件夹中。
command.
命令。
If you're more comfy, you can open up the file, the File Explorer at right.
如果您更喜欢，您可以打开文件，即右侧的文件资源管理器。
You'll see, in advance, I downloaded a directory.
您将看到，提前，我下载了一个目录。
I'll occasionally borrow content from today called src9,
我偶尔会借用今天名为 src9 的内容，
but there is my templates folder.
但那里是我的 templates 文件夹。
And you could click in the GUI in order to do
您可以在 GUI 中单击以执行
what I just did at the command line.
我在命令行中刚刚执行的操作。
All right, and, after this, let's go ahead and create one other file,
好的，在此之后，让我们继续创建另一个文件，
app.py.
app.py。
And, in app.py, let me go ahead now and do this.
在 app.py 中，让我现在继续执行此操作。
I'm going to import some functions that come with this framework called Flask.
我将导入一些与名为 Flask 的框架一起提供的函数。
So I'm going to say from flask, in lowercase, import Flask, capital F,
所以我要说，从 flask（小写）导入 Flask（大写 F），
and also a function called render template and an object called request.
以及一个名为 render_template 的函数和一个名为 request 的对象。
Now, how to do this?
现在，如何做到这一点？
You literally read the documentation, or you listen to someone
您可以直接阅读文档，或者听别人
like me tell you to begin your program this way.
像我一样告诉您以这种方式开始您的程序。
In the Flask framework comes three pieces of functionality
Flask 框架提供了三个功能模块
that are just useful to incorporate into my own program as we're about to see.
它们对我的程序非常有用，正如我们即将看到的那样。
Here's the line of code via which I can tell this framework
这是一行代码，通过它我可以告诉这个框架
to treat my file, app.py, as indeed a web application.
将我的文件 app.py 视为一个 Web 应用程序。
I create a variable, typically called app.
我创建了一个变量，通常称为 app。
I set that equal to the return value of calling
我将其设置为调用
this Flask function and pass in it, somewhat weirdly,
Flask 函数的返回值，并以某种奇怪的方式传递到其中，
the name of this file.
这个文件的名字。
So this is the only weird thing for now in that we haven't used this much,
所以目前为止唯一奇怪的是，我们还没有使用它很多，
if at all. __name__ is a special variable in Python that literally
如果有的话。__name__ 是 Python 中的一个特殊变量，它实际上
refers to the current file's name, no matter what file name you gave it.
指的是当前文件的名字，无论你给它起了什么名字。
So it's a nice way of referring to yourself
所以这是指代你自己的好方法
without manually typing the file name, which might change down the line.
而不必手动输入文件名，因为文件名可能会在以后发生变化。
And then, lastly, I'm going to do this.
最后，我要做这个。
And this is one other piece of new syntax for now.
而这是目前为止另一个新的语法。
I'm going to use an @ and say app.route.
我将使用一个 @ 并说 app.route。
And then in quotes, as an argument to this route function,
然后在引号中，作为此 route 函数的参数，
I'm going to specify the route for which I'm implementing some code
我将指定我要实现一些代码的路由
/ being the default, by convention.
/ 是默认值，这是约定俗成的。
I'm going to define immediately below that a function
我将立即在下面定义一个函数
that I can technically call anything I want,
从技术上来说，我可以给它起任何名字，
but I'm going to get in the habit of using reasonable defaults.
但我要养成使用合理默认值的习惯。
So I'm going to call this function index by default.
所以默认情况下，我将这个函数命名为 index。
But that's not a hard requirement.
但这并不是硬性要求。
And then, inside of this function, I'm simply
然后，在这个函数里面，我只是
going to return this, return "hello, world", quote, unquote.
要返回这个，返回 "hello, world"，引号。
And that's it.
就是这样。
This I now claim is a beginning of an actual web application.
我现在声称，这是一个真正的 Web 应用程序的开始。
It looks a little magical or cryptic as to what's going on.
看起来有点神奇或神秘，不知道发生了什么。
But, per the jargon I introduced earlier, this function here app.route
但是，根据我之前介绍的术语，这里这个函数 app.route
is defining a route for this application that
为这个应用程序定义了一个路由，
implies that whenever a human visit slash
这意味着只要一个人访问斜杠
on this application, what should happen is
在这个应用程序上，应该发生的事情是
this function index should get called.
这个函数 index 应该被调用。
And that function's purpose in life, at the moment,
而这个函数目前存在的意义
is just to return, quote, unquote, "hello, world", and that's it.
就是返回 "hello, world"，就这样。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这个。
Let me open my terminal and just to keep everything
让我打开我的终端，为了保持所有东西
clean because we're going to have a bunch of applications
干净，因为我们今天会有一堆应用程序
today in the works.
正在进行中。
I'm going to create one other folder called hello.
我将创建一个名为 hello 的文件夹。
And I'm going to move app.py and templates into that hello folder.
我将把 app.py 和 templates 移动到 hello 文件夹中。
So if I now type ls in my own personal account,
所以，如果我现在在我的个人帐户中输入 ls，
I've got that folder hello and also src9, which I brought with me today.
我拥有那个名为 hello 的文件夹，还有 src9，我今天把它带来了。
So if I now cd into hello and type ls again,
所以如果我现在 cd 到 hello 并再次输入 ls，
I'll see the two things we just created together, app.py
我将看到我们一起创建的两个东西，app.py
and the templates folder.
和 templates 文件夹。
And if I go one step further in ls templates itself,
如果我在 ls templates 本身中再往前走一步，
I should see, of course, index.html.
我当然应该看到 index.html。
All right, so a lot of steps to go through just to get started.
好吧，所以要启动，需要经历很多步骤。
But you'll see that this is fairly boilerplate eventually.
但你最终会看到，这相当于是模板。
I'm not going to run an HTTP server, but I
我不会运行一个 HTTP 服务器，但是我
am going to run flask run, which will turn this app.py into a working web
将运行 flask run，它将把这个 app.py 变成一个可工作的 Web
application.
应用程序。
The output after I hit Enter is going to look a little more cryptic.
我按下回车键后的输出会更难懂一些。
It's going to warn me this is a development server.
它会警告我这是一个开发服务器。
You should not use that same command in the real world.
你不应该在真实世界中使用相同的命令。
You should actually configure Flask a little differently if you're
如果你打算在现实世界中使用它，你实际上应该对 Flask 进行一些不同的配置。
going to use it in the real world.
But it does show me the random URL that GitHub created for me.
但它确实向我展示了 GitHub 为我创建的随机 URL。
And I'm going to go ahead and open this URL.
我将继续打开这个 URL。
It's going to open in a new tab.
它将在一个新标签页中打开。
And, voila, that is my web application.
瞧，这就是我的 Web 应用程序。
Completely underwhelming, but you'll notice
完全乏善可陈，但你会注意到
that, even though Chrome is hiding this, this
即使 Chrome 隐藏了它，但这个
is the equivalent of my having visited at the end of this URL simply a slash.
等同于我在这个 URL 的末尾访问了一个简单的斜杠。
All right, if I zoom out here, though, and maybe right-click or Control-click,
好吧，如果我在这里缩小，也许右键单击或 Control-单击，
and I choose View page source--
然后我选择查看页面源代码 -
recall, this is available in most every browser--
回想一下，这在大多数浏览器中都可用 -
you'll see that this isn't actually HTML because, at the moment,
你会看到这实际上不是 HTML，因为目前，
I'm literally just returning, quote, unquote, "hello, world".
我实际上只是返回了引号中的“hello, world”。
So, yes, it's text.
所以，是的，它是文本。
It's being rendered as a web page.
它正在被渲染为一个网页。
But it's not technically a web page that has valid HTML.
但从技术上讲，它不是一个具有有效 HTML 的网页。
So what I'm going to do here is this.
所以我要做的是这个。
I'm going to go back into VS Code.
我将回到 VS Code。
I'm going to open a second terminal by clicking
我将通过点击打开第二个终端
the plus icon toward the bottom right of my screen,
屏幕右下角的加号，
just so I can keep the server running.
这样我就可以让服务器保持运行。
But-- actually, nope, let me go ahead and do this.
但是 - 实际上，不，让我继续这样做。
Let me kill this terminal.
让我关闭这个终端。
Let me actually-- oops, I killed the wrong one.
让我实际 - 哎呀，我关错了。
Let me instead go into my hello directory again.
让我回到我的 hello 目录。
Let me open up app.py.
让我打开 app.py。
And this time, instead of saying hello, world, let me do this.
这一次，与其说 hello, world，不如让我这样做。
I want to return the contents of index.html,
我想返回 index.html 的内容，
which is that whole file I created, but I can't just specify its file name.
这是我创建的整个文件，但我不能仅仅指定它的文件名。
But I can do this.
但我可以这样做。
I can call a function called render_template,
我可以调用一个名为 render_template 的函数，
which comes with Flask.
它随 Flask 一起提供。
And its purpose in life is to go get that file from a folder
它的作用是从一个名为 templates 的文件夹中获取该文件
called templates, open it up and then send
打开它，然后发送
all of those bytes, all of those characters
所有这些字节，所有这些字符
to the user's actual browser.
到用户的实际浏览器。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续这样做。
Let me open my terminal again.
让我重新打开我的终端。
Let me do flask run inside of this same folder hello.
让我在这个相同的 hello 文件夹中运行 flask run。
I'm now going to go back to my tab here, click Reload,
我现在将回到我的标签页，点击重新加载，
and nothing appears to have changed.
并且似乎没有任何变化。
But if I right-click and choose View source this time after reloading,
但如果我在重新加载后右键单击并选择查看源代码，
now you'll see all of the HTML that I composed.
现在你将看到我编写的全部 HTML。
All right, so this has taken way more steps
好吧，所以这需要更多步骤
to do what we achieved by just running HTTP server last week.
来完成我们上周仅仅通过运行 HTTP 服务器所实现的功能。
But here's where now things can get a little interesting, whereby
但现在事情变得有趣起来，因为
now that we have this framework laid out,
现在我们已经建立了这个框架，
we can actually introduce other features of the framework
我们实际上可以引入框架的其他功能
to make things more dynamic.
让事情更加动态。
So, for instance, what I'm going to do is this.
例如，我要做的是：
I'm going to now introduce a feature of that variable
我现在要引入该变量的一个功能，
that I also imported called request, which refers to any HTTP request.
我之前也导入了一个叫做请求的变量，它指的是任何 HTTP 请求。
And it turns out, there's a property inside
事实证明，它内部有一个属性
of there called args, which is actually going
叫做 args，实际上会
to be a dictionary of all of the key value pairs
成为所有键值对的字典，
that the human might've provided via the URL.
用户可能通过 URL 提供这些键值对。
So I don't have to figure out, how do I find the thing after the question mark?
所以我不用考虑，怎么才能在问号后面找到那个东西？
I don't have to worry about parsing the ampersands.
我不用担心解析和号。
Flask does all of that for me and just hands
Flask 为我完成了所有这些工作，并直接将
me anything after the URL in a Python dictionary instead.
URL 后面的任何内容以 Python 字典的形式传递给我。
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and hide the terminal.
让我隐藏终端。
But, in app.py, let me go ahead and make a relatively simple change.
但在 app.py 中，让我做一个相对简单的更改。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我这样做。
Let me go ahead and open up in my hello folder, let me open up index.html.
让我打开我的 hello 文件夹，让我打开 index.html。
And let me go ahead and get rid of world and just put a placeholder here.
让我把 world 去掉，在这里放一个占位符。
Using curly brackets, two of them, on the left and right,
使用大括号，左右各两个，
I'm going to go ahead and plug in a variable like name.
我要插入一个叫做 name 的变量。
So here's now where I'm treating index.html not as literally
所以现在我将 index.html 不再视为一个字面意义上的
an HTML page anymore, but more as a template in the literal sense.
HTML 页面，而是更像一个字面意义上的模板。
So a template is kind of like a blueprint whereby
所以模板就像蓝图一样，通过它
you can construct most of what you want the human to see but then
你可以构建你想让用户看到的大部分内容，然后
leave little placeholders in, a la a blueprint
在里面留下一些占位符，就像蓝图一样
where you can fill in certain blanks.
你可以填入一些空白。
The double curly quotes here is actually a feature
这里的双大括号实际上是一个功能
of technically another language-- it's not
在技术上是另一种语言的功能，它不是
a programming language-- called Jinja.
一门编程语言，它叫做 Jinja。
But Jinja is simply a language that a bunch of other humans
但是 Jinja 仅仅是一种语言，很多其他的人
came up with that standardizes what syntax
发明了这种语言，它标准化了你可以使用的语法
you can use for these placeholders and some other features as well.
用于这些占位符和其他一些功能。
So this is going to happen more and more as you progress more
所以，随着你在编程和计算机科学方面的进步，这种情况会越来越多。
in programming and CS.
在编程和计算机科学方面的进步，这种情况会越来越多。
It's not going to be as simple as, oh, I'm implementing something in Python.
它不会像这样简单，哦，我在 Python 中实现了一些东西。
Or, oh, I'm implementing something in C. It's generally going to be,
或者，哦，我在 C 中实现了一些东西。通常来说，
oh, I'm implementing something with this full stack of software,
哦，我在这个完整的软件堆栈中实现了一些东西，
including HTML, CSS, Python, some SQL, some Jinja, and so forth.
包括 HTML、CSS、Python、一些 SQL、一些 Jinja，等等。
So into your vocabulary is now going to generally come a list of technologies
所以你的词汇里现在通常会包含你用来解决问题的技术列表，
that you're using when solving some problem, no
不再是单独的语言。
longer individual languages.
So, by this, I just mean this.
所以，我的意思是，就是这样。
The Flask framework took a look around the internet and saw,
Flask 框架在互联网上四处查看，发现
OK, the humans at the Jinja group came up
好吧，Jinja 小组的人想出了
with a nice simple syntax for putting placeholders in.
一个简单而简洁的语法，用于放置占位符。
Let's support that syntax in Flask.
让我们在 Flask 中支持这种语法。
So it's sort of one framework collaborating with another.
所以这有点像一个框架与另一个框架之间的协作。
So if I go back to app.py now, how do I actually pass from my application
所以，如果我现在回到 app.py，我如何将我的应用程序中
to that template whatever the human has typed in?
输入的内容传递到模板？
Well, it turns out I can go ahead and do this.
事实证明，我可以继续这样做。
Let me go ahead and in my index function, which, again,
让我在 index 函数中，再次
is what's going to get called anytime someone visits that slash route,
是每次有人访问斜杠路由时会被调用的函数，
I'm going to go ahead and create a variable called name.
我将创建一个名为 name 的变量。
I'm going to set it equal to requests.args.
我将它设置为等于 requests.args。
And then I'm going to go ahead and say, how about, quote, unquote, "name".
然后我将继续说，如何，引号，引号，"name"。
I claimed, a moment ago, that args is a dictionary that
我之前说过，args 是一个字典，它
just comes automatically with Flask and whenever
会自动与 Flask 配合使用，并且每当
a human makes a request to the server, and it
人类向服务器发出请求时，它
puts in that dictionary all of the key value pairs from the URL.
会将 URL 中所有键值对放入该字典中。
And the last thing I'm going to do here is this.
我要做的最后一件事是这个。
I'm going to actually say-- and, actually, just let
我实际上会说 - 并且，实际上，让我
me make this more explicit.
更明确一点。
Let me call this placeholder literally placeholder.
让我把这个占位符称为占位符。
And what I'm going to do now is, in render template,
我现在要做的就是在渲染模板中
I'm going to take advantage of one other feature that comes with this function.
利用这个函数的另一个功能。
It can take one or more arguments.
它可以接受一个或多个参数。
And if you pass in more, you can specify variables
如果你传入更多，你可以指定变量
that you want the function to have access to.
你想让函数访问。
So I can literally do something like this, placeholder equals name.
所以我可以直接这样做，placeholder 等于 name。
So recall that Python supports named parameters, which
请记住，Python 支持命名参数，即
just means that you can pass in multiple arguments to a function.
意味着你可以向函数传递多个参数。
But you can specify them by name.
但是你可以按名称指定它们。
So I am calling one of these arguments placeholder.
所以我在调用其中一个参数占位符。
And I'm setting the value of that argument
我正在设置该参数的值
equal to name, which itself is a variable that I
等于 name，它本身是一个我
defined just a moment ago.
刚定义的变量。
So, now, what's going to happen?
现在会发生什么？
Well, let me actually go back to my VS Code.
好吧，让我回到我的 VS Code。
I'm going to go ahead and run Flask as I did before.
我将继续像之前一样运行 Flask。
The URL is not going to change in this case,
在这种情况下，URL 不会改变，
I'm going to go back to my other tab.
我会回到我的另一个选项卡。
I'm going to go ahead now and change the URL manually-- let me zoom in here--
我现在将手动更改 URL - 让我放大这里 -
to be /?name=David.
设置为 /?name=David。
I'm not going to hit Enter yet.
我还没有按 Enter 键。
Let me zoom out.
让我缩小。
But, when I do zoom out here, I think we should see now, hello, David.
但是，当我在这里缩小时，我认为我们现在应该看到，你好，David。
So here we go.
就是这样。
Enter.
回车。
And, voila, we see hello, David.
瞧，我们看到了你好，David。
But, more interestingly, if I view source
但更有趣的是，如果我查看源代码
here by right-clicking or Control-clicking on the page or opening
通过右键单击或 Control-单击页面或打开
developer tools and so forth and go to View page source,
开发人员工具等等，然后去查看页面源代码，
it appears that what the server sent to my browser
看起来服务器发送到我的浏览器的是
is literally a web page that says hello, David.
一个字面意义上说“你好，大卫”的网页。
There is no more placeholder.
没有占位符了。
There is no more curly braces.
没有大括号了。
Literally, the content that came from the server is that string.
字面意义上，来自服务器的内容就是那个字符串。
And so this is the distinction now between being
所以这就是静态应用和动态应用之间的区别。
a static application versus dynamic.
静态应用与动态应用的区别。
What I wrote statically was literally this index.html file.
我静态地写的，其实是这个index.html文件。
But what got served dynamically is that file
但是动态服务的是那个文件
plus the substitution or interpolation of that placeholder variable.
加上那个占位符变量的替换或插值。
So we have the beginnings, it would seem, of a web application.
所以，看起来我们有了网页应用的雏形。
And think back to Google.
想想Google。
Google is essentially implemented the same way, /search?q=cats.
Google本质上也是用同样的方式实现的，/search?q=cats。
So they're doing more with the key value pair than just spitting it back out,
所以它们对键值对的操作不仅仅是直接输出，
but we have the beginnings now of a dynamic application.
但我们现在有了动态应用的雏形。
Any questions on any of this code or this framework thus far?
关于这段代码或框架，目前有什么问题吗？
Any questions thus far.
目前有什么问题吗？
No, all right, well, let's see what happens
没有，好的，让我们看看会发生什么
if I don't cooperate like a human.
如果我不像人类一样配合。
Let me actually go ahead and get rid of that parameter, hit Enter again,
让我把参数删掉，再按回车，
and I actually now got an HTTP 400 error.
现在我得到一个HTTP 400错误。
So this actually seems bad.
看起来不太好。
And it's a little subtle, but if I zoom into the tab here, it indeed says 400.
这有点微妙，但如果我放大这里的标签，它确实显示了400。
That's one of the HTTP status codes that you generally shouldn't
这是一个HTTP状态码，你一般不应该
see unless something goes wrong.
看到它，除非有什么错误。
200 meant OK.
200代表OK。
404 meant file not found.
404代表文件未找到。
400 means that something went wrong.
400代表有错误发生。
I guess I didn't pass in a name as I was supposed to.
我猜我没有像预期的那样传入一个名字。
But that's only because I was sort of blindly expecting this placeholder
但这只是因为我有点盲目地期望这个占位符
to exist.
存在。
So let me be a little smarter and code a little more defensively now as follows.
所以让我更聪明一点，现在用更防御性的代码来写，如下所示。
Let me say this.
让我这么说。
How about if there is a name parameter in the requests arguments,
如果请求参数中有name参数，
then go ahead and create a variable called name,
那么就创建一个名为name的变量，
set it equal to request.args, quote, unquote, "name".
把它设置为request.args，引号，反引号，“name”。
So treat it as a dictionary with that key.
所以把它看成是带有那个键的字典。
Else, if there is no name in the URL, let's
否则，如果URL中没有name，让我们
just default this variable to being something sensible like,
把这个变量默认设置为一些合理的，比如，
quote, unquote, "world".
引号，反引号，“world”。
So, now, let's proactively, using some sort of "week one style"
所以，现在，让我们积极地，使用某种“第一周风格”
conditional code, albeit in Python now from week six,
条件代码，尽管现在是来自第六周的Python代码，
let's just check is name in the URL, if so grab its value.
让我们检查一下URL中是否有name，如果有就获取它的值。
Otherwise, default to world instead.
否则，默认使用world。
So I'm still going to leave this code as is,
所以，我仍然保留这段代码，
passing in the placeholder for this template to get plugged in here.
传入这个模板的占位符，以便在这里插入。
But, now, if I go back to the browser and I just reload without passing
但是，现在，如果我回到浏览器，并且只是刷新而没有传入，
in name=David or anything else, now we have a sensible default.
如果使用 `name=David` 或者其他任何东西，现在我们就有了合理的默认值。
And if I go back to my View source tab and reload, I'll see that I have hello,
如果我回到 "查看源代码" 选项卡并重新加载，我将看到 "hello"，
world in this case.
在这种情况下是 "world"。
However, if I go back up to that URL and do /?name=David, now we have David.
但是，如果我回到该 URL 并添加 `/?name=David`，现在我们就有 "David" 了。
If I change the URL to be name=Carter, now we have Carter.
如果我将 URL 改为 `name=Carter`，现在我们就有 "Carter" 了。
So, indeed, we do have the beginnings of something that's more dynamic.
所以，确实，我们已经开始拥有更加动态的东西了。
Of course, this is a little tedious to have
当然，这样写 if 和 else 有一些繁琐，
to write out this if and this else.
要写出这个 if 和 else。
There's ways to condense this code to be a little tighter and a little faster
有一些方法可以压缩这段代码，使其更加紧凑，执行速度也更快，
to actually implement.
以便实际实现。
And, in fact, let me go ahead and propose that.
实际上，让我来提出建议。
We just do this.
我们只需要这样做。
Instead of treating args as a dictionary as
与其将 `args` 视为字典，
we did with square brackets-- which can cause problems
就像我们用方括号那样，那样可能会导致问题，
if that key does not exist.
如果该键不存在。
In fact, let me go back to that version.
实际上，让我回到那个版本。
Let me undo, undo, undo, whereby I'm just blindly
让我撤销，撤销，撤销，这样我就可以直接
going into request.args to get name.
进入 `request.args` 获取 `name`。
In fact, instead of just blindly indexing into this dictionary
实际上，与其直接索引这个字典，
called args, which turns out we can do this instead.
叫做 `args`，我们其实可以这样做。
Let me go ahead and say request.args.get,
让我来写 `request.args.get`，
which is a function that comes with a dictionary,
这是一个字典自带的函数，
and I can specify the name of the key that I want to get.
我可以指定想要获取的键的名称。
And, by default, if there is no key called name in a dictionary,
默认情况下，如果字典中没有名为 `name` 的键，
you're going to get back a default value of none,
你将获得一个默认值为 `None` 的值，
which is kind of like Python's equivalent of null,
有点类似于 Python 中的 null，
but it's none, capital N, in Python.
但在 Python 中，它是 `None`，大写 N。
But if you want to give it a different default,
但如果你想给它一个不同的默认值，
it's handy to know that this get function,
值得知道的是，这个 `get` 函数，
which you can use with dictionaries in general
它可以用于一般的字典，
can take a second argument, which will be the default
可以接受第二个参数，该参数将作为默认值，
value that you do get back if, in fact, there is no such key called name.
你确实会获取该值，如果事实上没有名为 `name` 的键。
So what this means is I can actually now keep all of the code the same,
所以这意味着我现在实际上可以保持所有代码不变，
but it's a little tighter.
但它更简洁了。
There's no if or else.
没有 if 或 else。
I can go back to my other browser window, click reload,
我可以回到我的另一个浏览器窗口，点击重新加载，
and it still works for Carter.
它仍然对 "Carter" 有效。
But if I get rid of that, I can now have hello,
但如果我删除它，现在我可以有 "hello"，
world still working just as before.
"world" 仍然像以前一样工作。
And just to add one more potential point of confusion to the mix,
为了给这个混合增加另一个潜在的混淆点，
it's a little dopey to say placeholder literally in your template,
在模板中直接说 "占位符" 有点傻，
especially if you're going to be using multiple pairs of curly braces for one
特别是如果你要为一个变量使用多个花括号对，
variable or another or another.
或者另一个，或者另一个。
So better style would be to actually call
所以更好的风格是实际调用
the variable what makes sense for what it is you're plugging in.
变量，它对你要插入的内容是有意义的。
So hello, name, with the name in curly braces.
所以 "hello, name"，用花括号括起来的 `name`。
This is-- I show this, though, because it gets a little confusing
我展示这个，是因为它会有点混乱，
if your variable's called name, and that's still
如果你的变量名为 name，而且它仍然
going to be the value you pass in.
将是你要传递的值。
You're going to very often see in the world of Flask
你会经常在 Flask 的世界中看到
this convention, where you literally write something equals something where
这种惯例，你实际上写 something 等于 something，其中
the names there are exactly the same.
那里的名称完全相同。
And the only thing to keep in mind here is that the name--
这里唯一需要注意的是名称——
this is the name of this parameter.
这是这个参数的名称。
This is the value of this parameter.
这是这个参数的值。
The fact that everything seems to be called name in this program
事实上，在这个程序中，所有东西似乎都叫做 name
is because these technical terms are colliding with the English word
是因为这些专业术语与我们所知的英语单词冲突
that you and I know as name for my name, Carter's name, and so forth.
我们称之为 name，我的名字，Carter 的名字等等。
But get past that only because it will be very common to literally see
但是要克服这一点，因为这将非常常见，你实际上会看到
something equals something, where just for visual convenience
something 等于 something，仅仅是为了视觉上的方便
the variable's name is exactly the value that you want to pass in.
变量的名称恰好是你想要传递的值。
So that too here is conventional.
所以在这里也是惯例。
All right, a little cryptic.
好吧，有点神秘。
But common boilerplate that you'll start to see again and again.
但这是你会一遍又一遍看到的常见模板。
Any questions now about this?
现在对这个有什么问题吗？
No?
没有？
OK, so let's make things a little more interesting and representative
好的，让我们让事情更有趣，更具代表性
of a real-world app.
一个真实的应用程序。
Let me propose that, now, we go about implementing
现在，让我建议我们去实现
maybe a second template altogether.
也许是一个完全不同的第二个模板。
In fact, let me go ahead and do this.
事实上，让我继续做这件事。
It'd be nice if the human doesn't need to be technologically savvy enough
如果人类不需要足够的技术娴熟
to say that, oh, if you want to be greeted by this website,
来说，哦，如果你想被这个网站问候，
you have to literally change the URL yourself, type in name equals--
你必须自己更改 URL，输入 name 等于——
no one does that.
没有人会那样做。
That's just not how the web works in terms of user interface,
这仅仅不是 web 在用户界面方面的工作方式，
but that is how browsers and servers do work.
但这就是浏览器和服务器的工作方式。
But, of course, on the web, we almost always use forms.
当然，在 web 上，我们几乎总是使用表单。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事。
Let me go into index.html, and let me get rid of just this hello, body.
让我进入 index.html，让我只去掉这个 hello，body。
And, instead, let me actually create an HTML form.
并且，让我实际创建一个 HTML 表单。
This form is going to use the get method if only so that we can
这个表单将使用 get 方法，只是为了我们可以
see what's going on inside of the URL.
查看 URL 内部发生了什么。
This form is going to have an input where I'm going to turn autocomplete
这个表单将有一个输入框，我将关闭自动完成功能
off, just like last week.
就像上周一样。
I'm going to do auto focus just to move the cursor there nicely by default.
我将使用 auto focus 来默认地将光标很好地移动到那里。
Somewhat confusingly, I'm going to give this input a name of name
有点令人困惑的是，我将给这个输入框一个名为 name 的名字
because I want Carter's name, my name, or someone else's human name.
因为我想要 Carter 的名字，我的名字，或者其他人的名字。
But I'm going to give it placeholder text of,
但我将给它一个占位符文本，
quote, unquote, "Name", capitalized, just
引号，引号，“Name”，大写，只是
to be grammatically clear as to what we're prompting the user for.
为了语法上清晰地表明我们正在提示用户输入什么。
And the type of this field is going to be text.
而且这个字段的类型将是文本。
Although, that's the implied default if I don't give it a type.
虽然，如果我不给它一个类型，那就是隐含的默认值。
I'm going to lastly have a button in this form, the type of which
最后，我将在这个表单中有一个按钮，它的类型是
is submit so that the browser knows to submit this form.
提交按钮的作用是让浏览器知道要提交该表单。
And the label I'm going to put on this button is Greet.
我要给这个按钮添加的标签是“问候”。
So I'm going to type in my name, click Greet.
所以我将输入我的名字，然后点击“问候”。
And I want to see hello, David or the like.
我希望看到“你好，大卫”或类似的文字。
But I need to specify the action for this form.
但我需要指定这个表单的动作。
And recall that, when we implemented "Google", quote, unquote,
还记得我们实现“谷歌”时，
we did a little something like this.
我们做了一些类似的事情。
Https://www.google.com/search, well, we're
https://www.google.com/search，嗯，我们
not going to punt to Google today.
今天不会使用谷歌。
We are implementing our own applications.
我们正在实现我们自己的应用程序。
So if this were a search application, I could literally have an action
因此，如果这是一个搜索应用程序，我可以直接有一个动作
of /search, but let's do something a little more semantically sensible.
为 /search，但让我们做一些语义上更合理的事情。
Let's create our brand new route called /greet.
让我们创建一个名为 /greet 的全新路由。
This is not the name of a folder.
这不是文件夹的名字。
It's not the name of a file.
这不是文件的名字。
It's more generically a path or a route that is now up to me to implement.
更笼统地说，它是一个路径或路由，现在由我来实现。
If I go back, though, to this application and reload this page,
但是，如果我回到这个应用程序并重新加载这个页面，
notice that I have the beginnings of a more user-friendly form
请注意，我有一个更加用户友好的表单的雏形
that's asking me for this name.
它正在询问我的名字。
However, if I do type in David and click Greet--
然而，如果我输入大卫并点击问候——
I'll zoom in just a moment--
我放大一下——
notice that the URL does change to /greet?name=David just like google.com
请注意，URL 确实更改为 /greet?name=David，就像 google.com 一样
works.
起作用。
But, of course, we're getting a 404 not found because I
但当然，我们得到了 404 未找到，因为我
haven't implemented this route yet.
还没有实现这个路由。
So let me zoom out.
所以让我缩小。
Let me go back to VS Code.
让我回到 VS Code。
Let me open app.py and make a little bit of a change there.
让我打开 app.py，并在那里做一些更改。
Let me make a little bit of a change and say this in app.py.
让我做一些更改，并在 app.py 中说这句话。
In app.py, instead of just getting the user's name and this default,
在 app.py 中，与其仅仅获取用户名和默认值，
let's simplify the index route and just have it sole purpose in life
让我们简化索引路由，让它唯一的生命意义
be to render index.html, the thing that contains the form.
就是渲染 index.html，它包含表单。
I'm going to now, though, create a second route, so app.route, quote,
但是现在，我要创建一个第二个路由，所以 app.route，引号，
unquote, "/greet".
引号，"/greet"。
And I could call this route anything I want.
我可以随意命名这个路由。
But greet seems sensible.
但“问候”似乎很合理。
I'm going to call the function below it anything I want.
我要给下面的函数命名为我想要的任何名字。
But, just to keep myself sane, I'm going to call it the same thing as the route
但是，为了保持清醒，我要给它和路由取同样的名字
even though that's not strictly required.
即使这不是强制要求的。
And then, in this route, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
然后，在这个路由中，我要继续做这件事。
I'm going to create a variable called name, set it equal to request.args.get,
我要创建一个名为 name 的变量，将它设置为 request.args.get，
quote, unquote, "name", then, quote, unquote, "world", so
引号，引号，“name”，然后，引号，引号，“world”，所以
the exact same line as before.
这行代码与之前完全相同。
And then I'm going to return render_template, which
然后我将返回 render_template，它
is the function that comes with Flask.
是 Flask 附带的函数。
I'm going to specify this time, though, render a template called greet.html--
不过，这次我要指定渲染一个名为 greet.html 的模板——
which doesn't exist yet, but that's not going to be a hard problem to solve--
它还不存在，但这并不难解决——
and pass in that variable.
并将该变量传递进去。
So the last thing I need to do is this.
所以最后一步就是这个。
And I'm going to cheat and copy and, in a moment,
我会作弊，复制，然后在一会儿
paste the contents of index.html into a new file called greet.html as follows.
将index.html的内容粘贴到一个名为greet.html的新文件中，如下所示。
Let me open up VS Code here in my other terminal.
让我在我的另一个终端中打开VS Code。
Let me go ahead and write code templates/greet.html.
让我继续写代码templates/greet.html。
Notice that I'm making sure to put the new file in the templates folder.
注意，我确保将新文件放到templates文件夹中。
Or I could cd into it and then run the code command.
或者我可以cd到它里面，然后运行code命令。
That's going to give me a new file.
这将会给我一个新文件。
I'm going to hide my terminal, paste that code,
我要隐藏我的终端，粘贴该代码，
and I'm going to get rid of the form.
我要去掉表单。
And, frankly, I should've just copied and pasted this earlier
坦白地说，我应该早点复制粘贴
because the only thing I'm going to put in greet.html is hello
因为我将在greet.html中放入的唯一东西是hello
and then, in curly braces, my placeholder, which
然后，在花括号中，我的占位符，它
we started to call name a moment ago.
我们刚才开始称之为名字。
So, to recap if I go into my terminal again, if I type ls,
所以，回顾一下，如果我再次进入我的终端，如果我输入ls，
I've still got app.py.
我仍然有app.py。
I've still got templates.
我仍然有templates。
But if I look inside of templates now, I've got two templates-- index.html
但是，如果我现在看看templates里面，我有两个模板——index.html
and greet.html. index.html is the thing you see when you visit my website.
和greet.html。index.html是你访问我的网站时看到的东西。
greet.html is the thing you see when you submit that form, it would seem.
greet.html是你提交该表单时看到的东西，看起来是。
So, indeed, if I go back to my browser and hit back--
所以，事实上，如果我回到我的浏览器，然后点击后退——
so I get back to that form.
所以我回到了那个表单。
For good measure, I'm going to reload because I
为了保险起见，我要刷新，因为我
want to make sure I have the latest version of everything.
想确保我有所有东西的最新版本。
I'm going to now try typing my name David.
我现在要尝试输入我的名字David。
I'll zoom in.
我要放大。
You'll see that the URL will again change to /greet with the question mark
你会看到URL再次变为/greet，带有问号
and my name.
和我的名字。
But, hopefully, we now indeed don't see a 404
但是，希望我们现在确实不会看到404
because the new route actually exists.
因为新路由实际上存在。
And if I zoom out, right-click or Control-click
如果我缩小，右键单击或Control-单击
and go to View page source, you still see
然后转到查看页面源代码，你仍然会看到
what appears to be a HTML file just for me even though it was dynamically
看起来像一个只针对我的HTML文件，即使它是动态的
generated instead.
生成的。
All right, if you're on board that this seems to be a correct application
好的，如果你同意这看起来是一个正确的应用程序
insofar as it does what I wanted it to do,
因为它做了我想要它做的事情，
let's critique the design as we've been in the habit of doing.
让我们像我们一直以来的习惯那样，批判一下设计。
I've now got three files, app.py, greet.html, and index.html.
我现在有三个文件，app.py、greet.html和index.html。
What might you not like about the design of this web application
即使你以前从未做过这些事情，你可能不喜欢这个web应用程序的设计吗？
even if you've never done this stuff before?
是的。
Yeah.
[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
是的，greet和index.html的内容相同，
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, greet and index.html have the same contents,
除了主体中间的那一两行。
except for that one or few lines in the middle of the body.
我的意思是，我实际上是复制粘贴的，这通常
I mean, I literally copied and pasted, which, generally,
即使我偶尔在课堂上这样做以节省时间，
even though I do it sometimes in class to save time,
如果我最终在我的文件中拥有相同的代码，
if I end up with the same code in my files,
that's probably cutting some corner and not the best design.
这可能是一种偷懒的做法，而且不是最好的设计。
Why?
为什么？
Well, what if I want to go in and change the title of this application
好吧，如果我想进入并更改此应用程序的标题
from hello to something else.
从“hello”改为其他内容呢？
It's not a huge deal.
这不是什么大问题。
But I have to change it in two places.
但我必须在两个地方更改它。
What if I've got some pretty CSS that I've added?
如果我添加了一些漂亮的 CSS 呢？
And so I've got some CSS up here in one file.
因此我在一个文件中放了一些 CSS。
I need to copy it into another file, change it both places.
我需要将它复制到另一个文件，并在两个地方都更改它。
Generally, having duplication of anything is bad design.
一般来说，任何东西的重复都是糟糕的设计。
So it turns out, there is a way to solve this.
事实证明，有一种方法可以解决这个问题。
And this is one of the features that you really
而这正是你在使用 Web 框架时才能真正获得的功能之一，无论是 Flask 还是其他框架。
start to get from a web framework, be it Flask or anything else.
你会得到解决这些问题的方案。
You get solutions to these problems.
所以我现在要做的就是这个。
So what I'm going to do now is this.
我要为这个应用程序创建一个第三个也是最后一个文件。
I'm going to create a third and final file for this application
从复制我已经有的内容开始。
by starting by copying what I have already.
让我回到我的终端窗口。
Let me go back to my terminal window here.
让我在 templates 文件夹中创建一个名为 layout.html 的第三个模板。
And let me create a third template in the templates folder called
它不必叫这个名字，但这是惯例。
layout.html.
所以我在这里总是这样做。
It doesn't have to be called that, but that's the convention.
当我创建这个文件并隐藏我的终端时，
So I'll always do that here.
我要继续将所有内容复制粘贴。
And, when I create this file and hide my terminal,
但我要进入这个名为 layout.html 的文件的主体中，
I'm going to go ahead and copy-paste all of that content.
它与我所有其他文件中的内容完全相同。
But I'm going to go inside of the body of this file, called layout.html,
我将使用稍微奇怪的语法。
which is otherwise identical across all of my files.
这更多的是 Jinja 语法，一些其他人多年前想出来的。
And what I'm going to do is use slightly weird syntax.
我要这样做。
This is more of that Jinja syntax that some other humans came up
一个单花括号和一个百分号。
with years ago.
我要指定“block”这个词，然后指定我想要为这个块起的名字。
And I'm going to do this.
根据惯例，我会保持简单，
Single curly brace and a percent sign.
只使用与我所在标签名称完全相同的内容，即 block body。
I'm going to specify the word block and then any name I want for this block.
然后我在右花括号之前放一个百分号。
And, by convention, I'm going to keep it simple
我在这里不需要任何东西。
and just use the exact same thing as the name of the tag
所以乍一看这也会很奇怪。
that I'm inside, so block body.
但这是一个惯例。
And then I'm going to put a percent sign just before the close curly brace.
我将用百分号再加一个花括号，
I don't need anything inside of this.
然后字面上写上“endblock”，中间没有空格。
So this too's going to look weird at first glance.
我要打开并关闭一个不是 HTML 标签的东西。
But it's a convention.
如果你愿意，它是一个 Jinja 标签。
I'm going to do another curly brace with the percent sign
所以，再次，你会看到更多证据表明，世界上合理的人
and then literally the word endblock, no space.
在语法上存在分歧，或者至少使用精神上类似的语法，
And I'm going to open and close what isn't an HTML tag.
但不会与 HTML 已经使用的尖括号语法冲突。
It's a Jinja tag, if you will.
长话短说，这是一种指定的方式，
So, again, you see yet more evidence of reasonable humans
你想要一个占位符，而不仅仅是一个单个变量的值，
in the world kind of disagreeing on syntax
你可以用它来替换一些内容，例如你标题中的所有内容。
or at least using syntax that's similar in spirit
所以，这是一个创建布局或模板的好方法，
but doesn't clash with the syntax, the angled brackets that HTML already uses.
你可以在其中插入任何内容。
Long story short, this is a way of specifying
因此，如果你需要更改一个页面中不止一个地方的标题，
that you want a placeholder, not just for a single variable's value
你只需要更改 layout.html 文件中的一处即可。
but for a whole block of code.
但它适用于整块代码。
Maybe it's simply a sentence.
也许它只是一句话。
Maybe it's a whole-- a web form element or more.
也许它是一个完整的网络表单元素，或者更多。
This is a placeholder now for a block of code.
现在这是一个代码块的占位符。
And the way I can do this-- or the way I can use this template--
而我这样做的方式，或者我使用这个模板的方式，
and this is where template now is getting all the more literal
而这正是模板现在变得越来越字面化的部分。
in the sense of what templates do.
从模板的功能意义上来说。
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将继续执行此操作。
I'm going to go into my two other files, like greet.html.
我将进入我的另外两个文件，比如 greet.html。
The only line that's different in this file vis-a-vis index.html
与 index.html 相比，该文件唯一的区别在于
is which line number?
哪一行？
9 is the only line that is unique.
第 9 行是唯一不同的行。
So what I'm going to do is this.
所以我将这样做。
I'm going to highlight that and copy it.
我将选中它并复制它。
And then I'm going to delete everything else in this file
然后我将删除该文件中的所有其他内容
because it's just redundant.
因为它们是冗余的。
Everything I need is in layout.html.
我需要的一切都在 layout.html 中。
At the top of this file, I'm going to use another curly brace and a percent
在这个文件的顶部，我将使用另一个花括号和一个百分号
sign, but I'm going to use a special keyword that
符号，但我将使用一个特殊的关键字，
comes with Jinja called extends.
它与 Jinja 一起使用，叫做 extends。
And I'm going to specify in quotes here the name of the template
我将在引号中指定要扩展的模板名称。
that I want to extend, so to speak.
也就是说，我想要扩展它。
So this is an example of what's in computer science known as inheritance.
所以，这是一个计算机科学中被称为继承的概念的例子。
I want to take everything from that layout and inherit from it
我想从那个布局中获取所有内容，并从它继承
all of its lines but plug in some of my own,
它所有的行，但插入一些我自己的行，
sort of from a parent-child relationship.
有点像父子关系。
Inside of this file, now, I'm going to specify
现在，在这个文件内部，我将指定
that the custom body that I want is this block body just like before.
我想要自定义的正文是这个 block body，就像以前一样。
And then, down here, I'm going to preemptively say endblock just
然后，在这里，我将抢先说 endblock，只是
to finish my thought in advance.
为了提前完成我的想法。
And then, inside of this block body, I'm going to simply paste that line of code
然后，在这个 block body 内部，我将简单地粘贴那行代码
that I Stole from the original version.
我从原始版本中“偷”来的那行代码。
So I'll concede that this is pretty ugly.
我承认这看起来很丑陋。
I've added three cryptic-looking lines, all of which
我添加了三行看起来很神秘的代码，它们都
relate to Jinja templating, again, syntax
与 Jinja 模板有关，再次说明，语法
that humans invented to give you the ability to write templates,
是由人类发明的，它让你有能力编写模板，
or blueprints.
或者蓝图。
But the point is that this single line, now line 5,
但重点是，这单行代码，现在是第 5 行，
is going to get plugged into that template, called layout.html,
将被插入到那个名为 layout.html 的模板中，
wherever that body block is meant to go.
无论 body 块应该放在哪里。
Lastly, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
最后，我将继续执行此操作。
The only lines in index.html that are unique are these here, 9, 10, 11, 12.
index.html 中唯一不同的行是这些，第 9 行、第 10 行、第 11 行和第 12 行。
So I'm going to highlight those and delete everything else.
所以我将选中它们并删除所有其他内容。
And then I'm going to do the exact same thing, extends layout.html at the top
然后我将执行完全相同的事情，在文件顶部使用 extends layout.html
of this file, then, below that, block body.
然后，在它下面是 block body。
Inside of the block body, I'm going to then say endblock at the end.
在 block body 内部，我将在最后说 endblock。
And, in the middle of that, I'm going to paste those lines of code.
在中间，我将粘贴那些代码行。
Just stylistically, I'm going to indent them just so I'm super clear visually
仅仅从样式上来说，我会将它们缩进，这样视觉上就能非常清晰
on what is inside of what.
哪些东西包含着哪些东西。
But that's it.
就这样。
So ugly?
所以很丑吗？
Yes, but, as soon as your web pages get longer and longer,
是的，但是，一旦你的网页越来越长，
this ends up being a drop in the bucket.
这就会变得微不足道。
It's three ugly-looking lines relative to a lot of HTML
相对于大量可能要插入并为你的应用定制的 HTML 代码来说，这只是三行难看的代码
that you might be plugging in and customizing for your application.
而已。
So now index.html looks like this.
所以现在 index.html 就像这样。
greet.html looks like this.
greet.html 就像这样。
And the only way they differ is the actual contents of that block of code.
它们唯一的区别就是那段代码块的实际内容。
layout.html is the main blueprint that's going to govern
layout.html 是主要的蓝图，它将支配
what the whole website looks like.
整个网站的外观。
I can change the title in one place.
我可以在一个地方改变标题。
I can add some pretty CSS in one place and so forth.
我可以在一个地方添加一些漂亮的 CSS 代码等等。
It's going to apply to each of those files.
它将应用于每个文件。
And, now, somewhat underwhelmingly perhaps,
现在，也许有点令人失望，
if I go back to this application and I click reload,
如果我回到这个应用程序并点击重新加载，
nothing is different because it still just works.
没什么变化，因为它仍然正常工作。
But I've made arguably a better design because now,
但我可以说设计更好了，因为现在，
when I change things to Carter here or I get rid of it altogether
当我在这里将东西改为 Carter 或完全去掉它时
and just visit the default--
并且仅仅访问默认的--
rather, if I just visit slash there, I'll get the form.
或者，如果我只是访问那里的斜杠，我会得到表单。
I've at least handled the situation where--
我至少处理了这种情况--
I've eliminated the situation where I've just copied and pasted
我消除了仅仅复制粘贴的情况
the same boilerplate code.
相同的样板代码。
So odds are someone like Google is doing something like this.
所以，很可能像 Google 这样的公司正在做类似的事情。
It's probably fancier certainly than this example.
当然，它可能比这个例子更复杂。
But any time you search for something on Google, generally, the top of the page
但是，无论何时你在 Google 上搜索东西，一般来说，页面的顶部
looks the same.
看起来都一样。
Maybe the bottom of the page looks the same.
也许页面的底部看起来也一样。
There's maybe some ads always at the top.
也许顶部总是有一些广告。
And then there's 10 search results.
然后有 10 个搜索结果。
So, probably, what they've done is they have some template that looks roughly
所以，他们可能已经做了一些模板，看起来大致
like this with all of the boilerplate stuff
像这样，包含所有他们希望每个用户在每个搜索结果页面上看到的样板代码
that they want every human to see on every page of search results.
。
And then they're just somehow customizing the block--
然后他们只是以某种方式定制了代码块--
a block of code somewhere there in the middle.
位于中间的某段代码。
All right, questions on any of this actual templating technique?
好的，对任何实际的模板技术有什么问题吗？
Anything at all?
任何问题都可以？
All right, how about another question about design?
好的，关于设计还有其他问题吗？
If I go back to this URL here and I search for something like David,
如果我回到这里这个 URL 并搜索像 David 这样的东西，
it's not that big a deal that it ends up in the URL.
它最终出现在 URL 中并不是什么大问题。
And, in fact, what's nice about HTTP parameters ending up in the URL
事实上，HTTP 参数最终出现在 URL 中的好处是，
is that URLs are therefore stateful.
URL 因此具有状态。
If you copy this URL and paste it into an email,
如果你复制此 URL 并将其粘贴到电子邮件中，
assuming the web server is still up and running at that URL, it will just work.
假设 Web 服务器仍然在那个 URL 上运行，它就会正常工作。
And the human to whom you send that link,
而你发送该链接的人，
they will see David or Carter or whatever name's
他们会看到大卫或卡特，或者任何名字
actually in that form, which may be as useful behavior.
实际上以这种形式，这可能是一种有用的行为。
Not so much for this application, but imagine now
这对这个应用来说意义不大，但现在想象一下
that you want to send someone a link of Google search results.
你想给某人发送一个谷歌搜索结果的链接。
It's a good thing that Google puts q=cats or dogs or birds or whatever
谷歌将 q=cats 或 dogs 或 birds 等等放在 URL 中是一件好事
in the URL because then the URL itself is stateful.
在 URL 中，因为这样 URL 本身就具有状态性。
What you see is what the recipient will see
你看到的就是接收者会看到的内容
because all of the inputs of the server that's requisite is in that URL.
因为服务器所需的所有输入都在该 URL 中。
But suppose that this form field, if I go back,
但假设这个表单字段，如果我返回，
wasn't asking for my name but my credit card number or my password up here.
不是询问我的姓名，而是询问我的信用卡号码或密码。
That should start to rub you the wrong way because it
这应该让你感到不舒服，因为
feels like no good will come from exposing private information in the URL
感觉在 URL 中暴露私密信息不会带来任何好处
because if you have a nosy sibling look over your shoulder.
因为如果你有一个爱管闲事兄弟姐妹从你背后偷看。
There it is in your search history.
它就在你的搜索历史记录中。
A roommate goes through your autocomplete and finds the data there.
室友会浏览你的自动完成并找到数据。
Or if you do, for whatever reason, copy-paste it,
或者出于任何原因，你复制粘贴它，
you're accidentally including private information in these URLs.
你就会无意中将私人信息包含在这些 URL 中。
So I said last week that there is an alternative to sending things
所以上周我说过，有一种替代方法可以发送东西
in the URL and that alternative is to use something
在 URL 中，这种替代方法是使用一些东西
that's not called get but a verb in the world of HTTP
它不叫 get，而是在 HTTP 世界中称为动词
that's called post instead.
叫做 post。
And it's actually a relatively simple change.
这实际上是一个相对简单的改变。
If I go into index.html, I can simply change the method from get to post.
如果我进入 index.html，我可以简单地将方法从 get 更改为 post。
Get is the default. Post is an alternative.
Get 是默认值。Post 是一种替代方法。
Even though, in some contexts, you'll see capitals, in HTML,
尽管在某些情况下你会看到大写字母，但在 HTML 中，
it should be lowercase, another example of left hand not talking to right.
它应该是小写字母，这是左脚不跟右脚走的另一个例子。
But, in this case, if I go now to my other tab with the browser,
但在这个例子中，如果我现在使用浏览器进入另一个标签页，
reload the page because I want to get the latest version of the form,
重新加载页面，因为我想获取表单的最新版本，
if I now type David--
如果我现在输入大卫 --
and I'll zoom in-- before hitting Enter, if you watch the URL now,
我将放大 - 在点击回车键之前，如果你现在观察 URL，
you should not see that ?name=David is up there,
你应该看不到 ?name=David 在那里，
nor would be your credit card or your password.
你的信用卡或密码也不会在那里。
Unfortunately, we're seeing another HTTP status
不幸的是，我们看到了另一个 HTTP 状态
code we haven't seen yet, 405, Method Not Allowed.
代码，我们还没见过，405，方法不允许。
Well, why is that?
为什么呢？
That's because now that I fully control the web server,
那是因为我现在完全控制了 Web 服务器，
I need to tell the web server that I do want to support not just get
我需要告诉 Web 服务器，我不仅要支持 get
which is the default but post as well.
这是默认的，而且还要支持 post。
The method the user is using is not supported.
用户使用的方法不支持。
So this is an easy fix even though it's going
所以这是一个简单的修复，尽管它将
to look a little cryptic at first.
最初看起来有点神秘。
If you want your greet method to support not just get but post,
如果你希望你的 greet 方法不仅支持 get，还支持 post，
you can specify another argument to this route function.
你可以为这个路由函数指定另一个参数。
So the default is literally this, methods= and then in square brackets,
所以默认值实际上是这个，methods= 然后在方括号中，
quote, unquote, "GET".
引号，引号，“GET”。
So what is this?
这是什么？
Methods is apparently a named argument being passed into the route function.
显然，Methods 是一个传递给路由函数的命名参数。
I claim its default value is this.
我断言它的默认值是这个。
What do the square brackets indicate in Python?
在 Python 中，方括号表示什么？
Not a dictionary.
不是字典。
Square brackets.
方括号。
A list, so it's a list of strings or strs in this case.
一个列表，所以它是一个字符串列表，或者在本例中是 strs。
This is the implicit default.
这是隐式默认值。
So you don't have to type this.
所以你不用输入这个。
It's just what works out of the box automatically.
它就是开箱即用的自动功能。
But if you want to change this from get to post,
但如果你想将其从 get 更改为 post，
you have to include methods equals a list of the methods
你必须包含方法等于方法列表
that you do want to support.
你想要支持的方法。
For another time, there's other HTTP methods.
还有其他 HTTP 方法。
There's delete.
有删除。
There's put.
有更新。
Those are the two biggies that you might use as well.
这两个是你可以使用的两个大方法。
Those are generally not supported as easily in the world of browsers,
在浏览器世界中，这些通常并不容易支持，
but get and post certainly are.
但 get 和 post 确实可以。
If you wanted to support both for whatever reason,
如果你想出于任何原因支持两者，
you can literally have a comma separated list of those methods instead.
你可以简单地用逗号分隔这些方法的列表。
But we don't really need both for privacy's sake.
但出于隐私考虑，我们不需要两者。
I claim I'm only going to use post now.
我声称我现在只打算使用 post。
So now if I go back to my other tab, go back
所以现在如果我回到另一个标签页，回到
to the form, reload to make sure everything is as expected,
表格，重新加载以确保一切如预期一样，
and now type in David and zoom in, you won't see my name in the URL.
现在输入 David 并放大，你不会在 URL 中看到我的名字。
But you will-- or you won't see it-- oh, good, not intended.
但你会——或者你不会看到它——哦，很好，不是故意这样。
But nor will you see it even in the body of the web page.
而且你甚至不会在网页主体中看到它。
So it's super secure.
所以它非常安全。
Why?
为什么？
I screwed up, but why?
我搞砸了，但为什么？
Yes.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不见]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, so good intuition.
DAVID J. MALAN：是的，很好的直觉。
Even if you knew that before, you might think through rationally,
即使你之前就知道，你可能也会理性地思考，
how might this be--
这可能是——
why might this be behaving this way?
为什么它会这样表现？
Well, if I go into app.py, it seems that if world is the value of the name
好吧，如果我进入 app.py，看起来如果 world 是名字的值
placeholder, well, it must be the case that there is no name
占位符，那么一定不存在名字
key in request.args in this case.
在本例中，request.args 中的键。
However, there's an alternative to request.args,
但是，request.args 还有一个替代方案，
and it's called request.form.
它叫做 request.form。
This is another example of visible and hidden being opposites of one another,
这是可见和隐藏相互对立的另一个例子，
request.args and request.form, at least for me,
request.args 和 request.form，至少对我来说，
are not obvious mappings to GET and POST, respectively.
不是对 GET 和 POST 的明显映射。
But that's what the Flask folks did.
但这就是 Flask 开发人员所做的。
And so the simple fix now, if I go back to VS Code,
因此，简单的解决方法是，如果我回到 VS Code，
is to change request.args to request.form
将 request.args 更改为 request.form
if you want to use post instead of get.
如果你想使用 post 而不是 get。
This is a weird misnomer because they're both coming from forms,
这是一个奇怪的误称，因为它们都来自表单，
whether you're using GET or POST.
无论您使用 GET 还是 POST。
But this is what some folks decided.
但这就是一些人的决定。
So let me go back to my browser, go back to the original form, reload
所以让我回到我的浏览器，回到原来的表单，重新加载
to make sure I get the fresh HTML, type in my name now, David,
以确保我得到最新的 HTML，现在输入我的名字，大卫，
zoom in, and click Greet.
放大，然后点击问候。
And, this time, you won't see my name in the URL,
而且，这次，你不会在 URL 中看到我的名字，
but you should see it in the body of the page.
但你应该在页面的主体中看到它。
So we've achieved some form of privacy, if you will.
所以，如果你愿意，我们已经实现了一些隐私。
Better applied to things like credit card numbers, passwords, and the like.
更适用于信用卡号码、密码等。
Phew, other questions?
呼，还有其他问题吗？
On any of this thus far?
到目前为止，对这些有任何疑问吗？
Anything yet?
有什么问题吗？
No, all right, yes, in the middle.
没有，好的，是的，在中间。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] post and get, the request [INAUDIBLE]??
观众：[听不清] post 和 get，请求[听不清]？
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
大卫·J·马兰：一个好问题。
To repeat if you were supporting both GET and POST,
再说一次，如果你同时支持 GET 和 POST，
should we have a second line that's also checking request.args?
我们是否应该添加第二行来检查 request.args？
Yes, if you were.
是的，如果你那样做了。
I, though, decided, at the last minute, only to support POST not GET.
不过，我在最后一刻决定只支持 POST，不支持 GET。
So I don't have to bother with that.
所以我不必为此烦恼。
But your question's a perfect segue to a final example of this Hello application
但你的问题是完美地引入了这个 Hello 应用的最后一个示例
where you can actually consolidate different types of functionality
在那里，你实际上可以将不同类型的功能
into individual routes.
合并到各个路由中。
Why?
为什么？
Well, at the moment, this application is super simple.
好吧，目前，这个应用程序非常简单。
It's literally got one form and then one resulting page.
它实际上只有一个表单，然后是一个结果页面。
But it's implemented, therefore, with a pair of routes, a pair of functions.
但它是用一对路由，一对函数实现的。
No big deal for small applications.
对于小型应用程序来说，没什么大不了的。
But if you imagine a more complicated application,
但如果你想象一个更复杂的应用程序，
be it Google or anything else that has many different web
无论是谷歌还是其他任何拥有很多不同网页的网站
forms on different pages, it's a little annoying
表单在不同的页面上，这有点令人讨厌
if every form needs to separate routes if only because you now
如果每个表单都需要单独的路由，仅仅因为你现在
have to keep track of literally twice as many functions.
必须跟踪实际上两倍数量的函数。
Your colleagues, your teaching fellow needs
你的同事，你的助教需要
to know which one is related to which.
知道哪个函数对应哪个路由。
So there's something to be said design-wise
所以，从设计的角度来看，
about consolidating related functionality into one single route
将相关功能合并到一个单一的路由中
so that everything is together.
以便将所有内容放在一起。
Well, we can achieve that relatively simply as follows.
好吧，我们可以通过以下方法相对简单地实现。
So let me go ahead and completely eliminate this greet route and simply
所以让我继续完全删除这个 greet 路由，并且只
have everything exist in the /route.
让所有内容都存在于 /route 中。
And I'm going to go ahead and highlight and cut these lines out of there
我要继续将这些行高亮显示并剪切掉
altogether.
全部。
But if I want my single /route to support multiple methods,
但如果我想要我的单个 /route 支持多种方法，
I indeed need to use methods equals and then, in square brackets, GET and POST.
我确实需要使用 methods 等于，然后，在方括号中，GET 和 POST。
Order doesn't matter.
顺序无关紧要。
But I'll keep them alphabetical in this case.
但我会在本例中按字母顺序排列它们。
Inside of my index route, I need to in advance is the user visiting me
在我的索引路由内部，我需要提前知道用户是否访问我
via GET or POST?
通过 GET 还是 POST？
Because if it's via GET, I want them to see the form.
因为如果通过 GET，我希望他们看到表单。
If it's via POST, I want to process, the form, that is,
如果通过 POST，我希望处理表单，也就是说，
do something with the user's input.
对用户的输入进行一些操作。
So it turns out it's relatively simple.
事实证明，这相对简单。
If request.method equals equals "POST", then I can do the following.
如果 request.method 等于 "POST"，那么我可以执行以下操作。
So you can literally check the request object, which comes with Flask,
因此，你可以直接检查 request 对象，它随 Flask 一起提供，
to figure out, was the word GET or the word POST in that virtual envelope?
以确定那个虚拟信封中是 GET 还是 POST？
And, depending on the answer, you can do something like this.
然后，根据答案，你可以执行类似的操作。
I can paste those lines from earlier, whereby I get
我可以粘贴前面提到的那些行，其中我获得
the variable name from request.form.
request.form 中的变量名。
And then I render the template greet.html, passing in that name.
然后我渲染 greet.html 模板，传入那个名字。
Otherwise, you know what?
否则，你知道吗？
I could just do else, return the template itself.
我可以直接使用 else，返回模板本身。
So if the method is POST, go ahead and process the form just as we did before.
因此，如果方法是 POST，继续处理表单，就像我们之前做的那样。
Else, go ahead and just render the index template which contains the form.
否则，继续渲染包含表单的 index 模板。
Strictly speaking, I don't even need the else.
严格来说，我甚至不需要 else。
I can get rid of that, just to tighten this up a little bit,
我可以去掉它，只是为了稍微压缩一下代码，
and unindent my last line.
并取消缩进最后一行。
Why?
为什么？
Because recall that, from C, from Python, as soon as you return a value,
因为回想一下，从 C，从 Python，一旦你返回一个值，
nothing in that function is going to get executed thereafter.
该函数中没有任何内容将在之后执行。
So you might as well kind of tighten up the code so
因此，你不妨压缩一下代码，这样
that you don't bother adding undue indentation if not needed.
你就不必在不需要的情况下添加多余的缩进。
So notice, now, if I go back to my browser, reload here,
所以请注意，现在，如果我回到我的浏览器，在这里重新加载，
it's not going to work yet.
它还不能工作。
But let's see if you can diagnose the issue.
但让我们看看你是否可以诊断问题。
If I type in David here and click Greet, now I'm
如果我在这里输入 David 并点击 Greet，现在我
back to getting a 404 but for different reasons.
又回到了得到 404，但原因不同。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Good, I haven't changed-- not the method.
大卫·J·马兰：好的，我没有改变——方法没有变。
But I haven't changed the action in the form itself.
但我没有改变表单本身的 action。
So if I go back to VS Code here and I go into the web forms,
所以如果我回到这里的 VS Code，然后进入 web 表单，
the HTML, POST is still fine.
HTML 中的 POST 仍然没问题。
But there is no /greet route anymore.
但 /greet 路由不再存在。
So I actually can just specify slash.
所以我实际上可以直接指定斜杠。
Or it turns out if you omit that altogether, the form will assume
或者事实证明，如果你完全省略它，表单会认为
that you want to submit it to the very route from which you
你想要将其提交到你所在的路由
came so that is fine as well.
这就是，这也很好。
I'm going to go ahead now and go back to that other tab and go back.
我现在将继续返回到那个其他选项卡并返回。
I'm going to reload the page.
我将重新加载页面。
And, just for good measure, this time, I'm
并且，为了保险起见，这次我
going to Control-click or right-click View page source.
将使用 Ctrl+单击或右键单击“查看页面源代码”。
And, here, yep, the action has indeed updated.
并且，在这里，是的，action 确实已更新。
So I think I fixed the bug.
所以我想我修复了 bug。
Now if I type in David and click greet, we're back in business with it working.
现在，如果我输入 David 并点击 greet，它又可以正常工作了。
So notice that this still allows me the convenience
所以请注意，这仍然允许我方便地
of having two separate templates, one for the form which shows the--
拥有两个单独的模板，一个用于显示表单的模板——
which collects the user input and one for the actual greeting
一个用于收集用户输入，另一个用于实际问候
which displays the user input.
显示用户输入。
So I'd argue that it still makes sense to keep those separate.
所以我认为将它们分开仍然是有意义的。
But I can avoid bloating my app.py by having
但我可以避免我的 app.py 代码膨胀，方法是
two methods for every single feature that I might want to implement.
为我可能想要实现的每个功能创建两个方法。
Now, there is still a bug in this implementation
现在，这个实现中仍然存在一个错误
even though it's a little bit subtle.
虽然它有点微妙。
So recall that, previously, we introduced this default value of world
回想一下，之前我们引入了这个 world 的默认值
just in case the form doesn't actually contain the word world
以防表格实际上不包含 world 这个词
as might've happened if I didn't-- if I [INAUDIBLE] into the URL that I was
就像我之前手动请求 URL 时没有输入或 [听不清] 一样。
requesting manually as I did before.
手动请求。
But it turns out that if you're using an actual form and not,
但事实证明，如果你正在使用一个真实的表格，而不是
of course, expecting the human to type anything into the URL bar, which
当然，期望人们在 URL 地址栏中输入任何内容，
no human would do, it turns out that the browser is still
没有人会这样做，事实证明浏览器仍然
going to submit a name parameter even if its value is blank,
会提交一个 name 参数，即使它的值为空，
that is, empty, the so-called empty string.
也就是空字符串。
And so even if it's the empty string, it's
所以即使是空字符串，它也
still going to be considered to be a value
仍然会被认为是一个值
and, therefore, not worthy of having the default value of world plugged in.
因此，它不值得使用 world 的默认值。
In other words, if I open up my terminal window here, rerun flask run,
换句话说，如果我在这里打开我的终端窗口，重新运行 flask run，
and go back over to my browser, and load this example, if I type in David,
然后回到我的浏览器，加载这个例子，如果我输入 David，
as before, I'm going to be greeted with hello, David.
和以前一样，我会收到 hello, David 的问候。
But if I try this again and don't provide an actual name but just click
但如果我再试一次，不提供实际的姓名，只点击
Greet, it turns out the name parameter's still
Greet，事实证明 name 参数仍然
going to be submitted to the server, in which case request.form.get is not
会被提交到服务器，在这种情况下，request.form.get 不会
going to rely on the default value but rather that empty string value.
依赖于默认值，而是依赖于空字符串值。
And so we see what appears to be a bit of an aesthetic bug hello, nothing.
因此，我们看到似乎存在一个美观的错误：hello, nothing。
So how can we go about fixing this?
那么我们如何解决这个问题呢？
Well, perhaps the simplest way is to no longer rely on this default
嗯，也许最简单的方法是不再依赖这个默认
value here inside of app.py.
值，它在 app.py 中。
So, in fact, let me go ahead and delete that default value altogether
所以，事实上，让我继续删除那个默认值
and pass name in as the variable it still is into greet.html, our template.
并将 name 作为变量传递到 greet.html 模板中。
But, in greet.html, let's add a bit of logic
但是在 greet.html 中，让我们添加一些逻辑
there whereby we conditionally display the name if and only if it's not empty.
在那里，我们只有在 name 不为空的情况下才显示它。
In other words, before I output blindly name inside of these curly braces,
换句话说，在我盲目地输出这些花括号内的 name 之前，
let me borrow some syntax from Python and actually use, within my Jinja
让我借用一下 Python 的语法，实际上在我的 Jinja
template, a conditional like this.
模板中使用这样的条件语句。
Open curly brace and then a percent sign because, this time,
打开花括号，然后是百分号，因为这次，
I want logic, not just interpolation of a variable.
我想要逻辑，而不仅仅是变量的插值。
And I'm going to say if name.
我要说 if name。
And then I'm going to do another percent sign and a single curly brace.
然后，我将添加另一个百分号和一个单花括号。
And then, after that, I'm going to still use my variable name name
然后，在那之后，我仍然会使用我的变量名 name
inside of two curly braces.
放在两个花括号内。
But, after that, I'm going to do again a single curly brace, a single percent
但是，在那之后，我将再次使用一个单花括号，一个单百分号
sign, and then I'm going to say else followed by one more percent sign.
符号，然后我将说 else，后面跟着一个百分号。
And then, after that, I'm going to go ahead and actually put my default value
然后，在那之后，我将继续并实际输入我的默认值
world and then close this if conditional with a single curly brace,
世界，然后用一个单花括号关闭这个 if 条件语句，
a single percent sign, and endif.
一个单百分号，以及 endif。
And then I'm going to go ahead and close that tag there.
然后，我将继续并关闭那里的标签。
So, in Jinja, it turns out that we can use it not only to plug in values.
所以，在 Jinja 中，事实证明，我们不仅可以用来插入值。
We can also do a bit of lightweight conditional logic using
我们还可以使用 if、else 和 endif 来进行一些轻量级的条件逻辑，
an if and an else and an endif in this case, which
在这种情况下，它
isn't quite like Python-- indeed the endif is a little bit different.
不像 Python - 实际上 endif 有点不同。
But this is particular now to the Jinja template.
但这现在是 Jinja 模板所特有的。
And I've done it all on one line just because this
我将所有内容都放在一行上，仅仅因为这
is a fairly bit-sized conditional, either print out the name
是一个相当小的条件语句，要么打印出姓名
or print out world.
要么打印出 world。
Otherwise, I could actually put these template tags on their own lines
否则，我实际上可以将这些模板标签放在它们自己的行上
in order to spread things out all the more.
以便更充分地分散事物。
We'll see now, before long, that there's actually
我们很快就会看到，实际上
some other control flow capabilities of Jinja including loops and more.
Jinja 还有一些其他的控制流功能，包括循环等等。
But, for now, this is a nice way to solve that one problem because now,
但现在，这是一个解决那个问题的不错方法，因为现在，
when I go back into my application and I go back to the form and type
当我回到我的应用程序，回到表单，输入
in D-A-V-I-D, it's still going to work as expected, hello, David.
D-A-V-I-D，它仍然按预期工作，hello，David。
But if I go back one final time, type nothing in thereby sending
但如果我最后再回来一次，不输入任何内容，从而发送
an empty value to the server and click Greet here to demonstrate as much,
一个空值到服务器，并点击 Greet 这里来演示这一点，
now we do, in fact, see hello, world.
现在，我们确实看到了 hello，world。
All right, any questions on this final example of just saying hello?
好了，关于这个简单说 hello 的最后一个例子，还有问题吗？
From those basics come pretty much all of dynamic web applications today.
从这些基本知识出发，几乎诞生了今天所有的动态网页应用程序。
No?
没有？
All right, so if you'll indulge me, here's an actual web application
好吧，如果你允许我，这里有一个真实的网页应用程序
that I made back in the day.
是我以前制作的。
So, when I was a sophomore, I think I was not very athletic,
所以，当我还是大二的时候，我想我不是很擅长运动，
so I didn't so much do freshman intramural sports as I did run them
所以我没有参加大一新生校内运动，而是负责管理它们
with a roommate of mine.
和我的一位室友一起。
So we were sophomores in Mather House.
所以我们是大二学生，住在 Mather House。
He was the athlete.
他是运动员。
I was the aspiring computer scientist.
我是一个有抱负的计算机科学家。
And so this was actually a screenshot of the very first web application
所以，这实际上是我制作的第一个网页应用程序的截图
I ever made.
我曾经制作过。
And this will sound old too.
这听起来也很老。
But, back in my day, freshman year, when we
但是，在我那个年代，大一的时候，当我们
registered for Frosh IMs, or Freshman Intramural Sports,
报名参加 Frosh IMs，也就是大一新生校内运动，
you would literally walk across Harvard yard
你真的要走过哈佛庭院
to Wigglesworth, where a certain proctor or RA lived who was running Frosh IMs.
到 Wigglesworth，那里住着一位负责管理 Frosh IMs 的导师或 RA。
And you would literally slide a sheet of paper
你真的要在一张纸上写下你的名字
under the door with your name on it and your choice of sports
和你想注册的运动项目，然后塞到门下面。
that you want to register for.
你想注册的运动项目。
So that was the state of the art in 1995.
所以这就是 1995 年的技术前沿。
This was ripe for disruption as people would now say.
正如人们现在所说，这是颠覆的成熟时机。
And, once I actually took CS50 in the fall of 1996, which did not
然后，我实际上是在 1996 年秋季上了 CS50，当时它并没有
teach, funny enough, web programming at the time,
教，有趣的是，当时没有教网页编程，
I think I spent that winter or spring figuring out
我想我在那个冬天或春天花时间弄清楚
how to do stuff with web programming, not using C and not even using Python.
如何使用网页编程，不使用 C 语言，甚至不使用 Python。
At the time, I was using a language called Perl, which is still with us
当时，我使用的是一种叫做 Perl 的语言，它现在依然存在
but not as popular as it was back in the day.
但没有以前那么流行了。
But what you're seeing here is a hideous screenshot
但你在这里看到的，是一个丑陋的截图
of what the user interface was.
展示了当时的界面。
This was me learning how to repeat background in images infinitely,
当时我在学习如何无限重复图像背景，
no matter how big the page was.
无论页面有多大。
Back in the day, there was no CSS, I think, even at the time.
那时，我想，甚至当时还没有 CSS。
So every one of these menu options was actually an image.
所以，每一个菜单选项实际上都是一个图片。
And even though-- this is a screenshot, so it's not animated.
虽然——这只是一个截图，所以它没有动画。
If you would hover over any of these words, what
如果你把鼠标悬停在这些词语上，我会
I would do using JavaScript, which did exist in an early form,
用早期的 JavaScript 做的是，
was just change the image from a blue image to a red image,
只是把图片从蓝色变成红色，
creating the illusion of the trickery we did last week with text decoration,
营造出我们上周用文本装饰所做的技巧的幻觉，
as you might recall in hover.
你可能还记得，用 hover 来实现。
So the web's come a long way.
所以，网络已经走了很长一段路。
But this is still representative, amazingly, some 20 years later
但令人惊讶的是，二十年后，这仍然代表着
of how web applications still work.
网络应用程序是如何运作的。
I used a different language.
我使用了一种不同的语言。
I used a different backend for my data or database.
我使用了不同的后端来处理我的数据或数据库。
But everything I did then we will now do effectively today
但我当时所做的一切，我们现在实际上可以在今天做
and beyond because the principles have not changed.
以及未来，因为原理并没有改变。
It's all based ultimately on HTTP and all of the stuff
这一切最终都基于 HTTP，以及我们
we discussed thus far this past week and now this.
过去一周以及现在讨论的所有东西。
So let's go ahead and make the beginnings of this website,
所以，让我们开始创建这个网站，
though, perhaps without as many of the hideous images underneath it.
不过，也许可以不用那么多难看的图片。
In my VS Code, I'm going to go ahead and close all of my prior tabs.
在我的 VS Code 中，我要关闭所有之前的标签。
I'll open up my terminal, and I'll hit Control-c to exit out
我将打开我的终端，然后按下 Ctrl+C 来退出
of Flask just like you can hit Control-c to exit out of the HTTP server.
Flask，就像你可以按下 Ctrl+C 来退出 HTTP 服务器一样。
I'm going to go ahead and hit cd to go back to my main workspace.
我将按下 cd 返回我的主工作区。
And I'm going to create a new folder with mkdir called froshims
我将使用 mkdir 创建一个名为 froshims 的新文件夹
so that all of my new application is inside of this folder.
这样我的所有新应用程序都将在这个文件夹中。
I'm going to cd into froshims.
我将进入 froshims 文件夹。
And let's go ahead and make a very simple application
让我们创建一个非常简单的应用程序
that essentially pretends to let first years register for a sport.
它本质上模拟了让一年级新生注册一项运动。
So I'm going to need to do a bit of typing up front.
所以我需要先输入一些东西。
But I'll do the first one from scratch.
但我将从头开始第一个。
And then we'll start just evolving that same example.
然后，我们将开始逐步演进那个例子。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我来做一下。
Let me go ahead and--
让我来——
actually, we'll do this.
实际上，我们会这样做。
We'll cut one corner.
我们会省掉一个步骤。
I'm going to go ahead and copy, from my hello example, app.py into this folder.
我将从我的 hello 示例中复制 app.py 文件到这个文件夹中。
I'm going to go ahead and copy from my hello examples
我将从我的 hello 示例中
templates my layout into this folder.
复制模板布局到这个文件夹中。
I'm going to create a new folder called templates.
我将创建一个名为 templates 的新文件夹。
I'm going to move that copied layout into templates
我将把复制的布局移动到 templates 文件夹中
so that, at this point in the story, if I clear my screen and type ls,
这样，在这个时间点，如果我清除屏幕并输入 ls 命令，
I've got the beginnings of a web application,
我就有了 web 应用程序的基础，
even though it's specific to just saying hello.
即使它只是用于简单的问候。
But I'm going to go ahead and into the templates folder
但是，我将继续进入 templates 文件夹
and go into layout.html.
并进入 layout.html 文件。
Let's just change this ever so slightly to say froshims as the title
我们稍微修改一下，将标题改为 froshims
just so we know we're looking at the right application.
这样我们就知道我们正在查看正确的应用程序。
And, now, let me go ahead and create a new file called how
现在，我将创建一个名为 how 的新文件
about index.html inside of templates that,
about index.html，放在 templates 文件夹中，
just as before, is going to extend that there template, so extends layout.html.
就像之前一样，它将继承模板，因此使用 extends layout.html。
Inside of here, I'm going to say block body just as before.
在这里，我将像之前一样输入 block body。
Preemptively going to say endblock.
提前输入 endblock。
And then, inside of here, I'm going to make
然后，在这里，我将创建
the beginnings of a super simple web page for first-year intramural.
一个非常简单的网页，用于一年级校内联赛报名。
So I'm going to use an h1 tag that's sort of big and bold that
因此我将使用 h1 标签，它比较大，而且加粗，
just says register at the top of the page sort of like a title.
它在页面顶部显示 “register”，有点像标题。
Below that, I'm going to have a form.
在下面，我将添加一个表单。
The action of this form I'm going to say proactively is going to say
我将提前声明该表单的 action 属性为
to /register.
/register。
So that's a to do.
所以，这是一个待办事项。
We're going to have to go implement a register route.
我们将需要实现一个 register 路由。
The method I'm going to use is post just for privacy's sake
我将使用 post 方法，纯粹为了保护隐私
so that if roommates are sharing the same computer,
这样，如果室友共用一台电脑，
they don't see, in the autocomplete, who's registered for what.
他们就不会在自动完成功能中看到谁注册了哪个项目。
Inside of that form, I'm going to have a single input first where
在表单中，我将首先添加一个单独的输入框，
autocomplete is off.
自动完成功能已关闭。
Autofocus is on.
自动聚焦功能已打开。
The name of this field will be name because I want
该字段的名称将是 name，因为我想
to ask the humans for their human name.
向用户询问他们的姓名。
The placeholder, just to be self-describing,
占位符，为了自描述，
is going to be, quote, unquote, "Name", capital N grammatically.
将是双引号包裹的 “Name”，首字母 N 大写，符合语法。
And then, lastly, the type of this field, though it's the default,
最后，该字段的类型，虽然是默认类型，
is text.
是 text。
So, so far, this is actually pretty darn similar to the hello example
到目前为止，这与 hello 示例非常相似
soliciting someone's name.
用于获取用户姓名。
But now I want to maybe implement a dropdown
但现在我可能想实现一个下拉
menu via which you can select a sport.
菜单，用于选择运动项目。
And, back in the day, I think the first version of froshims,
以前，我认为 froshims 的第一个版本，
students could only register for basketball, soccer,
学生只能注册篮球、足球，
and ultimate Frisbee.
以及极限飞盘。
So those were three of the fall sports.
所以，这三个是秋季运动项目。
So let me do this.
所以，让我来做这个。
It's a little weirdly named, but a dropdown menu in HTML
它有一个有点奇怪的名字，但在 HTML 中，下拉菜单
is called a select menu because you select something from it.
被称为选择菜单，因为你可以从中选择某些东西。
The name of this input, which is really what it is, is going to be sport.
这个输入的名称，实际上它就是这个，将是 sport。
Though, I could call the input anything I want.
不过，我可以随意给输入命名。
And, inside of this select element, I'm going to have a few options.
而且，在这个选择元素内部，我将有一些选项。
I'm going to have one where the option is how about basketball?
我将有一个选项是篮球怎么样？
Another option, the value of which is soccer.
另一个选项，它的值是足球。
And, lastly, a third option, the value of which is ultimate Frisbee.
最后，第三个选项，它的值是极限飞盘。
So just those three sports.
所以只有这三种运动。
But suffice it to say we could add even more.
但足以说明我们可以添加更多。
And then, outside of this select menu, I'm
然后，在这个选择菜单之外，我
going to have a button just like the hello example, the type of which
将有一个按钮，就像 hello 示例一样，它的类型
is submit, just to be super explicit even though that's not
是提交，为了非常明确，尽管这并不是
strictly necessary.
严格必要的。
But it's another attribute you'll see in the wild.
但这是你在野外会看到的另一个属性。
And then the name on the value of this button will be register.
然后这个按钮的名称或值将是 register。
So it's clear that you're not being greeted,
所以很明显，你并没有被问候，
but you're actually registering for sports.
而你实际上是报名参加运动。
Now, we're not quite good to go yet, but let me go into VS code's terminal
现在，我们还没有完全准备好，但让我进入 VS Code 的终端
again.
再来。
Let me open up app.py and close my terminal again.
让我打开 app.py 并再次关闭我的终端。
And let's just whittle this down to something super simple.
我们只需把它简化为一个非常简单的东西。
I don't want to get overwhelmed just yet.
我不想现在就感到不知所措。
I don't want to support even POST.
我甚至不想支持 POST。
So let's just whittle this down to the essence of this.
所以我们只需把它简化为它的本质。
So I can do a quick check mentally and make sure now,
所以我可以在脑海中快速检查一下，现在确保
when I run flask, that I'm serving up that registration form.
当我运行 Flask 时，我正在提供那个注册表单。
So, in my terminal, I'm going to run flask run in my froshims folder.
所以，在我的终端中，我将在我 froshims 文件夹中运行 flask run。
So far, so good.
到目前为止，一切顺利。
It's going to be by default the same URL unless I've rebuilt or created
它默认情况下将是同一个 URL，除非我重建或创建
a brand new codespace.
一个全新的代码空间。
So let me go back to my other tab and reload that URL.
所以让我回到我的另一个选项卡并重新加载那个 URL。
And, OK, we've got the beginnings of a more interesting form now.
好的，我们现在有了更有趣表单的雏形。
So it's got place for my name.
所以它有我的名字的占位符。
It's got a dropdown for the three sports.
它有一个包含三种运动的下拉菜单。
So let's see what happens, D-A-V-I-D. We'll say soccer.
所以让我们看看会发生什么，D-A-V-I-D。我们说足球。
And, when I click Register, just to be clear, what route will
然后，当我点击注册时，为了清楚起见，我将通过哪个路由
I find myself at per my URL?
在 URL 中找到我自己？
Slash.
斜杠。
What was it to be?
它是什么？
If I go back into my index.
如果我回到我的索引。
/register.
/register。
But what error will I see presumably at this point in time,
但到目前为止，我可能会看到什么错误，
given that app.py has only been implemented to this extent?
鉴于 app.py 仅实现了到目前为止的内容？
So probably 404 because the route won't be found.
所以可能是 404，因为找不到路由。
So if I click Register, I indeed end up at /register.
所以，如果我点击注册，我确实最终到了 /register。
But if I zoom in up top here, 404 not found.
但是，如果我在这里放大到顶部，404 未找到。
All right, so it's the beginnings of an application.
好的，所以这是一个应用程序的开端。
But I've not-- I've implemented the front end, so to speak,
但我还没有——可以说，我实现了前端，
the user interface but not the back end, the business logic that actually
用户界面，但不是后端，实际处理用户输入的业务逻辑，
does something with the user input.
对用户输入做些什么。
But a couple of enhancements here.
但是这里有一些改进。
But these are largely niceties in HTML.
但这些基本上只是 HTML 中的一些细微之处。
It's a little bad user experience that by default you're
默认情况下，这有点糟糕的用户体验，因为你正在
registering for basketball.
注册篮球项目。
I mean, that's fine.
我的意思是，这很好。
But, arguably, you're biasing people toward registering for basketball.
但可以说，你正在诱导人们注册篮球项目。
Or they might not realize that they're registering for basketball because they
或者他们可能没有意识到他们正在注册篮球项目，因为他们
didn't explicitly choose a sport.
没有明确选择一项运动。
So having a random, an arbitrary default that
因此，有一个随机的、任意的默认值，
just happens to be the first word alphabetically
正好是字母顺序上的第一个词，
is a little weak when it comes to design.
在设计方面有点弱。
So there's different ways to fix this.
所以有很多方法可以解决这个问题。
But one way is to do this.
但其中一种方法是这样做。
Add a new option at the very top.
在最上面添加一个新的选项。
But go ahead and disable it so that the user can't themselves
但继续禁用它，这样用户就不能自己
select it because you want them to select an actual sport.
选择它，因为你希望他们选择一项真正的运动。
By default, you can specify that it's indeed selected.
默认情况下，你可以指定它确实被选中。
And it has no value.
而且它没有值。
So not to judge any sport, but this particular option has no value.
所以，不是要评判任何运动，而是这个特定的选项没有值。
But what the human sees is the word sport, for instance.
但人类看到的是“运动”这个词，例如。
So this is kind of a hack.
所以这有点像黑客手段。
Ideally, the Select menu would just have a placeholder attribute
理想情况下，选择菜单只需要一个占位符属性
like the actual input boxes does.
就像实际的输入框一样。
But that does not exist.
但它不存在。
So if I reload now, it looks a little more user friendly.
所以，如果我现在重新加载，它看起来会更人性化一些。
So it says sport.
所以它显示“运动”。
I can't select sport ever again.
我以后再也不能选择“运动”了。
But it is the default, but I can select one of these three sports
但它是默认值，但我可以从这三种运动中选择一种
which just increases the probability that the human does
这只是增加了人们会这样做的可能性
what you might expect.
你可能会预料到的。
Of course, there's something else I can add here.
当然，我还可以在这里添加其他内容。
Suppose I don't even give my name.
假设我甚至不输入我的名字。
It still went through.
它仍然通过了。
It didn't work.
它没有成功。
It's still a 405, but the--
它仍然是 405，但是——
404.
404。
But the browser didn't stop me.
但浏览器没有阻止我。
So recall that we do have some other tricks.
所以请记住，我们还有一些其他技巧。
For instance, I can say that this dropdown, this select menu
例如，我可以说这个下拉菜单，这个选择菜单
is itself required-- or, sorry, not this one.
本身是必需的——或者，抱歉，不是这个。
The text box is itself required, for instance.
例如，文本框本身是必需的。
So now if I go back to the form and reload
所以现在，如果我返回表单并重新加载
and I just ignore the name question and click Register,
而我只是忽略姓名问题并点击注册，
the browser's going to yell at me.
浏览器会警告我。
Now, recall that this is not robust.
现在，请记住，这不是健壮的。
Client-side validation is not good.
客户端验证不好。
Why?
为什么？
What'd we learn last week?
我们上周学了什么？
Yeah, I mean, I can literally right-click or Control-click
是的，我的意思是，我可以直接右键单击或 Ctrl+单击
and open up Developer Tools.
并打开开发者工具。
I can go into that form using the Developer Tools.
我可以使用开发者工具进入该表单。
I can literally find the word required, delete it, and voila.
我可以直接找到 "required" 这个词，删除它，然后就完成了。
This form will now go through because the browser's
现在，这个表单将能够提交，因为浏览器
going to do what I change.
将执行我所做的更改。
So it's useful for user experience, making just things a little prettier
因此，它对用户体验很有用，使事情看起来更漂亮
and faster to validate.
并且更快速地进行验证。
But it's not going to be robust defense.
但它不会成为可靠的防御措施。
All right, so let's go back now to VS Code into my actual route
好的，现在让我们回到 VS Code，进入我的实际路由
and implement at least something here that resembles registration.
并在这里实现至少类似注册的功能。
So I'm going to go into app.py.
所以，我将进入 app.py。
And, in app.py, let's create this second route.
在 app.py 中，让我们创建第二个路由。
So, at app.route, quote, unquote, "/register"
因此，在 app.route，引号引起来，"/register"
to match what is in my HTML.
以匹配我 HTML 中的内容。
Let me define a function.
让我定义一个函数。
I can call it anything I want.
我可以随意命名它。
But, again, good convention to just call it the same thing as the route
但同样，良好的习惯是将其命名与路由相同
name so you don't get out of sync.
名称，这样你就不会不同步。
And then there's a couple of things I might want to do.
然后，我可能想做几件事。
When you register for this particular form,
当您注册此特定表单时，
what are the two things that the server should probably check for?
服务器应该检查哪些两件事？
What kind of logic should I have here?
我应该在这里使用什么样的逻辑？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] at anything for [INAUDIBLE]..
观众：[听不清] 任何东西 [听不清]..
DAVID J. MALAN: OK, so let's make sure that the name is present
大卫·马兰：好的，所以让我们确保名称存在
and the sport is present, ideally.
并且理想情况下，运动也存在。
So let's actually validate the user's input just like get int
所以，让我们像 get int 一样验证用户的输入
did back in week one.
在第一周做的那样。
Just like get string, get float, and all of those,
就像 get string、get float 和所有那些，
they made sure that you actually got input.
它们确保您确实获得了输入。
So there's a bunch of ways I can do this,
所以我有很多方法可以做到这一点，
but I'm going to go ahead and take a relatively canonical approach.
但我将采用一种相对规范的方法。
If not request.form.get, quote, unquote, "name",
如果 request.form.get，引号引起来，"name" 不存在，
I'm going to go ahead and then return, how about let's just see,
我会继续执行，然后返回，让我们看看，
failure, quote, unquote, "failure" just as a quick and dirty solution.
failure，引号引起来，"failure" 作为一个快速而肮脏的解决方案。
So if it is not the case that there is a value for the name field,
所以，如果名称字段没有值，
just assume that there's a failure.
就假设出现了错误。
So how can I test this?
那么，我该如何测试呢？
Let me go back to the other tab.
让我回到另一个选项卡。
Let me go ahead and not type in my name and click Register.
让我不要输入我的名字，然后单击注册。
And notice-- well, OK, I need to get rid of the required
然后注意 -- 好的，我需要去掉 "required"
if I actually want to see this thing go through.
如果我真的想看到这个东西被提交。
So you know what?
所以，你知道吗？
Let's just change the template.
让我们更改模板。
Let's get rid of that so I don't have to hack into it
让我们去掉它，这样我就不必手动入侵它
and delete things manually.
并手动删除内容。
So let me reload the form.
所以，让我重新加载表单。
Let me not type a name.
让我不输入名字。
Click register.
点击注册。
And, oh, dang it.
哦，糟糕。
405, Method Not Allowed.
405，方法不允许。
What's the fix for this in my app.py?
我的 app.py 中怎么解决这个问题？
What line number needs to change?
哪一行代码需要修改？
Yeah, over there.
对，就在那里。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, I need to allow both or at least POST at this point.
是的，我需要允许两者，或者至少允许 POST 方法。
So I'll keep it more restrictive.
所以我将限制更严格。
So methods equals and then in a list, quote, unquote,
所以 methods 等于一个列表，用引号括起来，
POST because that's what I'm using in my template as the method.
POST，因为这是我在模板中用作方法的。
All right, let's try again.
好吧，我们再试一次。
I'm going to go back.
我要返回。
I'm going to not type a name, and I'm going to click Register.
我不会输入名字，然后点击注册。
OK, so we caught the fact that the name was not provided.
好的，我们捕捉到了没有提供名字的事实。
Let's now go back and try again and actually cooperate.
现在让我们返回，再试一次，并真正合作。
David, Register, OK, now internal server error.
David，注册，好的，现在是内部服务器错误。
So something's gone even worse here.
所以这里出了更大的问题。
And, unfortunately, you're going to start to see
不幸的是，在接下来的几周里你会开始看到
this over the next couple of weeks.
这种情况。
This is like Python and the web's equivalent of segmentation fault.
这就像 Python 和 Web 的等效于段错误。
It's a different issue, but it's going to hurt just the same, unfortunately.
这是一个不同的问题，但不幸的是，它会带来同样的痛苦。
So let's go back to VS Code here.
所以让我们回到这里的 VS Code。
Nothing seems to have gone wrong, but that's because I've hidden my terminal.
似乎没有出错，但那是因为我隐藏了我的终端。
Let me open my terminal window, and, oh, OK, so
让我打开我的终端窗口，哦，好的，所以
it looks like I made a crazy number of mistakes here somehow.
看起来我在这里犯了很多错误。
But let me go ahead and focus on--
但我继续关注 -
and the formatting's a little weird for some reason.
并且格式有点奇怪，不知道为什么。
Here we go.
来了。
It's a little cryptic at first glance, but here's
乍一看有点神秘，但这里
the most important line of output.
是最重要的输出行。
The view function for, quote, unquote, "Register" did not
“Register” 的视图函数没有
return a valid response.
返回有效的响应。
So you're not going to see this one too often
所以你不太可能经常看到它
most likely unless you do what I did, which was you didn't have an else.
除非你像我一样，没有 else 语句。
You didn't handle the situation where there is a name
你没有处理有名字的情况
and something should've come back.
应该返回一些东西。
So maybe I could do this.
所以也许我可以这样做。
By default, I could just say something like success as a catch
默认情况下，我可以简单地说像 success 这样的捕获
all even though I've not done anything useful yet.
尽管我还没有做任何有用的事情。
Let me try this again.
让我再试一次。
Let me go back.
让我回去。
David is typed in.
David 已经输入了。
No sport, Register.
没有运动，注册。
OK, so now I'm making progress again.
好的，我现在又取得了进展。
So just like week one stuff, I make sure I'm always returning some value,
所以就像第一周的内容一样，我确保我总是返回一些值，
whether it's success or failure in this case.
无论在这种情况下是成功还是失败。
All right, let's do something a little more interesting, though.
好吧，让我们做一些更有趣的事情吧。
I could do this.
我可以这样做。
How about elif not request.form.get sport.
如果我们使用 `elif not request.form.get sport` 会怎么样？
I could similarly return failure.
我可以同样返回一个失败信息。
But this is a little silly to have two nearly identical conditionals.
但是，拥有两个几乎相同的条件语句有点蠢。
So, actually, let me just tighten this up.
所以，让我来简化一下。
Let me go ahead and, instead, get rid of those two lines
让我来把这两行代码删掉，
and maybe just do something like this in Python or not request.form.get sport.
然后用 Python 写成这样，或者用 `not request.form.get sport`。
This is maybe the tightest way just to ask two questions that are essentially
这也许是最紧凑的方式，可以同时问两个本质上
the same but for two different keys.
相同的问题，但是针对两个不同的键值。
But returning, quote, unquote, "failure"'s a little weak.
但是返回一个 `failure`  有点弱。
That's not a valid web page.
那不是一个有效的网页。
It's literally the word failure.
它只是单词 `failure`。
So maybe we do this, render_template, quote, unquote, "failure.html".
所以，也许我们可以使用 `render_template` 并返回 `failure.html` 文件。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
Down here, render_template success.html.
在下方，我们用 `render_template` 返回 `success.html`。
So we actually send the browser a valid web page, not just
所以，我们实际上向浏览器发送一个有效的网页，而不是仅仅
a single English word.
一个英文单词。
Of course, we're going to need those templates.
当然，我们需要那些模板。
So let me go in and do something like this.
所以，让我来做一些事情。
If I go into, how about, my terminal window.
如果我进入我的终端窗口。
I need another terminal because Flask is still running in that one.
我需要另外一个终端，因为 Flask 还在之前的终端中运行。
Let me go into froshims and let me do code of templates success.html.
让我进入 `froshims` 目录，然后在 `templates` 文件夹中创建 `success.html`。
I'm going to save a few keystrokes and copy-paste all that stuff from index.
为了节省一些按键，我要从 `index.html` 文件中复制粘贴一些内容。
But I'm going to delete most of it.
但是我将删除大部分内容。
And I'm just going to keep it super simple today.
我今天就将其保持超级简单。
You are registered.
你已经注册了。
And then-- well, really, not really because we're
然后，实际上，并不是真的因为我们
not going to bother doing anything yet with the user's input.
现在还没有打算对用户输入进行任何处理。
Let me do something similar now for failure.
现在，让我为 `failure` 文件做一些类似的事情。
So code templates failure.html.
创建 `templates` 文件夹中的 `failure.html` 文件。
I'm going to copy-paste the same thing.
我将复制粘贴相同的内容。
And now I'm going to say the opposite, You are not registered.
现在，我要说相反的内容，你没有注册。
But I'm not going to be very useful, and I'm not
但我不会很有用，也不会
going to even yet tell the user what they have done wrong.
告诉用户他们做错了什么。
But at least now we have the beginnings of a froshims app.
但至少我们现在已经有了 `froshims` 应用的雏形。
So let me go back, reload everything.
所以，让我回到首页，刷新一下页面。
Let me not cooperate at all and click Register.
让我不合作一下，点击注册按钮。
OK, so you are not registered because of some failure.
好的，你没有注册，因为某些错误。
I'll type in my name.
我会输入我的名字。
OK, let's at least do that much.
好的，至少要做到这一点。
I'm still not registered.
我仍然没有注册。
Let's go back.
让我们回到首页。
Let's leave David and choose soccer.
让我们把 `David` 改成 `soccer`。
Now, OK, now you are registered.
好的，现在你已经注册了。
So I got the success template instead.
所以，我得到了 `success` 模板。
All right, so that seems to be better progress or at least the beginnings
好的，看起来这是一个不错的进步，或者至少是一个开始
of an actually useful application.
一个真正有用的应用程序的开始。
But let's actually do more validation.
但是，让我们来进行更多验证。
Why?
为什么？
Because notice what the human could still do.
因为注意，人类仍然可以做些什么。
Suppose that, out of principle, you really
假设，出于原则，你真的
want to register for a different sport.
想注册一个不同的运动项目。
So you're not a fan of soccer.
所以你不太喜欢足球？
You want American football.
你想玩美式橄榄球。
So let's right-click or Control-click on that.
所以让我们右键点击或 Ctrl 键点击它。
Choose Inspect.
选择检查。
And you can even do this client side.
你甚至可以在客户端进行操作。
Let me write click on the Select menu.
让我右键点击“选择”菜单。
In Chrome, let me select Edit as HTML.
在 Chrome 中，让我选择“以 HTML 编辑”。
You can start adding any HTML you want.
你可以开始添加任何你想要的 HTML 代码。
So let me add an option football close option enter.
所以让我添加一个选项“足球”，然后关闭选项并按回车键。
And, aha, now you have to support football as well.
然后，啊哈，现在你必须支持美式橄榄球了。
Of course, this is going to work because if I type in David and football
当然，这会起作用，因为如果我在里面输入 David 和足球
and Register even though I'm not doing anything with the response,
并点击“注册”，即使我没有对响应做任何操作，
I got through that validation filter because I was just
我通过了那个验证过滤器，因为我只是
checking that there's an actual value.
检查是否存在实际的值。
So this is now no longer really correct because some annoying first year who's
所以现在这不再完全正确了，因为一些讨厌的 CS50 大一新生会
just taken CS50 is now going to do something
刚学完 CS50 就去做一些
like this to my web application.
类似这样的事情来破坏我的网页应用。
And we're going to have bogus data in the database, ultimately.
最终，我们的数据库中将会有虚假数据。
So how do you defend against this properly when it really is that easy?
所以，当事情真的很容易时，你如何才能正确地防御这种攻击？
And, honestly, as soon as you put a web application on the internet,
老实说，一旦你把一个网页应用放到互联网上，
bad things will happen to it because people with too much free time.
它就会遭殃，因为那些有太多空闲时间的人会捣乱。
So how do we defend against it?
所以我们如何防御这种攻击呢？
What would be a better approach?
更好的方法是什么？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Nice, so add another conditional such
很好，所以添加另一个条件，
that the only things allowed are the sports we actually
以便只允许我们实际提供的运动项目
are offering this semester.
在本学期提供。
And, in fact, you know what?
事实上，你知道吗？
We can take this one step further.
我们可以更进一步。
The fact that I hardcoded into my form, my select menu, those three sports--
我将这三个运动项目硬编码到了我的表单和下拉菜单中，
it'd be nice to maybe factor out those sports altogether
最好能把这些运动项目完全分离出来
so that I have one authoritative list that's used for generating the form
这样我就可以有一个权威的列表，用来生成表单
and also validating the user's input.
以及验证用户的输入。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这件事。
In app.py, let me go in here.
在 app.py 中，让我进入这里。
And I can put this, how about, the top of my file, to be conventional.
我可以把它放到文件顶部，这是惯例。
I'm going to create a global variable called sports.
我将创建一个名为 sports 的全局变量。
By convention, in Python, I'm going to make it all uppercase even though that
按照惯例，在 Python 中，我将把它全部大写，尽管这
doesn't mean anything functional.
并没有什么功能上的意义。
There's no const keyword in Python.
Python 中没有 const 关键字。
So it's more on the honor system that no one else should touch this.
所以，更多的是一种道德约束，即其他人不应该修改它。
But, inside of my list here, let's go ahead
但是，在我的列表里，让我们继续
and do only the official three, basketball, soccer,
只添加三个官方的项目：篮球、足球
and ultimate Frisbee.
和极限飞盘。
So now I have a Python list of values that it
所以现在我有一个 Python 列表，它包含了
would be nice to use to generate that other form.
用来生成那个表单的值，这会很棒。
So this is maybe nonobvious.
所以这可能不太明显。
But I think it's just an application of past ideas.
但我认为这只是对过去想法的应用。
What if I do this?
如果我这样做呢？
What if I pass into my index.html template
如果我传递到我的 index.html 模板中
a placeholder called sports and set it equal to the value
一个名为 sports 的占位符，并将其设置为等于该值
of that global variable sports.
该全局变量 sports 的值。
Now, I'm trying to adhere to best practices.
现在，我正在尝试遵循最佳实践。
The placeholder is called sports in lowercase.
占位符被称为 sports，用小写字母。
But the actual variable I called all uppercase just
但实际变量我全部用大写字母命名只是
to make clear that it's a constant even though that's on the honor system.
为了明确它是一个常量，即使这只是基于信任系统。
But this too is conventional.
但这也很常规。
This is a Pythonic way or a Flask-centric way to do this.
这是一种 Python 风格或 Flask 中心化的做法。
But now, in index.html, this is where Jinja gets interesting.
但现在，在 index.html 中，这里就是 Jinja 开始变得有趣的地方。
This lightweight syntax for using placeholders
这种轻量级的占位符使用语法
gets interesting because I can now do something like this.
变得有趣，因为我现在可以做一些类似的事情。
I'm going to delete all three of the sports
我要删除所有三个运动
but not the disabled option, which is just the placeholder text, inside
但不是禁用选项，它只是占位符文本，在里面
of this select menu.
这个下拉菜单中。
Now I'm going to do this.
现在我要这样做。
Just like Python, I'm going to say for sport
就像 Python 一样，我要说 for sport
in sports using the curly brace notation and the percent signs, which
在 sports 中使用花括号和百分号，它们
are Jinja specific even though Jinja and Python use almost the same syntax.
是 Jinja 特定的，即使 Jinja 和 Python 使用几乎相同的语法。
And that's one of the upsides of it.
这也是它的优势之一。
You're not learning two things.
你不用学两件事。
You're learning 1.1 new things.
你学的是 1.1 件新东西。
endfor, which looks stupid, but this is a convention
endfor，看起来很傻，但这是一种约定
in a lot of languages to literally say end and the name of the keyword
在很多语言中，实际上就是说 end 和关键字的名称
that you are ending with no space.
你结束的地方，没有空格。
Inside of this Jinja loop, I'm going to write an option element once, option.
在这个 Jinja 循环中，我将编写一个 option 元素，一次，option。
And then, inside of the two option tags, I'm
然后，在两个 option 标签中，我
going to do my placeholder syntax with two curly braces
将使用我的占位符语法，用两个花括号
and just say sport like this.
并像这样说 sport。
And if I now go back into my browser tab and hit back here
如果我现在回到我的浏览器标签并点击返回这里
and I reload the page, notice that I still
然后我重新加载页面，请注意我仍然
have a dropdown that's still automatically populated
有一个下拉菜单，它仍然自动填充
because indeed if I go to View page source and look at the actual HTML,
因为实际上，如果我查看页面源代码并查看实际的 HTML，
there's some extra weird whitespace, but that's
有一些额外的奇怪空格，但那是
because I hit Enter in my template.
因为我在我的模板中按了回车键。
And it's generating literally what I put inside of that Jinja tag.
它正在生成我放在那个 Jinja 标签里面的内容。
It's generating that list of sports.
它正在生成那个运动列表。
And it turns out--
事实证明——
I'm going to do this just to be thorough.
我要做这件事，仅仅是为了彻底。
It turns out that the option element technically lets
事实证明，option 元素从技术上讲允许
you specify a value for that sport.
你指定该运动的值。
Often, they're one and the same.
通常，它们是一样的。
What the human sees is what the value of the option is.
人类看到的是选项的值。
It's kind of like the a href thing in the world of URLs.
这有点像 URL 世界中的 a href 东西。
But this is not going to change the functionality.
但这不会改变功能。
But it's going to do this.
但它将执行此操作。
If I reload now and I View page source, this is maybe a more common way
如果我现在重新加载并查看页面源代码，这可能是一种更常见的方式
to see options where, in orange, in my browser,
查看选项，用橙色显示在我的浏览器中，
is what the server is going to receive.
是服务器将要接收的内容。
In white is what the human's going to see.
白色是人类将要看到的内容。
They don't have to be one and the same for reasons we'll soon see.
它们不必完全相同，原因我们很快就会看到。
But what's nice now is that if I do actually
但现在很好的是，如果我真的
want to officially support American football, I can go in here,
想正式支持美式足球，我可以在这里，
add "football", quote, unquote, to my list,
将“足球”添加到我的列表中，
go back to the form, reload, and voila.
回到表单，重新加载，瞧。
Now I have a list of all four.
现在我有四个的列表。
But I haven't done the second side of what you proposed,
但我还没有做你提议的第二部分，
which is actually validate those sports.
那就是验证那些运动。
So let me do that.
所以让我来做。
Let me go over to app.py.
让我去看看 app.py。
And, in app.py-- and we'll no longer support football there--
在 app.py 中，我们不再支持那里的足球，
let's do this in my registration route.
让我们在注册路线中做这个。
So, instead of just checking, is there a value?
所以，与其只是检查是否有值，
And the whole point of using not is kind of like in C
使用“not”的整个要点就像在 C 中
where you use an exclamation point to invert the meaning.
你用感叹号来反转含义。
So if it's empty but it's not, then it's-- the whole value is true.
所以，如果它为空，但它不为空，那么它是——整个值都是真的。
Let's get rid of this line.
让我们去掉这行。
And let's instead do something like this.
让我们改为做这样的事情。
How about if not request.form.get name.
如果 request.form.get name 不是，怎么样？
So let's still just check for a name.
所以让我们还是只检查是否有名字。
Or request.form.get, quote, unquote, "sport" is not in the sports list.
或者 request.form.get，引号，“sport”不在体育列表中。
Now go ahead and say there's a failure.
现在说一下有错误。
So what does this mean?
所以这意味着什么？
If I go back to the browser and reload, I now see only three sports.
如果我回到浏览器并重新加载，现在我只能看到三种运动。
And I think this will work,
我认为这会奏效，
OK, David.
好的，大卫。
We'll register, say, for soccer, Register, and it seems to work.
我们将注册，比如，足球，注册，看起来它奏效了。
But if some hacker comes along and really
但如果一些黑客出现，并且真的
wants to register for American football, I'll right-click there.
想要注册美式足球，我会在那里右键单击。
I'll inspect this.
我会检查一下。
I'm going to hack the form and add a bogus option
我将破解表单并添加一个虚假选项
at the very end just for myself.
在最后，只是为了我自己。
And, down here, I'm going to say option value equals, quote, unquote,
然后，在下面，我要说 option value 等于，引号，
"football".
“足球”。
And then, inside of the option, I'm going
然后，在选项内部，我将
to say football just to be consistent even though they're one and the same.
说足球，为了保持一致，尽管它们是同一个。
Save that.
保存。
Close the developer tools.
关闭开发者工具。
Choose the hacked option.
选择破解的选项。
Register, but, no, we caught it this time.
注册，但是，不，这次我们抓住了它。
So this is hugely important.
所以这非常重要。
And there are so many darn websites in the real world where
现实世界中，有太多糟糕的网站，
the programmers either don't know or don't care
程序员要么不知道，要么不关心
to actually validate stuff server side.
实际上在服务器端验证东西。
This is how servers quite often get hacked.
这就是服务器经常被黑客入侵的方式。
You might have client-side validation using HTML or JavaScript.
你可能使用 HTML 或 JavaScript 进行客户端验证。
And it looks nice.
看起来不错。
It's immediate.
它是即时的。
It's very pretty and graphical.
它非常漂亮，图形化。
But if you're not also paranoically checking on the server,
但如果你没有偏执地检查服务器，
this is indeed how servers get hacked.
这确实就是服务器被黑客攻击的方式。
Or, at least in the best case here, your data set
或者，至少在最好的情况下，你的数据集
is sort of polluted with sports that you're not actually going to offer.
会充满你不打算提供的运动。
So this is not a very harmful attack, but it's
所以这不是一个非常有害的攻击，但它是
representative of what kind of actions can be taken on your server
代表了在你的服务器上可以采取的行动类型
if you don't distrust the user.
如果你不怀疑用户。
So, unfortunately, this is kind of a negative day.
所以，不幸的是，今天有点负面。
Never, ever trust user input.
永远不要信任用户输入。
We saw that already with SQL and injection attacks.
我们已经在 SQL 和注入攻击中看到了这一点。
All right, any other questions?
好的，还有其他问题吗？
Any questions thus far on this?
到目前为止对此有任何问题吗？
Otherwise, we'll add a bit of spice in just a moment.
否则，我们一会儿会加点调味料。
No?
没有？
All right, well, just to show you an alternative to this,
好的，为了向你展示一个替代方案，
let me change the GUI, the Graphical User Interface, slightly.
让我稍微改变一下 GUI，图形用户界面。
Drop-down menus pretty compelling here.
下拉菜单在这里非常引人注目。
But there's other techniques.
但还有其他技术。
And we won't dwell on HTML tags, which you can pick up largely online.
我们不会详细讨论 HTML 标签，你可以在网上找到大部分内容。
But let me go into maybe index.html just to show you
但让我进入 index.html，向你展示
one different approach here.
这里一种不同的方法。
And if you really like radio buttons, the little circles that
如果你真的喜欢单选按钮，那些小圆圈
are mutually exclusive-- this is a throwback to radios, before my time,
是互斥的——这是对无线电的回归，在我那个时代之前，
in cars where, when you pushed the button for one radio station,
在汽车上，当你按下某个广播电台的按钮时，
it would pop out the buttons for another, essentially,
它会弹出另一个的按钮，本质上，
for your favorite channels.
为了你最喜欢的频道。
Radio buttons are, by definition, therefore, mutually exclusive.
因此，根据定义，单选按钮是互斥的。
So if I want to see those radio buttons and not a select menu,
所以如果我想看到这些单选按钮，而不是一个下拉菜单，
let me go into index.html.
让我进入 index.html。
And, instead of this select menu, let me actually delete that.
然后，代替这个下拉菜单，让我把它删除。
And even though this isn't going to be super pretty, let me do this.
虽然这看起来不会超级漂亮，但让我这样做。
for sport in sports, just as before, endfor, just preemptively.
对于运动中的运动，就像之前一样，结束循环，先发制人。
Inside of this Jinja loop, I'm going to do this.
在这个 Jinja 循环中，我要这样做。
I'm going to do an actual input tag.
我将使用一个真正的 input 标签。
But it's not going to be text.
但它不会是文本。
But the name of this tag--
但这个标签的名称——
of this element is going to be sport.
这个元素的名称将是 sport。
The type of this element is going to be radio for radio buttons.
这个元素的类型将是 radio，用于单选按钮。
And the value of this button is going to be whatever that sport is.
这个按钮的值将是该运动。
But what the human is going to see next to the radio button to the right
但人类在单选按钮右侧看到的是
is the same thing, the name of the sport.
同样的东西，运动的名称。
So this is going to look a little different.
所以这看起来会有点不同。
And it is going to look ugly in my black and white viewport here with no CSS.
而且在没有 CSS 的黑白视窗中，它看起来会很丑。
But it does speak to how you can change the user interface just using
但这确实说明了如何仅使用不同的构建块来更改用户界面。
different building blocks.
不同的构建块。
Let me reload.
让我重新加载一下。
And, OK, it's probably not the right call here
好的，这可能不是这里的正确做法
because it's just kind of making things ugly.
因为它只是让事情变得难看。
But it's as simple as that because if I now click on this or this or this,
但这很简单，因为如果我现在点击这个，这个或者这个，
they're indeed mutually exclusive.
它们确实互斥。
However, suppose that you want to allow the particularly athletic first years
但是，假设你想允许那些特别有运动天赋的一年级新生
to sign up for not one but two sports or all three.
报名参加一项运动，而是两项或三项。
In no case now can you support that right now.
现在，你无法支持这种情况。
The workaround now for a bad website would
对于一个糟糕的网站，现在的变通方法是
be, oh, just go register twice, or go register three times.
哦，就是去注册两次，或者去注册三次。
It's not a huge deal because you just hit back.
这不是什么大问题，因为你只需要点击返回。
And then you change the dropdown and submit.
然后你改变下拉菜单并提交。
You hit back you change the dropdown and submit.
你点击返回，改变下拉菜单并提交。
But that's just bad design.
但这只是糟糕的设计。
Surely, we can do better than that.
当然，我们可以做得更好。
So, in fact, let's make one change here and use checkboxes.
所以，实际上，让我们在这里进行一个更改，使用复选框。
And if you've never really thought hard about this in the web,
如果你以前从未真正认真想过这个问题，
radio buttons and checkboxes have this distinct property
单选按钮和复选框具有这种独特的属性
where the former is mutually exclusive, and the latter
前者是互斥的，而后者
is inclusive whereby you can check 0 or more of those boxes collectively.
是包含的，你可以集体选中这些框中的 0 个或多个。
So if I actually just go into that same template
所以，如果我真的进入那个相同的模板
and change the type of this input from radio to checkbox
并将此输入的类型从单选按钮更改为复选框
and then go back to the browser and reload,
然后回到浏览器并重新加载，
you immediately get what you and I see in the real world as checkboxes.
你会立即得到你和我，在现实世界中所看到的复选框。
And the upside of this is that you can check now 0 or more of them.
这样做的好处是，你现在可以选中 0 个或多个。
But the catch-- and this is subtle--
但是问题是——而且这一点很微妙——
the catch with our code right now is that we're only expecting one value.
我们现在代码的问题是，我们只期望一个值。
So it's a minor fix, but it's a useful thing to know.
所以这是一个小修补，但这是一个有用的知识。
If I go back to app.py, if I actually want to get all of the sports
如果我回到 app.py，如果我真的想获取所有运动
from the users, I'm going to have to change my validation slightly.
来自用户，我将不得不稍微改变一下我的验证。
So I'm going to do this.
所以我会这样做。
I'm going to check for the presence of a name as before.
我将像以前一样检查是否存在一个名字。
But then I'm going to use a loop to validate the sports because I
但随后，我将使用一个循环来验证这些运动，因为我
don't want them to slip, like football, back into the list
不想让它们溜回去，就像足球一样，回到列表中
even if it's not there.
即使它不在那里。
So I'm going to say this in Python.
所以我会在 Python 中这样写。
for each sport in request.form.getall.
对于 request.form.getall 中的每项运动
If you know it's a checkbox, you want to get all of the checked values, not one,
如果你知道它是一个复选框，你想要获取所有选中的值，而不是一个，
for the sport parameter, then go ahead and do this.
对于 sport 参数，然后继续执行此操作。
If the current sport is not in that sports list up top,
如果当前运动不在顶部的那个运动列表中，
then go ahead and return render_template failure.html.
那么，继续返回 render_template failure.html。
Did I make a mistake here?
我在这里犯错了吗？
I think we're good there.
我认为我们在这里没问题。
So we're checking against every value that was checked on the form.
所以我们正在检查表单中所选中的每个值。
Is it actually valid?
它是否有效？
And so now if I go in here, reload, type in my name David, and I'll
所以现在，如果我在这里，重新加载，输入我的名字 David，然后我会……
just check one of them, for instance, because I've not hacked the form
比如，就检查其中一个，因为我没有黑掉表单
and added something bogus like football.
并在里面添加了一些虚假的东西，比如足球。
Maybe someone was alluding to this.
也许有人在暗示这个。
I see now an error.
我现在看到了一个错误。
So let's do this together.
所以我们一起做吧。
Not sure what I did wrong.
我不确定我做错了什么。
I'm going to open up my terminal and go to here.
我要打开我的终端，并转到此处。
And, oh, interesting, my spacing's a little weird here.
而且，哦，有趣的是，我的间距在这里有点奇怪。
But attribute error.
但是属性错误。
Immutable dictionary has no attribute getall.
不可变字典没有属性 getall。
So this is me lying to you.
所以这是我在骗你。
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
But [INAUDIBLE], are you here?
但是 [听不清]，你在吗？
Did Flask change since I last did this?
自从我上次做这件事以来，Flask 有变化吗？
No.
没有。
OK, so Flask post form getall.
好的，所以 Flask post 表单 getall。
All right, here we go.
好的，我们开始吧。
About 2012, this is probably out of date.
大约 2012 年，这可能已经过时了。
But ah.
但是啊。
You know, that's not a bad idea, OK.
你知道，这不是一个坏主意，好的。
All right, OK, in Flask, how do I get all of the values
好的，好的，在 Flask 中，如何获取所有值
from an HTML input of type checkbox from request.form?
来自 request.form 中类型为复选框的 HTML 输入？
Well, this is horrifying.
好吧，这太可怕了。
getlist!
getlist！
Damn it, OK.
该死，好吧。
What a good duck.
真是个好鸭子。
All right, so-- all right, so we'll rewind in time.
好的，所以 - 好的，所以我们会倒回时间。
So thank you.
所以谢谢。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
So that's a good lesson.
所以这是一个很好的教训。
Just do as I do.
就像我做的那样。
All right, so getlist will get you a list of all of those values.
好的，所以 getlist 将会获得所有这些值的列表。
So now if I go ahead and register as David,
所以现在，如果我继续以 David 的身份注册，
click just soccer without injecting something
只点击足球，而不用注入一些东西
like American football and Register, now I'm,
像美式足球，然后点击注册，现在我，
in fact, registered but not really, not really in the sense
事实上，已经注册了，但实际上没有，在某种意义上说没有
that we haven't actually done anything with the data.
我们实际上没有对数据做任何事情。
So this is to say, ultimately, that there's a lot of these building blocks,
所以，最终的意思是，有很多这样的构建模块，
not only in HTML, which is mostly a throwback to last week but also now,
不仅在 HTML 中，它主要是一个对上周的回顾，而且现在，
in Flask, where you can process all of those building blocks
在 Flask 中，你可以处理所有这些构建模块
and take control over what up, until now,
并控制到目前为止，
is usually the domain of Google or the websites that you actually use.
通常是谷歌或你实际使用的网站的领域。
Now you actually have more of the building blocks via which
现在，你实际上拥有了更多用来实现这些事物的构建模块。
to implement these things yourself.
你自己实现这些东西。
So let's go ahead and add some final features to froshims
所以，让我们继续为 froshims 添加一些最终功能
here where we're actually doing something with the results.
在这里，我们实际上用结果做了一些事情。
And, for this, I'm going to open up a version in advance.
并且，为此，我将提前打开一个版本。
So I'm going to go over to VS Code here.
所以我要去到 VS Code 这里。
And let me go ahead and close these tabs but go into my second terminal window.
然后让我继续关闭这些标签，但进入我的第二个终端窗口。
And I'm going to go into today's src9 directory.
我要进入今天的 src9 目录。
And I'm going to go into version 4 of froshims, which has
我将进入 froshims 的版本 4，它包含
everything we just did plus a bit more.
我们刚刚做的一切，再加上一些。
In particular, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
特别是，我要继续做这个。
I'm going to show you app.py, which, additionally,
我将向你展示 app.py，另外，
has some comments throughout.
在整个文件中有一些注释。
But, in app.py, what you'll notice is that, after all of my validation,
但是，在 app.py 中，你会注意到，在我完成所有验证之后，
I'm actually got a couple of new features here.
我实际上在这里添加了一些新功能。
It's a little weak in terms of UI to just tell the user failure.
仅仅告诉用户失败，在 UI 方面有点弱。
You are not registered.
你没有注册。
That's all my template previously did.
这就是我之前的所有模板所做的。
But what if I borrow an idea from my index template where all of this time,
但是，如果我从我的索引模板借鉴一个想法，在那里，我一直，
for hello and froshims, I've been passing in input.
对于 hello 和 froshims，我一直传递输入。
So what if I do this?
那如果我这样做呢？
Let me show you.
让我演示给你看。
In templates, failure.html-- or, rather, let's see, in templates, error.html.
在模板中，failure.html--或者，让我们看看，在模板中，error.html。
So notice this, I can make the beginnings
所以请注意这一点，我可以开始创建
of a common format for an error page.
错误页面的通用格式。
So, in error.html of this fourth example,
所以，在这个第四个例子中的 error.html 中，
I've just got some big, bold error message at the top.
我只是在顶部放了一些大而粗的错误消息。
But I have a paragraph tag inside of which
但我在里面有一个段落标签
is a placeholder for an error message.
是错误消息的占位符。
And then I've gone one step further just because and put a happy cat or grumpy
然后，我仅仅因为这样做，更进一步，放了一只快乐的猫或一只沮丧的
cat as an image to let you down easy that something has gone wrong.
猫作为图片，让你更容易地接受发生了错误的事实。
But this is like now every website where there's generally some customized error
但这就像现在每个网站，通常都会有一些定制的错误
message when something has gone wrong or when you have not
消息，当发生错误时，或者当你没有
cooperated with the rules of the form.
与表单的规则配合。
So what am I doing instead?
那我在做什么呢？
Instead of rendering failure.html very generically,
与渲染非常通用的 failure.html 不同，
I'm rendering this new template error.html.
我正在渲染这个新的模板 error.html。
And I'm passing in a custom message.
并且我传递了一个自定义消息。
Why?
为什么？
Because now, in my app.py, my logic, I can actually say,
因为现在，在我的 app.py 中，我的逻辑，我实际上可以这么说，
you're missing your name.
你缺少你的名字。
You're missing a sport.
你缺少一个运动项目。
Or I can tell the human what the error, which is much better user interface.
或者我可以告诉人类错误是什么，这在用户界面上要好得多。
Down here, though, on this new line, here's
不过，在这下面，在这条新的行上，这里就是
where I'm now beginning to actually register registrants.
我开始真正注册注册者的地方。
What's the easiest way to do this?
最简单的做法是什么？
Well, let me scroll to the top of this file.
好吧，让我滚动到这个文件的顶部。
And you'll see that, in addition, to a big list of sports,
你会看到，除了一个庞大的运动项目列表之外，
I also have an empty dictionary initially of registrants.
我最初还有一个空的注册者字典。
Why?
为什么？
Well, dictionaries are this nice Swiss army knife, key-value pair, key, value,
好吧，字典就像一把瑞士军刀，键值对，键，值，
key, value.
键，值。
Names could be keys.
名字可以是键。
And maybe sports could be values, at least
也许运动项目可以是值，至少
if I'm supporting just single sports.
如果我仅仅支持单一运动项目。
So I could have a fancier structure, but this
所以我可以有一个更复杂的结构，但这个
seems sufficient, two columns, key, value, for name, sport, name, sport,
似乎足够了，两列，键，值，用于名字，运动项目，名字，运动项目，
and so forth.
等等。
So how do I put a person's name into that global dictionary?
那么，如何将一个人的姓名放入该全局字典中呢？
Well, I'll use the syntax from week six, registrants bracket name
嗯，我将使用第六周的语法，registrants 括号名称
equals sport that associates that value with that key.
等于 sport，它将该值与该键关联起来。
And, now, what you'll see in that I've added a new route /registrants.
现在，你会看到我添加了一个新的路由 /registrants。
And this is where things get interesting.
而这正是事情变得有趣的地方。
If I look at this premade route as you will too,
如果我查看这个预制的路由，你也会这样做，
as you look at code that's been written for you in the weeks to come,
就像你查看未来几周为你编写的代码一样，
well, this sort of invites me to look at registrants.html.
嗯，这似乎在邀请我查看 registrants.html。
Why?
为什么？
Apparently, this registrants.html template
显然，这个 registrants.html 模板
is being passed this global dictionary.
正在传递这个全局字典。
How might I use that?
我该如何使用它？
Well, let me go into VS Code's terminal.
好吧，让我进入 VS Code 的终端。
Let me take a look at registrants.html.
让我看一下 registrants.html。
And, interesting, we haven't used this HTML much.
有趣的是，我们并没有太多地使用这个 HTML。
I used it super briefly last week.
上周我非常简短地使用过它。
This is an HTML table.
这是一个 HTML 表格。
It's not going to look super pretty because I'm not
它不会看起来非常漂亮，因为我没有
using bootstrap or CSS more generally.
使用 Bootstrap 或更一般的 CSS。
But notice that, in the table's head, there's
但是请注意，在表格的头部，有
name and sport from left to right in the two columns.
从左到右两列中分别为 name 和 sport。
And then, in the table body or tbody, notice
然后，在表格主体或 tbody 中，请注意
that I have a whole bunch of tr, tr, tr, one for every registrant in that Jinja
我有很多 tr，tr，tr，每个 tr 都对应该 Jinja 中的每个注册者
loop.
循环。
Each of the cells, the table datas have the person's name.
每个单元格，即表格数据都包含该人的姓名。
And then if you go inside of that dictionary and look up the name,
然后，如果你进入那个字典并查找该姓名，
you get the value thereof, so name, sport, name, sport.
你会得到它的值，所以姓名、运动、姓名、运动。
And the route, of course, again, is just this, render registrants.html
当然，路由仍然是这个，渲染 registrants.html
by passing in that dictionary.
通过传入那个字典。
So what is registrants.html?
那么 registrants.html 是什么呢？
It's just this.
就是这个。
So I think if we go and run this version of the application,
所以，我认为如果我们运行这个版本的应用程序，
we have some nice new features.
我们有一些很棒的新功能。
Let me go ahead and do Flask--
让我继续使用 Flask -
let me kill Flask in the other window just so it's not using the same port.
让我在另一个窗口中关闭 Flask，这样它就不会使用相同的端口。
Let me do flask run inside of froshims4.
让我在 froshims4 中执行 flask run。
So far, so good.
目前为止，一切顺利。
Let me go over to my other tab.
让我切换到另一个标签页。
Let me reload.
让我重新加载。
So I get the latest HTML.
这样我就能获得最新的 HTML。
I'm going to go ahead and type in something like David
我将继续输入像 David 这样的内容
but select no sport using radio buttons.
但使用单选按钮选择没有运动。
So, again, you can only pick one.
所以，再说一次，你只能选择一个。
And now not only am I seeing one grumpy cat there.
现在，我不仅看到了一只生气的小猫。
It's also telling me at the top that I'm missing the sport.
它还在顶部告诉我，我缺少运动。
Conversely, if I reload the page, don't give my name.
相反，如果我重新加载页面，不提供我的姓名。
But do give the sport and register.
但要提供运动并注册。
Now you see that I'm missing name and not sport.
现在你会看到，我缺少姓名，而不是运动。
So, again, the UI is not very pretty, but it has the building blocks
所以，再说一次，UI 并不漂亮，但它具有构建块。
of being much more appropriate.
更合适得多。
Let me now cooperate on both fronts.
现在让我在这两个方面都进行合作。
David wants to register for soccer, Register.
大卫想要报名参加足球，报名。
And now notice where I am.
现在注意我身在何处。
Apparently, I got redirected to the registrants route,
显然，我被重定向到了注册路线，
inside of which is this two column table.
其内是这个两列表格。
It's not very interesting yet.
现在还不太有趣。
So let me go back to the form.
所以让我回到表单。
And let me register Carter, for instance,
例如，让我注册卡特，
for, say, basketball, Register.
比如，参加篮球，报名。
And now there's two of us.
现在我们两个人了。
Let me actually go back to the form.
让我实际回到表单。
And let me register Yulia for ultimate Frisbee, Register.
让我注册尤利娅参加极限飞盘，报名。
Now there's three of us.
现在我们三个人了。
And, again, the CSS is ugly, but I do have an HTML table.
再说一次，CSS 很难看，但我确实有一个 HTML 表格。
And if I right-click and View page source,
如果我右键单击并查看页面源代码，
you'll see David, soccer; Carter, basketball; Yulia, ultimate Frisbee all
你会看到大卫，足球；卡特，篮球；尤利娅，极限飞盘，全部
as tr, tr, tr.
都是 tr，tr，tr。
So, again, if you now think about an app like Gmail in your inbox,
所以，再说一次，如果你现在考虑像收件箱里的 Gmail 这样的应用，
odds are if your inbox is indeed a big table,
如果你的收件箱确实是张大表格，
then it's probably tr, tr, tr, tr.
那么它很可能是 tr，tr，tr，tr。
And Google is rendering all of that HTML dynamically
而谷歌正在动态地渲染所有这些 HTML
based on all of the emails in some variable somewhere.
基于某个变量中的所有电子邮件。
Well, let me go back here and see, how did that redirect work?
好吧，让我回到这里看看，那个重定向是怎么工作的？
Let's watch this a little more slowly.
让我们再慢点看看。
Let me go up to the main form at slash.
让我去到斜杠下的主表单。
Let me type in David.
让我输入大卫。
Let me type in-- select soccer.
让我输入——选择足球。
And let me Zoom in to the URL.
让我放大 URL。
And notice that, when I submit this form,
注意，当我提交这个表单时，
even though the action is /register, I'm indeed ending up at /registrants.
尽管 action 是 /register，但我的确最终到达了 /registrants。
So how is that actually happening?
所以，这究竟是怎么发生的？
Well, let me go back and do it one more time.
好吧，让我返回并再做一次。
But, this time, let me open up Developer Tools.
但是，这次，让我打开开发者工具。
Let me go to the Network tab, which, recall, we played with last week.
让我去网络选项卡，记得吗，我们上周玩过它。
And let me go ahead and do this again.
让我继续这样做。
So David, Soccer, and I'm going to click Register.
所以大卫，足球，我要点击注册。
And now, notice, interesting, two routes were actually involved.
现在，注意，有趣的是，实际上涉及了两条路线。
The first one here is Register.
这里第一个是注册。
But notice if I go to headers, ah, 302 found.
但是注意，如果我去到标题，啊，302 找到了。
302 indicated some kind of redirect.
302 表示某种重定向。
What's the redirect going to?
重定向到哪里？
Well, if I look-- scroll down here at response headers,
好吧，如果我看看——向下滚动到响应标题，
there's a lot of stuff that's not interesting,
有很多东西不有趣，
but location was the one we cared about last week. /registrants, oh,
但 location 是我们上周关注的。/registrants，哦，
that's why the second request over here at left is actually /registrants.
这就是为什么左边这里的第二个请求实际上是 /registrants。
And it is 200 OK because it's all of these basic building
它是 200 OK，因为它包含所有这些基础构建
blocks from last week and now this.
模块，来自上周，现在还有这个。
Where did that redirect come from?
那个重定向来自哪里？
Well, now you have the ability to do this.
好吧，现在你有能力做到这一点。
Notice that, in my register route, the last thing I said we had done
请注意，在我的注册路由中，我最后说我们已经做的事情
was add the name and the value to this global dictionary.
是在将名称和值添加到这个全局字典中。
But the very last thing I did was redirect the user to the /registrants
但我做的最后一件事是将用户重定向到 /registrants
route.
路由。
What is redirect?
什么是重定向？
Well, at the very top of this file, notice
嗯，在这个文件的顶部，请注意
that I proactively imported not just flask, render_template, and request.
我主动导入的不仅仅是 flask、render_template 和 request。
I also imported redirect this time, which
这次我还导入了 redirect，它
is a function that comes with Flask that automatically issues the HTTP 302
是一个与 Flask 一起提供的函数，它会自动发出 HTTP 302
redirect for you without you having to know anything about those numbers
重定向，而无需你了解任何关于这些数字的知识
or otherwise.
或其他任何信息。
Let's do one final example before we break for snacks.
在我们去吃零食前，让我们做一个最后的例子。
In this final example, froshims5, let's actually do something with SQL.
在这个最后的例子中，froshims5，让我们实际使用一下 SQL。
SQL, after all, allows us to persist the data because this version here,
毕竟，SQL 允许我们持久化数据，因为这里的这个版本，
with this global dictionary, what's the downside of using this global variable
使用这个全局字典，使用这个全局变量的缺点是什么
to store all of our registrants?
来存储我们所有的注册者？
What's the downside?
缺点是什么？
Yeah.
对。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly, so, as soon as the server quits
大卫·马兰：没错，所以，一旦服务器关闭
or if something goes wrong like maybe the power goes out,
或者如果出现问题，比如电源断电，
or we have multiple servers or something like that,
或者我们有多个服务器，诸如此类，
we'll lose the contents of that dictionary.
我们会丢失该字典的内容。
And so that's not really good to store data
因此，这不是一个真正适合存储数据的做法
that you care about in the computer's memory alone or RAM.
你关心的数据，仅存储在计算机的内存或 RAM 中。
You want to store it on disk using something like fopen and fwrite
你应该将其存储在磁盘上，使用像 fopen 和 fwrite 这样的工具
and all of the file I/O stuff we talked about.
以及我们讨论过的所有文件 I/O 相关内容。
But, in week seven, recall, we introduced SQL.
但是，在第七周，你还记得，我们引入了 SQL。
So that writes things to disk in a .db file.
这样会将内容写入磁盘上的 .db 文件中。
So let's actually do that with one final example.
所以让我们用一个最后的例子实际操作一下。
Let me go ahead and close these tabs here in my terminal.
让我先在我的终端中关闭这些标签。
Let me go ahead and close the old version of froshims
让我先关闭 froshims 的旧版本
and go into froshims5 now.
然后现在进入 froshims5。
And, in this version, let me show you, in app.py, the following.
在这个版本中，让我在 app.py 中向你展示以下内容。
It's almost the same in terms of what we're importing from Flask.
从 Flask 中导入的内容几乎是一样的。
But I'm also going to import from CS50's library
但我还要从 CS50 的库中导入
a SQL function, which we used briefly when we wrote code
一个 SQL 函数，我们在编写代码时简短地用过它
in Python to talk to a SQLite database.
在 Python 中与 SQLite 数据库进行交互。
This is the one example of a CS50 training wheel
这是 CS50 辅助工具的一个例子
that we actually do keep on deliberately through the end of the term
我们确实有意保留到学期结束
because it's actually just really annoying
因为使用大多数第三方库与 SQL 交互，以一种用户友好的方式真的很烦人
to use most third-party libraries with SQL in as user friendly a way.
使用大多数第三方库与 SQL 交互，以一种用户友好的方式真的很烦人。
You're welcome to, but I do think that, even though you shouldn't
你可以使用它们，但我认为，尽管你不应该
be using get in getstring, getfloat anymore the SQL function's actually
再使用 getstring、getfloat 中的 get，SQL 函数实际上
pretty darn useful, I would say.
非常有用，我可以这么说。
So how do we use this?
我们如何使用它？
Everything in this file so far is pretty much the same except for that import,
到目前为止，这个文件中的一切都与之前基本相同，除了那个导入，
including these lines here.
包括这些行。
But notice that I am opening up a file called froshims.db.
但请注意，我正在打开一个名为 froshims.db 的文件。
And that's a database that's empty initially.
它是一个最初为空的数据库。
But it is in my account.
但它在我的账户中。
So, actually, let me do this.
所以，实际上，让我这样做。
Let me run sqlite3 on froshims.db.
让我在 froshims.db 上运行 sqlite3。
Let me increase the size of my terminal.
让我增加终端的大小。
Hit Enter.
按回车键。
What can I type to see the structure of this database?
我该输入什么才能查看该数据库的结构？
Sorry.
抱歉。
Wait, what?
等等，什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, yes, thank you.
大卫·J·马兰：哦，是的，谢谢。
.schema should show me.
.schema 应该会显示给我。
OK, it's actually a very simple database, a registrants table with one,
好的，它实际上是一个非常简单的数据库，一个包含一个的 registrants 表，
two, three columns, an ID for a unique identifier,
两个，三个列，一个 ID 用作唯一标识符，
a primary key, the name of the person, and the sport
主键，人的姓名，以及运动
for which they're registering.
他们正在注册的运动。
And, presumably, the ID will be automatically incremented for me.
而且，可以推测，ID 会自动为我递增。
So let me exit out of that.
所以，让我退出它。
Go back to app.py.
回到 app.py。
And this line 8 here is just giving me access to that SQLite database.
而这里的第 8 行只是给了我访问该 SQLite 数据库的权限。
And recall that the three slashes are appropriate.
请记住，三个斜杠是合适的。
It's not a typo relative to something like a URL.
与像 URL 这样的东西相比，这不是一个错别字。
Here is my three sports that I want to support.
这是我想要支持的三个运动。
Looks like my index route is pretty much the same.
看来我的索引路由几乎相同。
So nothing new there.
所以那里没什么新东西。
In fact, I'm using that same lesson as before
事实上，我正在使用与之前相同的课程
in passing in the whole sports list.
传递整个运动列表。
Notice that, OK, this is interesting.
注意，好的，这很有趣。
Deregister, this version is going to let users sort of bow out of a sport
取消注册，这个版本将允许用户退出某个运动，
as tends to happen over the course of a semester.
正如在一个学期中经常发生的。
But we'll come back to that.
但我们稍后会回到这个问题。
But let's look at register now.
但现在让我们看看 register。
register is almost the same even though I do have some comments here.
register 几乎相同，尽管我在此有一些注释。
We're making sure to validate the form.
我们正在确保验证表单。
But this is where it gets interesting.
但这就是它变得有趣的地方。
I'm now inserting rows into the database to register these registrants.
我现在正在将行插入到数据库中以注册这些注册者。
Notice that I'm using CS50's library to insert into the registrants table
请注意，我正在使用 CS50 的库插入 registrants 表
into these two columns name and sport, these two values.
到这两个列 name 和 sport 中，这两个值。
And I'm being very careful to use question marks to escape the user's
而且我非常小心地使用问号来转义用户的
input to avoid injection attacks.
输入以避免注入攻击。
And then I just redirect the user.
然后我就重定向用户。
But what's going to be interesting about this version is this too,
但这个版本有趣的地方还在于，
/registrants no longer just uses Jinja and iterates over a global variable.
/registrants 不再仅仅使用 Jinja 并在全局变量上迭代。
In this version, we're selecting all of the registrants
在这个版本中，我们正在选择所有注册者
and getting back a list of dictionaries.
并返回一个字典列表。
And then we're passing that list of dictionaries
然后我们将该字典列表
into the Jinja template called registrants.html.
传递到名为 registrants.html 的 Jinja 模板中。
So, just to make clear what's going on there,
所以，为了清楚地说明那里发生了什么，
let me open up templates and registrants.html.
让我打开模板和注册用户.html。
It's almost the same as before.
它几乎和以前一样。
Notice that I'm using the dot notation this time, which Jinja also supports.
请注意，这次我使用的是点符号，Jinja 也支持它。
And it's almost always the same as the square bracket notation.
它几乎总是与方括号符号相同。
So you'll see both in documentation online.
因此，您将在在线文档中看到这两种方式。
But notice that I have a third column in the registrants table
但是请注意，我在注册表中有一个第三列
that's a little interesting.
这有点意思。
And this will be the final lesson for froshims.
这将是新生入学的最后一课。
A button via which people can deregister themselves, like a bow out of froshims.
一个按钮，人们可以通过它自己取消注册，就像从新生入学中退出一样。
So let's do this.
让我们这样做。
Open the terminal.
打开终端。
Let's do flask run in version 5 of this here.
让我们在这个版本 5 中运行 Flask。
Let me go into my other tab, close the Developer Tools, go to the /route,
让我进入我的另一个标签，关闭开发者工具，转到 /route，
and I have a form quite like before.
我有一个和以前一样的表单。
But now, when I register, David for soccer and click
但是现在，当我注册大卫参加足球，然后点击
Register, notice that it's ugly UI.
注册，注意它是一个丑陋的 UI。
But there's a button next to David to deregister themselves.
但是在大卫旁边有一个按钮可以让他自己取消注册。
Let's go back to slash.
让我们回到斜杠。
Let me also register Carter, for instance, for basketball and so forth.
让我还注册卡特，例如，参加篮球等等。
There's now two buttons.
现在有两个按钮。
This, now, is what really ties together our discussion of SQL
现在，这真正将我们对 SQL 的讨论联系在一起
and primary keys with the world of the web.
以及主键与 web 世界。
Suppose that there were two Davids in the class, which there surely are,
假设班上有两个大卫，肯定会有，
two Carters, two Yulias, two of any names.
两个卡特，两个尤利亚，两个任何名字。
We clearly can't rely on first names alone
我们显然不能仅仅依靠名字
to uniquely identify humans in a room like this.
来唯一地识别像这样房间里的人。
So we probably should use opaque identifiers,
所以我们可能应该使用不透明标识符，
that is, those numbers, 1, 2, 3.
也就是说，那些数字，1、2、3。
Indeed, if I go into VS Code--
实际上，如果我进入 VS Code -
let me open another terminal and make it bigger.
让我打开另一个终端，并把它放大。
And, in my src9 froshims version 5, let me run sqlite3 of froshims.db.
在我的 src9 新生入学版本 5 中，让我运行 froshims.db 的 sqlite3。
And, sure enough, if I do SELECT * FROM registrants; I'll see the two of us
当然，如果我执行 SELECT * FROM registrants；我会看到我们两个人
thus far.
到目前为止。
And we've indeed been automatically-- been
而且我们确实被自动地 - 被
assigned an auto-incrementing primary key, 1, 2, respectively.
分配了一个自动递增的主键，分别是 1、2。
That's useful now in the web especially or user interfaces in general.
这在 web 上，尤其是在一般的用户界面中非常有用。
If I view this page as source, here in my browser,
如果我将此页面视为源代码，在我的浏览器中，
notice that both David and Carter have their own form in a third td
请注意，大卫和卡特都在第三个 td 中有自己的表单
element next to them.
元素旁边。
And that's what gives us this.
这就是我们得到它的原因。
But notice that form, even though it's an ugly UI,
但是请注意，这个表单，即使它是一个丑陋的 UI，
is a form that will post to a /deregister route a hidden input,
是一个将发布到 /deregister 路由的表单，带有一个隐藏的输入，
the name of which is ID to match the primary key column,
它的名字是 ID，用于匹配主键列，
the value of which is 1 for me and 2 for Carter.
它的值为 1 代表我，2 代表卡特。
So this is how you stitch together a browser and a server.
所以，这就是你将浏览器和服务器缝合在一起的方式。
When there's a database involved, you just
当涉及到数据库时，你只需
uniquely identify the things you care about by passing numbers around
通过传递数字来唯一地识别你关心的东西。
from browser to server and back.
从浏览器到服务器再返回。
You might visually show David and Soccer and Carter and Basketball.
你可能在视觉上展示大卫和足球以及卡特和篮球。
But the server only needs the unique identifier.
但服务器只需要唯一的标识符。
And that's why we dwelled so much, in week seven,
这就是为什么我们在第七周花了那么多时间，
on these primary keys and, in turn, foreign keys.
讲解这些主键以及相关的外键。
So, when I go back to this form here and click on deregister,
所以，当我回到这个表单并点击取消注册时，
this is going to submit ID equals 1 to the /deregister route which should--
这将提交ID等于1到/deregister路由，它应该--
and this was the only route we didn't look at earlier.
这是我们之前没有看过的唯一一条路线。
Let me open up app.py again.
让我再次打开app.py。
You'll see that this happens in deregister.
你会看到这发生在deregister中。
In the deregister route, which only supports POST,
在deregister路由中，它只支持POST，
I'm going to get the ID from the form.
我将从表单中获取ID。
If there is, in fact, an ID and it wasn't missing for some reason,
如果实际上存在一个ID，并且它没有因为某种原因丢失，
I'm going to execute delete from registrants
我将执行从registrants删除
where ID equals question mark as a placeholder, passing in that number.
其中ID等于问号作为占位符，传入该数字。
And then I'm just going to redirect the user back to registrants
然后，我将把用户重定向回registrants
so they can see who is still actually registered.
以便他们可以看到谁实际上仍然注册了。
So if I go back to my browser here and I deregister myself,
所以，如果我回到我的浏览器，并取消注册我自己，
we should see that now that's gone.
我们应该看到它现在不见了。
And if I deregister Carter, that's now gone.
如果我取消注册卡特，它现在也消失了。
And if I indeed go back to VS Code, open up my terminal window, make it bigger,
如果我确实回到VS Code，打开我的终端窗口，并将其放大，
run SELECT * FROM registrants, now no one is registered for the sport.
运行SELECT * FROM registrants，现在没有人注册了这项运动。
And so we've effectively stitched all of these things together.
所以我们有效地将所有这些东西缝合在一起。
So that's all how we might implement froshims.
所以这就是我们如何实现froshims。
Just so you've heard the vocabulary, what we've implemented
为了让你听到这些词汇，我们所实现的是
is a paradigm known MVC, Model View Controller,
一个被称为MVC的范式，即模型-视图-控制器，
where the view is everything the human sees, the templates, the HTML, the CSS,
其中视图是人类所看到的一切，模板，HTML，CSS，
the JavaScript.
以及JavaScript。
The controller is everything that's in app.py, the logic
控制器是app.py中的一切，逻辑
that we've actually been implementing.
是我们一直在实现的。
But, as soon as you introduce a database especially or even
但是，一旦你引入一个数据库，尤其是甚至
a global dictionary, then you have the M in MVC, a model, which
一个全局字典，那么你就会在MVC中得到M，即模型，它
is where all of your data is stored.
是所有数据存储的地方。
Now, you don't have to think about it this way.
现在，你不必这样想。
But humans, over time, realized that, wow, most of our web apps
但随着时间的推移，人类意识到，哇，我们的大多数网络应用程序
follow this similar paradigm.
都遵循这种类似的范式。
So they started thinking about different components of the application
所以他们开始考虑应用程序的不同组件
as having these different identifiers.
具有这些不同的标识符。
So there's still a lot more.
所以还有很多。
We have not yet considered how, when you log into a website,
我们还没有考虑当你在网站上登录时，
the website remembers that you've logged in.
网站如何记住你已经登录了。
We've not remembered how you can keep track of what's
我们还没有记住如何跟踪某人的购物车里有什么。
inside of someone's shopping cart.
东西。
This was a lot of effort just for two-second joke.
这只是为了一个两秒钟的笑话，就付出了很多努力。
But let's go-- with that said, for roll-ups and snacks
但是，话虽如此，为了补充和零食，
as served, let's take a 10-minute break.
我们休息十分钟。
We'll see you in 10 for that and more as we wrap up.
我们将在 10 分钟后回来，届时我们将继续讨论更多内容。
All right, we are back, and let's consider now
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们考虑一下
how web applications typically work when you actually
当您实际上使用网络应用程序时，它们通常是如何工作的
have to log into them, which is most every web application nowadays.
需要登录时，如今几乎所有网络应用程序都是这样工作的。
Somehow or other, even though you only log in once,
尽管您只登录一次，
at least at the start of the day or the start of the browser tab
至少在一天开始或浏览器标签页打开时，
that you open, somehow or other, websites
您打开的网站，总能以某种方式
are still able to remember that you've logged in already.
记住您已经登录了。
And that's how you see your Gmail inbox or your social media feed or the like.
这就是为什么您能看到您的 Gmail 收件箱或社交媒体信息流等等。
So here, for instance, is a representative login form.
所以这里，例如，是一个典型的登录表单。
This one here for Gmail or for all of Google services.
这个用于 Gmail 或所有 Google 服务。
And let's consider what actually happens underneath the hood with respect
现在让我们考虑一下当您使用您的用户名和密码登录到这样的网站时，这些虚拟信封在引擎盖下实际发生了什么。
to those virtual envelopes when you do log in with your username and password
涉及到那些虚拟信封，当您使用您的用户名和密码登录到这样的网站时
to a site like this.
到这样的网站。
Well, typically, inside of the virtual envelope
通常情况下，在您的浏览器发送到 Google 服务器的虚拟信封内，也就是 accounts.google.com，
that your browser sends to Google servers, that is, accounts.google.com,
您的浏览器发送到 Google 服务器的虚拟信封内，也就是 accounts.google.com，
is a request maybe for that form.
可能是一个对该表单的请求。
So GET slash HTTP version 2 or whatever version your browser's actually working
所以 GET 斜杠 HTTP 版本 2 或者您的浏览器实际工作中的任何版本
and some other headers dot, dot, dot.
以及其他一些标头等等。
But, for the most part, that's what we've seen thus far.
但到目前为止，这基本上是我们所见过的。
When you then actually log in--
当您真正登录时——
or, rather, when you visit that page, hopefully, you
或者说，当您访问那个页面时，希望您
get back a response from the server saying that everything is OK.
从服务器获得一个回复，说明一切正常。
That is 200, OK.
也就是 200，表示一切正常。
And the response that comes back is text/html, so same as last week.
返回的响应是 text/html，与上周一样。
This is just what's inside of those virtual envelopes back and forth.
这只是这些虚拟信封来回传递的内容。
But, when you log in to a server, it turns out, typically,
但是，当您登录到服务器时，事实证明，通常情况下，
what's happening is that the server is, unbeknownst to you,
服务器正在做的事情是，在您不知情的情况下，
kind of stamping your hand once it's verified your username
在验证了您的用户名之后，服务器会给您盖章
and your password to remember that you have logged in.
以及密码，以记住您已经登录。
In particular, what Google server is going
特别是，Google 服务器在您访问了该表单并通过 POST 提交了该表单后，
to send back after you visited that form and submitted that form as via POST,
Google 服务器将在您访问了该表单并通过 POST 提交了该表单后，
is you're going to get back a response that looks like this.
您将获得一个看起来像这样的响应。
It's going to, hopefully, say 200, OK.
希望它会说 200，表示一切正常。
It's probably going to be a web page written in text/html.
它可能是一个用 text/html 编写的网页。
But an additional HTTP header that we didn't focus on last week, which
但还有一个上周我们没有关注的 HTTP 标头，它
is this one, the Set-Cookie header.
就是这个，Set-Cookie 标头。
And the Set-Cookie header specifies yet another one
Set-Cookie 标头指定了另一个
of these key-value pairs, the name of which
这些键值对，它的名称
can actually be anything depending on the server, the value of which
可以是任何东西，取决于服务器，它的值
is some unique identifier.
是一个唯一的标识符。
So you've all probably heard about cookies in the context of the web.
所以你们可能都听说过网络中的 cookie。
You've probably heard that they're not good for your privacy.
你们可能听说过它们对隐私不好。
And that's generally true.
这通常是正确的。
But cookies need to exist if you want web pages to be
但是，如果您希望网页能够
or websites to be stateful, that is, remember a little something about you.
或者网站要保持状态，也就是说，记住你的一些信息。
And so session is the name of the--
所以会话是这个的名称——
session is a word that describes the maintenance
会话是一个描述维护的词
of state between a client and a server.
客户端和服务器之间状态。
That is to say, if the server's remembering something about you,
也就是说，如果服务器记得你的一些信息，
you have a session with that server, the equivalent, really, of a shopping cart.
你与该服务器之间就存在一个会话，这实际上相当于一个购物车。
So, in fact, if you go to amazon.com or any website via which you can not only
实际上，如果你去 Amazon.com 或者任何你可以不仅
log in but add items to a shopping cart or equivalent, that is a session.
登录，还能将商品添加到购物车或类似东西的网站，那就是一个会话。
Shopping cart is the real-world equivalent thereof.
购物车是现实世界中的等价物。
So this Set-Cookie header is essentially a directive
所以这个 Set-Cookie 头部本质上是一个指令
from the server to your browser to store this value in the browser's
来自服务器到你的浏览器，将这个值存储到浏览器的
memory somewhere, either for the life of the browser tab or maybe even longer,
内存中某个地方，要么是该浏览器标签的整个生命周期，要么可能更长，
for an hour, a day, a year, depending on the expiration time that's actually
一个小时、一天、一年，具体取决于实际设置的过期时间。
set.
设置。
The idea, though, is that because your browser is designed to understand HTTP
不过，思路是，因为你的浏览器被设计成理解 HTTP
also, just like the server, you're on the honor system, your browser,
同样，就像服务器一样，你遵循的是诚信系统，你的浏览器，
such that the next time you visit Google's same server,
所以下次你访问 Google 的同一个服务器时，
you should remind the server what cookie was set.
你应该提醒服务器设置了什么 cookie。
That is to say, the browser should send back to the server,
也就是说，浏览器应该发送回服务器，
not set cookie because it's already been set, but a cookie header that
不是设置 cookie，因为它已经设置过了，而是一个包含相同值的 cookie 头部。
contains exactly that same value.
包含完全相同的那个值。
So the metaphor here is kind of like when
所以这里的一个比喻是，就像当你
you go into maybe a bar or a club or an amusement park,
走进一个酒吧、夜店或游乐园，
and you showed your ticket, or you paid your fees, ideally,
你出示了你的票，或者你支付了费用，理想情况下，
they'd do something like stamp your hand such that the next time you
他们会做一些类似在你的手上盖章之类的事情，这样下次你
go through the line, you don't have to take out your ticket again or your ID
排队的时候，你就不必再拿出你的票或你的身份证
and prove that you have paid or that you belong there.
来证明你已经支付了费用，或者证明你属于这里。
You just show your hand stamp.
你只要出示你的手上的印章就可以了。
And the idea is that the bouncer can trust
这个思路是，门卫可以信任
that if you're presenting this hand stamp
如果你出示这个手上的印章，
and maybe it's the right color and the right picture for that particular day,
而且它可能是当天正确的颜色和图案，
they should just let you in without prompting you again
他们就应该让你进去，不用再问你
for your ticket or your money or, in this case, your username and password.
你的票、你的钱，或者在本例中，你的用户名和密码。
So cookies are a very good thing functionally.
所以从功能上来说，cookie 是一件非常好的东西。
They are a feature of HTTP.
它们是 HTTP 的一个功能。
And they are how servers implement state between themselves and you
它们是服务器在自身和你之间实现状态的方式
because, after all, when you click on a link on a web page
因为，毕竟，当你点击网页上的链接时，
or another link on a web page, eventually,
或者网页上的另一个链接，最终，
the browser icon stops spinning.
浏览器图标停止旋转。
And it's no longer connected to you typically.
而且它通常不再连接到你。
But, so long as the next link you click results in a virtual envelope going
但是，只要你点击的下一个链接导致一个虚拟信封从
from client to server containing this header,
客户端发送到服务器，并包含这个头部，
it's the equivalent of just reminding the server who you are.
它就相当于提醒服务器你是谁。
This value is generally a big number, a big alphanumeric number,
这个值通常是一个大数字，一个大的字母数字组合，
so it's some unique identifier.
所以它是一个独特的标识符。
Generally speaking, cookies do not need to contain your actual username,
一般来说，cookie 不需要包含你的实际用户名，
your actual password.
你的实际密码。
That's generally frowned upon.
这通常是不被接受的。
The useful information like your username,
有用的信息，比如你的用户名，
your password, what's in your shopping cart
你的密码，你的购物车里有什么
can be stored entirely server side.
都可以完全存储在服务器端。
This cookie is just a reminder to the server who you are.
这个 cookie 只是提醒服务器你是谁。
The problem with cookies, though, nowadays
然而，如今 cookie 的问题是
is that they're used so often for advertising,
它们被用来做广告，
for tracking, and the like.
用来跟踪等等。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Well, this is a natural result of that basic primitive.
嗯，这是那个基本原语的自然结果。
If your browser unbeknownst to you is in the habit of just presenting
如果你的浏览器在不知不觉中习惯了每次访问网站就展示
this hand stamp every time it visits a website,
这个手印，
you're proactively reminding websites who
你就主动地提醒网站你是谁，
you are again and again, at least who you
一次又一次地提醒他们，至少你是谁，
are in the sense of if you logged in.
从你是否登录的角度来说。
Now they'll always know who you are.
现在他们总是知道你是谁。
Even if you're in incognito mode, for instance, private mode browsing,
即使你在隐身模式下，例如，私密模式浏览，
your hand is still getting stamped.
你的手仍然会被盖章。
Your incognito window is still sending that same unique identifier
你的隐身窗口仍然会发送同一个独特的标识符
again and again.
一次又一次。
And, so long as you don't log in, they might not
只要你不登录，他们可能不会
know that your Carter or David, but they do
知道你是 Carter 还是 David，但他们确实
know you're the same user or the same person using that browser or, rather,
知道你是同一个用户，或者同一个使用那个浏览器的人，或者说，
the same browser visiting the website because that hand stamp is
同一个访问网站的浏览器，因为那个手印
going to be sent again and again.
会一遍又一遍地被发送。
But, when you clear your cookies or when you close your incognito window,
但是，当你清除你的 cookie 或关闭你的隐身窗口时，
that's like washing your hand and starting fresh,
就像洗手然后重新开始一样，
getting a new unique identifier.
获得一个新的唯一标识符。
So you appear to be someone different even though, as an aside,
所以你看起来像是一个不同的人，即使作为旁白，
even if you're in the habit of using incognito mode
即使你习惯使用隐身模式
and clearing your browser tabs and all of that,
并清除你的浏览器标签页等等，
with very, very high probability, servers can still track you nowadays
很有可能，服务器现在仍然可以追踪到你
based on your IP address, of course, which
根据你的 IP 地址，当然，它
is on the outside of those envelopes, based on the particular browser
在那些信封的外面，根据你安装的特定浏览器
extensions that you have installed, based on the various fonts
扩展程序，根据你安装的各种字体
that you have installed.
你安装的字体。
There's some crazy-high-percentage likelihood
有一个非常高的可能性
that a browser can uniquely identify you even if you're scrubbing
浏览器可以唯一识别你，即使你在清理
your tracks in this way, so just FYI.
你的踪迹，所以仅供参考。
But, for today's purposes, it all derives from this thing called cookies.
但，就今天而言，这一切都源于这个叫做 cookie 的东西。
And this is how they are then set.
这就是它们被设置的方式。
So let's actually use this a little more productively
所以让我们实际更有效地利用它
and leverage it in the context of Flask by using another global variable that
并将其应用于 Flask 的环境中，使用另一个全局变量，该变量
comes with Flask that you can import that gives you access
与 Flask 一起提供，你可以导入它，它可以让你访问
to the equivalent of a shopping cart.
类似于购物车的功能。
That is to say, Flask deals with all of this stuff
也就是说，Flask 处理了所有这些东西
like setting cookies and checking for cookies and all of the plumbing.
比如设置 cookie、检查 cookie 以及所有基础功能。
Someone else have solved that for you.
其他人已经为你解决了这些问题。
And Flask just handles the contents of the shopping cart
Flask 只处理购物车的内容
or the username to you in the context of a variable.
或以变量的形式将用户名提供给你。
So let me go over to VS Code here.
所以让我切换到 VS Code。
And, during the break, I created a new folder called login.
在休息期间，我创建了一个名为 login 的新文件夹。
If I type ls, I've got the beginnings of an app.py and a templates folder.
如果我输入 ls，我会有一个 app.py 和一个 templates 文件夹。
And, in the templates folder, I've got the beginnings
在 templates 文件夹里，我还有
of a layout.html and an index.html just so I
layout.html 和 index.html 文件，这样我
don't have to type quite as many characters to get started.
就不需要输入太多字符来开始。
What I'm going to do with this app, though,
我打算用这个应用程序来做的是
is let's implement a very simple app that allows the user to log in
实现一个非常简单的应用程序，允许用户登录
and demonstrates how a server can remember that you are, in fact,
并演示服务器如何记住你是否确实
logged in.
登录。
So let me open up app.py.
所以让我打开 app.py。
And, at the very top of this file, which is otherwise--
在这个文件的开头，它原本是
let me shorten this even further so it looks as simple as possible.
让我进一步简化它，使其看起来尽可能简单。
In this app.py, let me go ahead and simply add one more import
在这个 app.py 文件中，让我继续添加一个导入
up here called session.
它名为 session。
And that's going to give me the equivalent of a shopping
这将给我一个相当于购物车的工具。
cart at my disposal.
我可以随意使用。
But I do need to configure it.
但我需要配置它。
And there's some different ways to configure it.
有一些不同的配置方法。
But the conventional way or a recommended way
但是传统的或推荐的方法
here is as follows, to run app.config.
是如下运行 app.config。
And then set this configuration variable, which is flask specific,
然后设置这个 Flask 特定的配置变量
called SESSION_PERMANENT equals false so that this will indeed
名为 SESSION_PERMANENT 等于 false，这样它将成为
be treated as a session cookie.
一个会话 cookie。
So, as soon as you quit your browser or close your tabs, typically,
因此，当您退出浏览器或关闭选项卡时，通常
what's in the session will be deleted.
会话中的内容将会被删除。
This does tend to vary by browser.
这确实会因浏览器而异。
Sometimes things might be kept around longer than you expect.
有时某些东西可能会比你预期的保留更长时间。
But, by default, this is going to ensure that, essentially, the cookie is
但是，默认情况下，这将确保 cookie 实际上
deleted when you quit the browser.
在您退出浏览器时被删除。
I'm also going to do this app.config SESSION_TYPE is going
我也将进行 app.config SESSION_TYPE 设置
to equal, quote, unquote, "filesystem".
等于“filesystem”。
This just ensures that the contents of your shopping cart or equivalent
这只是确保您的购物车内容或类似内容
are stored in the servers--
存储在服务器的
in the server's files, not in the cookie itself for privacy's sake.
文件中，而不是在 cookie 本身中，出于隐私考虑。
And, lastly, I'm going to activate sections on this app
最后，我将在这个应用程序上激活部分内容
by just running this line of code.
通过运行这一行代码。
These, for today's purposes, are sort of copy-paste-able lines
这些对于今天的目的来说，是可复制粘贴的代码行
that just get sessions working in a recommended manner for you.
可以使会话以推荐的方式为您工作。
Hereafter, now, we can just use them as we expect, as we would hope.
从现在开始，我们可以像预期的那样使用它们，就像我们希望的那样。
So let me do this.
所以让我来做这件事。
Let me now open up another file in templates called, say, index.html.
现在让我在 templates 文件夹中打开另一个文件，例如 index.html。
And, in index.html, I'm going to make a very simple web page that's
在 index.html 中，我将创建一个非常简单的网页，它
just going to check if the user is logged in or not
只是检查用户是否已登录
and explain as much if they are.
如果已登录，就说明一下。
So, in the body block of index.html, which I prepared in advance,
因此，在 index.html 的 body 部分，我已经提前准备好了
I'm going to do this.
我要做这个。
I'm going to use Jinja, not to have a loop or a placeholder,
我将使用 Jinja，不是为了循环或占位符，
but an actual conditional like this.
而是一个真正的条件语句，像这样。
If the user is logged in with a name, then go ahead and output inside of--
如果用户使用用户名登录，则继续在内部输出 -
and let me do this else here.
并让我在这里做 else 部分。
And, actually, let me proactively do this just
而且，实际上，让我主动地这样做，
so you can see the structure, endif.
这样你就能看到 endif 的结构了。
So I've got the beginnings of an if else block in Jinja.
所以我在 Jinja 中创建了一个 if else 块的开头部分。
If there's a name variable in this template, say this,
如果此模板中存在 name 变量，就说
You are logged in as name period.
你已以 name 登录。
And then let's give the human a link--
然后，让我们给用户一个链接 -
actually, nope, let's do this.
实际上，不，让我们这样做。
Else, if you are not logged in, you are not logged in.
否则，如果你没有登录，你就没有登录。
So super simple English text that's just going to tell us,
所以这只是一个非常简单的英文文本，它只是告诉我们，
is the user logged in with a name?
用户是否已使用用户名登录？
Or are they not?
还是没有？
And I'm not even going to bother with a password.
我甚至不会考虑密码。
We're going to keep it simple with just a name to demonstrate.
为了演示，我们将只使用用户名来简化操作。
All right, so now what am I going to do in my controller,
好了，现在我要在我的控制器中做什么，
that is to say, app.py?
也就是说，在 app.py 中？
Let's go ahead and do this.
让我们继续执行这个操作。
Let's go ahead and create an app.py called login.
让我们创建一个名为 login 的 app.py 文件。
So I have a route that just handles logins for the user.
所以，我有一个路由，它只处理用户的登录。
And I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要继续做这个。
Initially, I'm going to define a function called login.
最初，我将定义一个名为 login 的函数。
And I'm going to have it return render template of login.html.
我将让它返回 login.html 的渲染模板。
So this is going to be a login form by default.
所以这将成为默认的登录表单。
Well, let's create that.
好吧，让我们创建它。
Let me go into my templates directory.
让我进入我的模板目录。
I'm going to go ahead and create a new file called login.html.
我要创建一个名为 login.html 的新文件。
And, in login.html, I'm going to borrow some of this
在 login.html 中，我将借用一些来自
HTML-- this template from before.
HTML 的 - 之前这个模板。
In login.html, I'm going to just have a very simple form for logging
在 login.html 中，我将只创建一个非常简单的登录表单，
in, again, no password per se, just a user's name.
再次强调，没有密码，只有用户名。
So let's keep it simple as follows.
所以让我们像下面这样简化它。
form action equals, quote, unquote, /login.
form action 等于，引号，引号，/login。
The method for privacy's sake will be post.
为了隐私，方法将是 post。
Inside of this form, let's just ask the user for an input with autocomplete
在这个表单中，让我们只要求用户输入一个带自动完成功能的输入框，
off by default and autofocus on.
默认情况下关闭，自动聚焦开启。
And the name of this field will be name for the human name.
这个字段的名称将是 name，用于表示用户名。
The placeholder text, as before, will be, quote, unquote, "Name," capital N.
与之前一样，占位符文本将是，引号，引号，“Name”，大写 N。
And the type of this field will be the default, which is just text.
这个字段的类型将是默认值，也就是文本。
And then, lastly, let's have a button, the type of which
最后，让我们添加一个按钮，它的类型
is submit because its purpose in life is to submit this form.
是 submit，因为它的作用是提交这个表单。
And, inside of that button, we'll see the words login.
并且，在这个按钮里面，我们会看到“登录”这两个字。
So very similar to greet, very similar to register.
所以它非常类似于greet，也非常类似于register。
But we're now just implementing a login form.
但我们现在只是在实现一个登录表单。
OK, now let's go back to app.py.
好了，现在让我们回到app.py。
The only thing login does right now is display this form.
login目前唯一做的就是显示这个表单。
But let's actually handle the user's logging in.
但让我们真正处理用户的登录。
So I'm going to do this.
所以我将要这样做。
If the request.method equals, quote, unquote, "POST"
如果request.method等于“POST”，
and, therefore, the form was logically submitted, let's do this.
这意味着表单在逻辑上被提交了，让我们做这个。
Let's use this session variable.
让我们使用这个session变量。
So this session variable that I imported globally here
所以我在全局范围内导入的这个session变量
is essentially a dictionary.
本质上是一个字典。
It's an empty dictionary with two columns
它是一个空的字典，有两列
ready to receive keys and values.
准备接收键值对。
So if I want to put in someone's name from this login form,
所以如果我想从这个登录表单中输入一个人的姓名，
I can just tuck it in the session.
我就可以把它塞到session里。
And it's similar in spirit to this thing that we did last time for froshims,
它在精神上类似于我们上次为froshims所做的事情，
giving myself a global dictionary.
给自己一个全局字典。
But the problem with that was that, as soon as the server quits,
但问题是，一旦服务器停止，
all of the memory contents are lost.
所有内存内容都会丢失。
And it was also global.
它也是全局的。
So no matter whether it was me or Carter or Yulia visiting the same URL,
所以无论是我还是Carter还是Yulia访问同一个URL，
there was no distinction among users.
用户之间没有区别。
All of us were treated as the same user.
我们都被当作同一个用户对待。
But what's brilliant about this session variable is that flask, because it
但这个session变量的妙处在于，flask因为它
knows about HTTP and Set-Cookie and cookie,
知道HTTP和Set-Cookie以及cookie，
it creates the illusion that whether you, the programmer,
它会产生一种错觉，无论是你，程序员，
have one user or a million users, the contents of session
有一个用户还是一百万个用户，session的内容
are guaranteed to always be unique for me or for Carter or Yulia
都保证对我，Carter或者Yulia来说都是独一无二的
or whatever human is visiting your code at that moment in time.
或者任何正在访问你的代码的人，在那个特定时间点。
You have the illusion that everyone has their own session object or dictionary
你会有这样的错觉，每个人都有自己的session对象或字典
or, really, everyone has their own shopping cart
或者，更确切地说，每个人都有自己的购物车
just like you would expect on an amazon.com.
就像你在亚马逊网站上所期望的那样。
So let's use this session object like a dictionary.
所以让我们像使用字典一样使用这个session对象。
Let's do this, let's remember the user's name from the form by going in session,
让我们这样做，让我们通过访问session来记住表单中的用户名，
quote, unquote, "name" and set the value of that key equal to request.form.get
“name”，并将该键的值设置为request.form.get
name.
name。
So whatever's in the form, let's plop it into this global session dictionary
所以表单中有什么，我们就把它放到这个全局的session字典中
to remember the user.
以记住用户。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
Just for user interfaces' sake, let's do this,
为了用户界面的缘故，让我们这样做，
let's return a redirect, a 302 or whatever, to slash.
让我们返回一个重定向，一个302或其他，到斜杠。
Let's just redirect the user back to the home page to see if they are, in fact,
让我们将用户重定向回主页，看看他们是否真的
logged in at that point.
在那个时候登录了。
So I think, at this point, that's the entirety of my login route.
所以我想，在这一点上，这就是我的登录路由的全部内容。
If the user has submitted their name via POST, store their name in the session,
如果用户通过POST提交了他们的姓名，将他们的姓名存储在session中，
and then redirect the user back to the home page.
然后将用户重定向回主页。
The home page meanwhile looks again like this.
与此同时，首页看起来是这样的。
If there is a name in this template, we're going to see that person's name.
如果模板中有一个名字，我们将会看到这个人的名字。
Else, we're going to see that they're not logged in.
否则，我们会看到他们没有登录。
So how do we get at that name?
那么我们如何获取这个名字呢？
Back to app.py.
回到 app.py 文件。
Let's just assemble these building blocks.
我们只需要将这些构建块组合在一起。
In my index route, I'm going to do this.
在我的索引路由中，我会这样做。
name equals session.get, quote, unquote, name.
name 等于 session.get、引号、引号、name。
So you can treat session similar to request.args, similar to request.form.
因此你可以像对待 request.args 和 request.form 一样对待 session。
But it's a more permanent thing.
但它更持久。
At least so long as it's the same human logged in,
至少只要是同一个用户登录，
I'm going to get my name or Carter's name or Yulia's name
我会得到我的名字，或者 Carter 的名字，或者 Yulia 的名字，
depending on whose browser is visiting my URL at this moment in time.
取决于此时此刻哪个浏览器的访问我的 URL。
All right, so let's cross my fingers because I
好吧，让我们祈祷一下，因为我
wrote a lot of this on the fly.
很多代码都是即兴写的。
Let me open my terminal window in my login folder and do flask run.
让我在登录文件夹中打开终端窗口并执行 flask run。
And, OK, I screwed up already.
好吧，我已经搞砸了。
Session is not defined.
Session 未定义。
Did I mean session in lowercase?
我的意思是小写的 session 吗？
No, not in this case.
不，在这种情况下不是。
It turns out what I should have done is one more line from flask_session import
事实证明，我应该再添加一行代码：从 flask_session 导入
Session.
Session。
Why?
为什么？
This is another flask library.
这是另一个 Flask 库。
It's technically a third-party library that other smart people
从技术上来说，它是一个第三方库，由其他聪明人
wrote for flask users to use.
为 Flask 用户编写。
So I copied and pasted that line from the documentation.
所以我从文档中复制粘贴了这一行。
So clearly forgot about it.
所以显然忘记了它。
Let me get rid of this registrants dictionary which
让我删除这个 registrants 字典，它
has nothing to do with this example.
与这个例子无关。
Let me now open my terminal again and do flask run.
现在让我再次打开终端并执行 flask run。
OK, now we seem to be in good shape.
好的，现在我们似乎没问题了。
No error message is apparent.
没有明显的错误消息。
Let me go back to my URL and reload.
让我回到我的 URL 并重新加载。
And notice I am not logged in.
请注意，我没有登录。
Now, this is not very user friendly because the only way I know I can log
现在，这很不友好，因为我知道我唯一可以登录的方式
in is by going to /login.
是去 /login 页面。
So let's actually improve the UI.
所以让我们实际改进一下 UI。
In index.html, if you are not logged in, let's do this.
在 index.html 文件中，如果你没有登录，让我们这样做。
a href equals /login.
a 标签的 href 属性等于 /login。
And let's give them a link to log in.
让我们给他们一个登录链接。
And, otherwise, you know what?
否则，你知道吗？
Let's do this.
让我们这样做。
a href equals, quote, unquote, /logout even though it doesn't exist yet if we
a 标签的 href 属性等于、引号、引号、/logout，即使它还不存在，如果我们
want to facilitate the user logging out.
想要帮助用户退出登录。
But I think this will be a nicer UI because if I reload now,
但我认为这会是一个更友好的 UI，因为如果我现在重新加载，
I'm told that I'm not logged in.
我会被告知我没有登录。
But there's my new login link shown conditionally.
但是我的新登录链接会根据条件显示。
Well, let's do this.
好吧，让我们这样做。
If I click on this, it's super small.
如果我点击它，它太小了。
But, in the bottom left-hand corner of my browser,
但是，在我的浏览器左下角，
I'm seeing the /login route.
我看到了 /login 路由。
If I click on that there is that login form, no password, super simple,
如果我点击它，就会出现登录表单，没有密码，非常简单，
just a name.
只有一个用户名。
I'll type in D-A-V-I-D. And now, notice, if I Zoom in here,
我将输入 D-A-V-I-D。现在，请注意，如果我在这里放大，
I'm indeed currently at the /login route.
我确实当前位于 /login 路由。
But, when I log in, I'm going to be--
但是，当我登录时，我将要--
oh, damn it.
哦，该死。
I did make a mistake.
我确实犯了一个错误。
405 method not allowed.
405 方法不允许。
I think we fixed this before.
我认为我们之前已经修复了这个问题。
I can go back into app.py.
我可以回到 app.py 中。
Which line number do I need to fix?
我需要修复哪一行？
Method was not supported for which route?
哪个路由不支持该方法？
So, yeah, line 16.
所以，是的，第 16 行。
So I think I need methods equals both of them.
所以我认为我需要 methods 等于它们两者。
So GET so I can display the form.
所以 GET，这样我就可以显示表单。
And POST so I can process the form.
以及 POST，这样我就可以处理表单。
Let's try this again.
让我们再试一次。
I'm just going to go back.
我只要返回。
And I'm going to click--
我将点击 --
type David and click Log In.
输入 David 并点击登录。
And I'll zoom in on the URL.
我将放大 URL。
Log In, ah, you are logged in as David.
登录，啊，您已以 David 的身份登录。
Now I can log out.
现在我可以注销了。
And, indeed, if I log out.
而且，确实，如果我注销。
This one's not going to work.
这个不会起作用。
I think I'm going to get a 404 not found, but that's fixable too.
我认为我将得到 404 未找到，但这也是可以修复的。
So let me go back into VS Code.
所以让我回到 VS Code 中。
Let me go down to the bottom of the file.
让我向下滚动到文件底部。
And let's add another route /logout.
让我们添加另一个路由 /logout。
Just GET is fine because I'm not posting anything to it.
只需要 GET 就可以了，因为我不会向它发送任何 POST 请求。
I'll define a function called logout just to match the name of the route.
我将定义一个名为 logout 的函数，以便与路由名称匹配。
And you wouldn't know this without reading the documentation,
而且如果不阅读文档，您将不知道这一点，
but if you want to clear the session and forget
但是，如果您想清除会话并忘记
the user's name, forget the items in their shopping cart,
用户名，忘记他们购物车中的商品，
you can do session.clear.
您可以执行 session.clear。
And that will just clear the contents of the session
这将清除会话的内容
wherever the server is storing them.
无论服务器将它们存储在哪里。
And then I can just return a redirect.
然后我只需要返回一个重定向。
redirect to, for instance, slash.
重定向到，例如，斜杠。
So let's see this in action.
让我们看看它的实际效果。
Let me go back to the browser and hit back.
让我回到浏览器并点击后退。
I'm logged in as David.
我已以 David 的身份登录。
But now, when I click Log out, I'm going to quickly go to--
但是现在，当我点击注销时，我将快速转到 --
and I'll show you in the inspector.
我将在检查器中向您展示。
Inspect, Network tab.
检查，网络选项卡。
Let's click on Log out.
让我们点击注销。
I indeed end up at logout first.
我确实首先到达了注销页面。
But then I'm redirected to this long URL, which is unique to my codespace.
但随后我被重定向到这个很长的 URL，它是我的代码空间独有的。
But the first logout URL redirects me with a 302 until I see a 200.
但第一个注销URL会以302重定向我，直到我看到200。
And I'm back at the home screen.
然后我回到了主屏幕。
So, even though that was a bunch of steps for me to do,
所以，即使我做了一大堆步骤，
that is how every website implements the notion of logins and also shopping
这就是每个网站实现登录和购物概念的方式。
carts.
购物车。
Now, you might add some fanciness with usernames and passwords
现在，你可能会添加一些花哨的东西，比如用户名和密码
and the like, maybe two-factor authentication and the like.
以及类似的东西，比如双重身份验证等等。
But it all boils down to storing stuff in the session
但归根结底，都是将东西存储在会话中
and using those cookie headers in order to keep track of who is who.
并使用这些cookie头来跟踪谁是谁。
Any questions on these techniques thus far?
到目前为止，对这些技术有任何疑问吗？
No?
没有？
All right, how about an actual Amazon, if a simplistic one?
好吧，一个真正的亚马逊，如果它很简单的话？
Let me do this.
让我来做这个。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到这里的VS Code。
Let me close these tabs, and let me open up an example
让我关闭这些选项卡，让我打开一个示例
that I wrote in advance, this one in my src9 directory's store folder,
我之前写过，这个在src9目录的store文件夹里，
so the beginnings of an electronic commerce store online.
所以，这是在线电子商务商店的雏形。
Let me just dive in blindly and do flask run for this one.
让我直接跳进去，为这个执行flask run。
And let me go to my browser tab and reload because I'm
让我去浏览器选项卡并重新加载，因为我
going to see my new app now.
现在要看到我的新应用。
And it's super simple, also ugly.
它超级简单，也很丑。
There's no CSS or fanciness there.
那里没有CSS或花哨的东西。
But it's just HTML.
但它只是HTML。
And this is the earliest version, if you will, of Amazon 1.0
如果你愿意，这是亚马逊1.0的早期版本
where they just sold books, and only these five books, for instance.
他们只卖书，比如只有这五本书。
So what's going on here?
那么，这里发生了什么？
Well, here is how using all of today's primitives,
好吧，这是使用今天所有的基本元件的方法，
you can start to infer how websites work.
你可以开始推断网站是如何工作的。
So let me View page source.
所以让我查看页面源代码。
And, even though the UI is not very pretty, let's see what's inside here.
而且，即使UI不是很漂亮，让我们看看这里面有什么。
There's an h1 tag for books, just like the title of the page.
有一个关于书籍的h1标签，就像页面的标题一样。
There's a whole bunch of h2s, each one of which
有一堆h2，每一个
represents apparently the title of a book.
显然代表了一本书的标题。
And below every title is a unique form.
在每个标题下面都是一个唯一的表单。
Every form, though, has an action of /cart.
但是，每个表单都有一个/cart的操作。
And every one submits via post to that cart.
并且每个表单都通过post提交到那个购物车。
But notice this trick.
但注意这个技巧。
Just like the deregistration for froshims, every one of these forms
就像froshims的注销一样，这些表单中的每一个
has a unique ID that's hidden, but the value for this one is 1.
都有一个隐藏的唯一ID，但这个的value是1。
The value for this one is 2.
这个的value是2。
The value for this one is 3.
这个的value是3。
So even though for froshims, we used it to deregister people
所以即使对于froshims，我们也用它来注销人们
to opt out of the froshims, here, you're using it to effectively add items
选择退出froshims，在这里，你用它来有效地添加项目
to your cart.
到你的购物车。
Why?
为什么？
Well, where is this data coming from?
好吧，这些数据从哪里来？
Let's poke around further.
让我们进一步看看。
I'm going to open another terminal window in VS Code.
我要在VS Code中打开另一个终端窗口。
I'll make it bigger.
我会把它放大。
I'm going to go into src9 and store.
我要进入src9和store。
And if I type ls, you'll see app.py, requirements.txt, templates,
如果我输入 ls，你会看到 app.py、requirements.txt、templates，
all of which I predicted would exist.
这些都是我预测会存在的。
There's a temporary folder called flask_session.
这里有一个名为 flask_session 的临时文件夹。
This is where, surprise, surprise, your sessions
这里就是，不出所料，你的会话
are temporarily stored on the server.
临时存储在服务器上的地方。
So even if the computer quits or reboots, the files are still there.
所以即使电脑关闭或重启，文件仍然存在。
The shopping carts are still there, but you shouldn't need to go in there.
购物车仍然存在，但你不应该需要进入那里。
And definitely don't change things in there because things will break.
而且绝对不要更改里面的东西，因为会出错。
But notice store.db, which came with my folder today.
但请注意 store.db，它今天随我的文件夹一起提供。
Let me run sqlite3 of store.db.
让我运行 store.db 的 sqlite3。
.schema to see what's going on in there.
.schema 查看里面发生了什么。
It's a super simple database table called books
这是一个非常简单的名为 books 的数据库表
with an ID column and a title column.
它有一个 ID 列和一个标题列。
And that's it.
就是这样。
Let's see what's inside.
让我们看看里面有什么。
SELECT * FROM book; Not surprisingly, there are the five books.
SELECT * FROM book；不出所料，有五本书。
So, again, you see how we're stitching these technologies together
所以，再次，你看到我们是如何将这些技术缝合在一起的
using these basic building blocks.
使用这些基本构件。
So let's look now-- let me quit out of SQLite.
所以让我们现在看看-- 让我退出 SQLite。
Let me shrink my terminal window and open up app.py.
让我缩小我的终端窗口并打开 app.py。
And there's some comments in here.
这里有一些注释。
But, for the most part, it's the same as before.
但总的来说，它与之前相同。
I'm importing some of the session stuff, so I can keep
我正在导入一些会话内容，这样我就可以继续
track of whose shopping cart is whose.
跟踪谁的购物车是谁的。
I'm opening, though, in this version, the database called store.db.
但是，在这个版本中，我正在打开名为 store.db 的数据库。
I'm doing that same stuff, copy-paste with the session just to make sure
我在做同样的事情，复制粘贴会话只是为了确保
that it works.
它起作用。
And then, down here, this is where things
然后，这里，就是事情
get really kind of interesting and, again, representative of web
变得真正有趣，并且再次，代表了 web
apps everywhere.
应用程序随处可见。
My /route, that is, my index, has this line of code first,
我的 /route，也就是我的索引，首先有这一行代码，
a book's variable that gets the return value of the CS50 function--
一个名为 books 的变量，它获取 CS50 函数的返回值--
CS50 execute functions.
CS50 执行函数。
SELECT * FROM books return value.
SELECT * FROM books 返回值。
What does that return?
它返回什么？
Well, recall that, when using the CS50 library and you're
好吧，回想一下，当使用 CS50 库并且你正在
using the SQL function, this execute function within SQL,
使用 SQL 函数时，这个在 SQL 中的 execute 函数，
you're getting back, from db.execute typically, a list of dictionaries.
你通常从 db.execute 中返回一个字典列表。
And the keys of those dictionaries represent the columns
而这些字典的键代表列
from the database table.
来自数据库表。
So here is a Python list per the square brackets.
所以这里有一个 Python 列表，根据方括号。
Every element in this list is a dictionary as per the curly braces,
此列表中的每个元素都是一个字典，根据花括号，
not to be confused with Jinja's curly braces today
不要与今天的 Jinja 的花括号混淆
and that's in the HTML files.
那在 HTML 文件中。
Here's one key.
这里是一个键。
Here's another, value and value, respectively.
这里还有另一个，分别是值和值。
So, again, db.execute, when using SELECT,
所以，再次，db.execute，当使用 SELECT 时，
returns just a list of dictionaries.
只返回一个字典列表。
It's as simple as that.
就这么简单。
So if I go back to VS Code, I have a string of SQL inside of my argument
所以如果我回到 VS Code，我的参数里包含了一串 SQL 语句
to this Python function.
传给了这个 Python 函数
That gives me a variable called books, which
这样我得到一个名为 books 的变量，它
is a list of all of the books in the database.
是一个包含数据库中所有书籍的列表
So I can certainly pass that in as an argument
所以我可以把它作为参数传递
to render template so that, when books.html is rendered,
给 render template 函数，这样当 books.html 被渲染时
it has access to all those books.
它就能访问所有这些书籍
So let me do that.
让我来做吧
Let me go into templates books.html.
让我进入 templates 文件夹下的 books.html 文件
And, perhaps not surprisingly, here's that same boilerplate as before.
不出所料，这里和之前一样是相同的模板代码
We extend the layout.
我们扩展了布局
Here's my body block.
这是我的 body 代码块
Here's that h1 tag that just says Books at the top of the page.
这是一个 h1 标签，在页面顶部显示 “Books”
And here is a Jinja for loop in the template that
这里是一个模板中的 Jinja 循环，它
is going to output, for every book, an h2, which is smaller but still bold
将输出每本书对应的 h2 标签，字体比 h1 小，但仍然是粗体
for the title.
用于显示书名
And then inside of that-- or below that is a form that's identical for every
然后在它里面或者下面是一个表单，每个表单都一样
book except--
除了
notice that I'm very cleverly outputting a unique value
注意我非常巧妙地输出了一个唯一的值
for every one of those forms.
对于每个表单
Just relying on those primary keys back and forth, back
只是依靠这些主键来回传递
and forth to implement this notion of adding.
来回传递来实现添加的功能
And so what is the /cart method?
那么/cart 方法是什么？
Let's follow these breadcrumbs.
让我们跟随这些线索
And I'm doing this deliberately live.
我故意这样做，而且是实时演示
If you were to receive or inherit code like this
如果你收到或继承了这样的代码
from a colleague, a friend, a class, you really
来自同事、朋友或课程，你真的
just follow these breadcrumbs to wrap your mind around what's going on.
只需要跟随这些线索，就能理解代码的功能
And, honestly, start with the files that feel
诚实地说，从看起来最简单的文件开始
the simplest like I did, like index.html, start with the entry point.
比如我做的 index.html，从入口文件开始
So let's see the cart route.
让我们看看 cart 路由
It's a little longer.
它有点长
But let's walk through it step by step.
但让我们一步一步地看
So the cart route supports both GET and POST.
所以 cart 路由支持 GET 和 POST 请求
It looks like, with these lines, which I haven't had occasion to use yet,
看起来，这些代码行，我还没用过
I'm just checking.
我只是检查一下
If there is no cart in the session, create a cart that's an empty list.
如果 session 中没有购物车，就创建一个空的购物车列表
And I'm doing this logically in this program
我在程序中这样做是有逻辑的
because I want to make sure that the cart always exists even if it's empty.
因为我想确保购物车始终存在，即使它是空的
Even if it's empty initially, that's what that line of code
即使它最初是空的，这就是这行代码
is essentially doing.
做的事情
So we can put things in it.
这样我们就可以往里面放东西了
So if we have submitted something to this cart and thus the method is POST,
所以如果我们向购物车提交了一些东西，那么方法就是 POST
let's go ahead and grab the ID of the book from request.form.
让我们从 request.form 中获取书籍的 ID
Let's go ahead and make sure that that ID is actually valid,
让我们确保这个 ID 确实是有效的
and it's actually a number, so it doesn't evaluate to false.
并且它确实是一个数字，所以不会被判断为 false
And if so, do this.
如果是，就做下面的操作
Go into the sessions cart, which is initially an empty list.
进入 session 里的购物车，它最初是一个空列表
And, just like we saw in week six, append an item to the list.
就像我们在第六周看到的，将一个条目追加到列表中
Append, append, append.
追加、追加、追加。
So we just have a list of book IDs.
所以我们现在只有一系列书籍ID。
And then, when you are done with that, redirect to the cart route.
然后，当你完成这些操作后，重定向到购物车页面。
Well, that's a little weird and almost recursive
嗯，这有点奇怪，而且几乎是递归的
because the cart route that we're in is redirecting to itself.
因为我们所在的购物车页面正在重定向到它自己。
But redirects are always get requests when done like this.
但是，当以这种方式执行重定向时，它始终是GET请求。
So even though we ended up here via a POST,
所以即使我们通过POST请求到达这里，
this redirect is going to send me back via a GET, to the same route.
这个重定向将通过GET请求把我送回同一个页面。
And that is why now, outside of the conditional, these final two lines
所以现在，在条件语句之外，最后两行
apply.
生效。
Here is a books variable.
这里有一个books变量。
I don't want to get all of the books because I'm not showing you
我不想获取所有书籍，因为我不会展示给你
the catalog now of amazon.com.
现在亚马逊网站的商品目录。
I'm showing you your shopping cart.
我正在展示你的购物车。
And how do I do this?
我该怎么做呢？
I'm SELECTing * FROM books WHERE the id of the book is IN this list of ids.
我从books表中选择所有行，其中书籍id位于该id列表中。
And you haven't seen this yet most likely.
而且你很可能还没有见过这个。
But, in the CS50 library, if you use parentheses and a question mark,
但是，在CS50库中，如果你使用括号和问号，
so placeholder as always, you can then plug a list into that question mark,
所以像往常一样占位符，然后你可以将列表插入问号中，
and the library will separate them all via commas.
库将用逗号将它们全部分隔开。
You might have for a past problem set manually.
对于之前的习题，你可能手动做过。
We will generate the commas for you.
我们将为你生成逗号。
So everything is nicely escaped.
所以一切都很好地转义了。
And then we're just rendering a template cart.html, passing in those books.
然后我们只是渲染一个模板cart.html，并将这些书籍传递进去。
So what's cart.html?
那么cart.html是什么呢？
That's the last breadcrumb to follow.
这是最后要跟踪的线索。
cart.html, and really nothing going on that's that interesting here.
cart.html，这里实际上没有什么有趣的事情。
There's an h1 tag at the top.
顶部有一个h1标签。
There's an ordered list, which is a numbered list just because.
这里有一个有序列表，只是一个编号列表。
And then there's this Jinja loop that's outputting a list item or li element
然后这里有一个Jinja循环，它输出一个列表项或li元素
for every book showing its title.
用于显示每本书的标题。
So if I go back to the store here and actually start
所以如果我回到商店，开始
adding things to the cart, there, I've added that to the cart.
添加东西到购物车，我已经添加了它。
All right, just one book.
好的，只有一本书。
Let's jump to the last one, so the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
让我们跳到最后一本书，银河系漫游指南。
How about Mostly Harmless?
那基本上无害呢？
Click that.
点击它。
Now there's two items in the shopping cart.
现在购物车里有2件商品了。
Let me go back.
让我回去。
There's now three items in the shopping cart and so forth.
现在购物车里有3件商品了，以此类推。
But if I were to make this URL public-- it's currently private by default.
但是如果我要公开这个URL--它目前默认是私有的。
So not everyone on the internet can visit it at the same time.
所以不是每个人都能同时访问它。
If I were to make this public and any one of you
如果我要公开这个，而你们中的任何一个人
were to open it on your phone or laptop, you
在你的手机或笔记本电脑上打开它，你
would see an empty cart because you would have a different handstamp,
会看到一个空购物车，因为你会有一个不同的手印，
a different cookie.
一个不同的cookie。
But the server would be keeping track of all of our shopping carts
但是服务器会跟踪我们所有的购物车
in, if you will, that flask session folder, just all sort of
在，如果你愿意，那个flask session文件夹中，就是各种各样的
happens automatically.
自动发生。
Phew, OK.
呼，好的。
So that then is how amazon.com is implemented.
这就是 Amazon.com 的实现方式。
Questions?
有问题吗？
Yeah.
是的。
AUDIENCE: Or is the client--
观众：还是客户——
so let's say if you open up this application.
比如，你打开这个应用程序。
How do the server know that this is to be a new session now?
服务器如何知道这现在是一个新会话？
[INAUDIBLE] and someone who starts up a new session.
[听不清]，以及启动新会话的人。
How does the browser [INAUDIBLE] when someone [INAUDIBLE] that is
浏览器如何[听不清]，当有人[听不清]，那是
like a new session?
像一个新会话？
DAVID J. MALAN: A really good question.
大卫·马兰：一个非常好的问题。
How does the browser--
浏览器如何——
how does the server to give you a brand-new session the first time you
服务器如何才能在你第一次访问网站时给你一个全新的会话？
visit a website?
访问网站？
When you visit something.com for the first time,
当你第一次访问 something.com 时，
your browser will not send a cookie header.
你的浏览器不会发送 cookie 头。
There will be no cookie colon session equals value.
不会有 cookie 冒号会话等于值。
It's just going to be blank, it's going to be my showing you
它将是空白的，它将是我向你展示
my other hand that has no ink on it.
我的另一只手上没有墨水。
Then the server will know, well, if you didn't send me a cookie,
然后服务器就会知道，嗯，如果你没有给我发送 cookie，
I'm going to set one for you by stamping your hand with the set cookie header.
我将使用 set cookie 头为你在你的手上盖章，来为你设置一个。
It's just going to generate typically a really big random number that's
它通常会生成一个非常大的随机数，它是
different for you, for me, for you to keep track of us individually.
对你、对我、对你是不同的，以便分别跟踪我们。
So that's all.
就是这样。
It would just happen by default. And Flask makes all of that
它会自动发生。Flask 使所有这一切
happen because we have not only imported these lines at the top.
发生，因为我们不仅在顶部导入了这些行。
We have also used these configuration lines too
我们也使用过这些配置行
to ensure that the server does exactly what I just described.
以确保服务器完全按照我刚才描述的方式运行。
If you had to do all of that manually, honestly, it
如果你必须手动完成所有这些工作，说实话，它
would be so annoying to make web applications because you'd
会让创建网络应用程序变得非常烦人，因为你得
do copy-paste all of the time.
一直进行复制粘贴。
This is still some copy-paste, but it's way less than implementing
这仍然有一些复制粘贴，但这远远少于实现
all of this cookie stuff on your own.
你自己所有的 cookie 相关的东西。
All right, how about a final set of examples
好的，我们来看最后一组示例
that allow us to escalate quickly to a larger data
使我们能够快速升级到更大的数据
set and make this more like an actual amazon.com or maybe an actual imdb.com.
集，并使它更像一个真正的 Amazon.com，或者可能是一个真正的 IMDb.com。
And we'll do this by way of a tour of some pre-written examples
我们将通过参观一些预先编写好的示例来做到这一点
rather than do all of these here from scratch.
而不是从头开始在这里做所有这些。
So I'm going to go into my terminal window.
所以我要进入我的终端窗口。
I'm going to hit Control-c to kill the previous version of the store.
我将按下 Ctrl-c 来杀死商店的先前版本。
And I'm going to go into shows version 0 initially, which has our old friend
我将最初进入 shows 版本 0，它包含我们老朋友
shows.db from our SQL lecture, which has all of the latest TV shows from IMDb
来自 SQL 讲座的 shows.db，它包含了来自 IMDb 的所有最新电视剧
using the same schema as then.
使用与当时相同的模式。
And there's an app.py.
还有一个 app.py。
There's a requirements.txt.
还有一个 requirements.txt。
And there's a templates folder just as predicted
还有一个 templates 文件夹，正如预期的那样
because we're still using Flask.
因为我们仍然使用 Flask。
So let's go ahead and take a look at what's
所以，让我们继续看看是什么
going on inside of this file app.py as our entry point.
这个文件app.py里面正在发生的事情，作为我们的入口点。
All right, so I see some pretty familiar imports now.
好了，现在我看到了一些非常熟悉的导入。
I see shows.db using the SQL library, so nothing too interesting there.
我看到shows.db使用SQL库，所以这里没什么太有趣的东西。
The index route is super simple.
索引路由超级简单。
It's just rendering index.html.
它只是渲染index.html。
And then there's a search route.
然后还有一个搜索路由。
So this is kind of an amalgam of google.com and imdb.com.
所以这有点像google.com和imdb.com的混合体。
I want to implement this relatively simple search
我想实现这个相对简单的搜索
website for IMDb, just a search box.
IMDb 网站，只是一个搜索框。
Well, we can kind of preemptively infer how this is going to work.
好吧，我们可以先发制人地推断一下这是如何工作的。
A shows variable is being set to the return value of db.execute,
一个shows变量被设置为db.execute的返回值，
where I'm executing SELECT * FROM shows WHERE the title of the show
我在执行SELECT * FROM shows WHERE the title of the show
equals this question mark.
等于这个问号。
And what am I plugging in?
我该插入什么呢？
Well, just like Google, I'm plugging in the value of the q attribute
好吧，就像谷歌一样，我插入了q属性的值
from the URL apparently.
显然来自URL。
Then I'm rendering a template called search.html.
然后我渲染一个名为search.html的模板。
And I'm passing in those shows as a list of Python dictionaries.
我将这些shows作为Python字典列表传递进去。
So that's it.
就是这样。
It's only-- that's the entirety of the back-end logic here.
这只是——这里的所有后端逻辑。
It's a search engine.
这是一个搜索引擎。
So what might I want to do next?
那么接下来我想做什么呢？
Well, my mind goes to index.html.
好吧，我的脑海里浮现了index.html。
Let's just see what the template looks like.
我们看看这个模板长什么样。
So I can wrap my mind around index.html.
这样我就可以理解index.html。
OK, it's pretty darn simple.
好吧，它非常简单。
It's just a form that has an action of /search,
它只是一个有一个/search操作的表单，
which aligns with the route we just saw.
这与我们刚才看到的路由相一致。
Method is get.
方法是get。
It's got an autocompleting input called q, as expected,
它有一个名为q的自动完成输入，正如预期的那样，
and a button called Search.
还有一个名为Search的按钮。
So not really that stimulating there versus past examples we've done.
所以，与我们过去做的例子相比，这里并不那么令人兴奋。
Let me go into search.html, which is the other template in here.
让我进入search.html，这是这里另一个模板。
So let me open my terminal and do code of templates search.html.
所以让我打开我的终端，并执行templates search.html的代码。
Close the terminal.
关闭终端。
OK, this is kind of like the bookstore too.
好吧，这有点像书店。
It's just iterating over the shows, outputting list item, list item,
它只是遍历shows，输出列表项，列表项，
list item.
列表项。
But I'm using an unordered list instead of ordered.
但我使用的是无序列表而不是有序列表。
So there's not that much to this application to enabling search.
所以，这个应用程序启用搜索并不需要太多内容。
But recall that, two weeks ago, when we introduced HTML and CSS and JavaScript,
但请回想一下，两周前，当我们引入HTML、CSS和JavaScript时，
we completely punted to the actual google.com.
我们完全转向了真正的google.com。
Today we are, if you will, google.com or imdb.com.
今天我们是，如果你愿意，google.com或imdb.com。
So let's go into the terminal window, do flask run.
所以，让我们进入终端窗口，执行flask run。
I'll go back into my browser and reload.
我将返回到我的浏览器并重新加载。
So we no longer see the store.
所以我们不再看到商店了。
We now see IMDb.
我们现在看到IMDb。
And it's a pretty simple search box.
它是一个非常简单的搜索框。
Let me search for the office as in the past, click Search.
让我像以前一样搜索office，点击搜索。
And notice two things.
请注意两件事。
At the top of the URL is ?q=the+office.
URL 首部是 ?q=the+office。
The plus is a way of encoding spaces in URLs so that it's just one long string,
加号是用来对 URL 中的空格进行编码的一种方法，这样它就只是一串长字符串，
but that's conventional.
但这是一种惯例。
And then there's a lot of offices.
然后就出现很多个办公室。
But why is this?
为什么会出现这种情况？
Well, there's the American one, the UK one.
嗯，有一个美国版，还有一个英国版。
There's some prior ones that weren't nearly as popular as either.
还有一些早期的版本，它们远没有这两个版本受欢迎。
So there's a bunch of offices in there.
所以里面有很多个办公室。
But we could probably--
但我们可能可以——
we can tie our ideas together here.
将我们的想法联系在一起。
Let me open another terminal.
让我打开另一个终端。
Make it bigger.
放大它。
Go into src9 shows0.
进入 src9 shows0。
sqlite3 of shows.db .schema.
shows.db 的 sqlite3 .schema。
Oh, yeah, there's a lot of data in this database.
哦，是的，这个数据库里有大量的数据。
Let's do .schema show specifically.
让我们 specifically 做 .schema show。
OK, so we have the year of every show.
好的，所以我们有每个节目的年份。
So this just means I can play around now with the intersection of SQL and Python
所以这意味着我现在可以玩玩 SQL 和 Python 的交集了
as follows.
如下所示。
Let me go back to how about search.html.
让我回到 search.html。
And, instead of just showing the title, why don't I
还有，与其只显示标题，我为什么不
do something like curly curly brace show, quote, unquote, year.
做一些类似于花括号、show、引号、引号、年份这样的操作。
Curly curly brace because why?
为什么用花括号？
Well, every element in this list is a dictionary.
嗯，这个列表中的每个元素都是一个字典。
So I have access to all of those SQL columns.
所以我可以访问所有这些 SQL 列。
So let me reload.
所以让我重新加载。
And now you see, oh, that's why there's so many offices.
现在你看到了，哦，这就是为什么有这么多办公室。
They're each from different years.
它们分别来自不同的年份。
So every piece of data you have access in SQL you have access to in Python you
所以你在 SQL 中可以访问的每条数据，你也可以在 Python 中访问，你现在可以通过
now have access to in HTML by just knowing
了解如何将这些想法拼凑起来
how to stitch these ideas together.
来访问 HTML 中的数据。
All right, so what's not so good about this?
好的，那么这样做的不好之处是什么？
Well, if I go back to the search box and I search for just office, Enter,
嗯，如果我回到搜索框，只搜索 office，然后回车，
there's apparently no show called literally office, at least lowercase o.
显然没有一个节目叫 office，至少小写 o 不是。
Let me try a little more specific, Office, as someone might type.
让我尝试更具体一点，Office，就像有人可能会输入的那样。
OK, so there's one version of Office, but not The Office from 2013.
好的，所以有一个版本的 Office，但不是 2013 年的 The Office。
But what if I want to have more of a wild card search?
但是如果我想进行更多通配符搜索呢？
Well, we can borrow these ideas too.
好吧，我们也可以借用这些想法。
So let me go back into VS Code here in my app.py.
所以让我回到 VS Code 中的 app.py。
And I think here, instead of using equal, what was the keyword?
我认为这里，而不是使用等号，关键词是什么？
Yeah, so we can do like, for instance.
是的，所以我们可以像这样，例如。
But this we have to be a little careful of.
但我们必须小心一点。
We don't want to resort to a Python f-string
我们不想诉诸于 Python f-string
where we plug in values with percent signs and the like.
在那里我们用百分号等符号插入值。
So this is a little bit tricky, but it's worth
所以这有点棘手，但值得
knowing that if you want to do wildcard searches safely
知道如果你想安全地进行通配符搜索
we still should distrust the user's input.
我们仍然应该不信任用户的输入。
So what I'm going to do is this even though it's
所以我要这样做，尽管它
going to look a little cryptic.
看起来有点神秘。
I'm going to just do a question mark.
我将只做一个问号。
But, instead of passing in request.args.get of q,
但是，与其直接传入 request.args.get 的 q，
first, let's tuck this in a variable so the code is a little more readable.
我们先把它塞到一个变量里，这样代码的可读性会更高。
q equals that even though that's not changing anything fundamentally.
q 等于它，虽然这在本质上并没有改变任何东西。
Let's do this.
我们试试看。
Let's put my percent sign here, concatenate q with that,
我们在这里放一个百分号，将 q 与它连接起来，
and then put another percent sign here so that this whole string,
然后在这里再放一个百分号，这样整个字符串，
after joining and joining three things together, gets
在将三个东西连接在一起之后，就会
plugged into the question mark and therefore escaped.
被插入问号中，从而被转义。
You should not use an f-string for this thing.
你不应该为此使用 f-字符串。
You should always use the question mark placeholder as we keep preaching.
你应该始终使用问号占位符，就像我们一直倡导的那样。
All right, so now that I've done this, I think my search functionality just
好的，现在我已经做完这些了，我认为我的搜索功能就
got way better.
变得好多了。
Why?
为什么？
So if I go back to the form--
所以，如果我回到表单——
and I'll reload to clear everything.
然后我重新加载以清除所有内容。
I'll zoom in a little bit.
我会稍微放大一点。
Let's type in just office in lowercase with no the.
让我们只输入小写的 office，没有 the。
And I think I should get now every TV show that has office, O-F-F-I-C-E,
我认为我现在应该得到所有包含 office，O-F-F-I-C-E 的电视剧，
in it somewhere even if it's officer.
即使是 officer，它也应该包含在其中。
So that might not be quite what we want.
所以，这可能不是我们真正想要的。
But there's indeed a much broader match here.
但确实这里匹配范围更广。
So more like the imdb.com.
所以更像是 imdb.com。
But now it's a design decision.
但这现在是一个设计决策。
Do you want your-- do you want to be really nitpicky
你想要你的——你想要变得非常吹毛求疵吗？
and require users to type in The Office?
并要求用户输入 The Office？
Do you want it to be capitalized?
你想要它被大写吗？
This now becomes more of a user interface or design decision, not so
这现在更多地变成了一个用户界面或设计决策，而不是
much code.
太多代码。
All right, well, let's make one tweak here
好的，我们在这里做一个小小的调整，
that's representative all the more of today's modern apps.
它更能代表当今的现代应用程序。
It turns out that this approach of generating
事实证明，这种方法，即在用户提交输入或访问新 URL 时
new HTML every time a user submits input or visits a new URL
每次生成新的 HTML，
is increasingly dated whereby every URL is unique, as opposed to apps
越来越过时了，因为每个 URL 都是唯一的，而不是应用程序
being much more interactive.
更加交互。
So it turns out, there's this technique in general,
所以事实证明，一般来说，
in the world of the web, where you use something
在网络世界中，你使用某些东西，
called AJAX, which used to stand for Asynchronous JavaScript And XML.
叫做 AJAX，它曾经代表异步 JavaScript 和 XML。
Nowadays, it just refers to using JavaScript
现在，它只是指使用 JavaScript
to get more data from the server so the user's URL doesn't even change,
从服务器获取更多数据，这样用户的 URL 甚至不会改变，
and the whole browser screen doesn't flash as though the whole page is
整个浏览器屏幕不会像整个页面一样闪烁。
being reloaded.
正在重新加载。
So this is going to look a little more cryptic.
所以这看起来会更神秘一点。
But let me go ahead and show you an alternative
但我还是继续向你展示一个替代方案，
to this relatively easy approach.
替代这种相对简单的方案。
A lot of today might be feeling like a lot.
今天很多东西可能让你感觉很多。
It's about to feel more like a lot but not in a way
它即将让你感觉更多，但不是以一种
that you need to replicate, just to give you a taste of what more modern web
你需要复制的方式，只是让你体验一下更加现代的网络
apps are doing.
应用程序在做什么。
I'm going to close these two tabs.
我将关闭这两个选项卡。
I'm going to go ahead and exit out of SQLite.
我将继续退出 SQLite。
I'm going to kill my previous version of Flask.
我将关闭我之前版本的 Flask。
And I'm going to go into shows version 2 now.
现在我将进入 shows 版本 2。
And, in shows2, I'm going to do flask run.
在 shows2 中，我将运行 flask。
So the app is running.
所以应用程序正在运行。
I'm going to go back to my URL here and just reload.
我将回到我的 URL 并重新加载。
And notice I've gotten rid of the Search button altogether,
请注意，我已经完全去掉了搜索按钮，
minor aesthetic detail.
一个小小的美学细节。
But what I like about this now is that if I search for O-F-F-I-C-E,
但现在我喜欢的是，如果我搜索 O-F-F-I-C-E，
you're seeing the beginnings of autocomplete,
你会看到自动完成的开始，
which is kind of everywhere.
这几乎无处不在。
But you can't implement autocomplete if you have to reload the whole page,
但是，如果你必须重新加载整个页面，你无法实现自动完成，
reload the whole page.
重新加载整个页面。
Why?
为什么？
If nothing else, the user's going to be--
如果不是别的，用户将要——
see a big flash of white as the whole page redraws itself,
看到整个页面重新绘制时出现的白光闪现，
which is not what we're used to.
这不是我们习惯的。
If I start over, O-F-F, notice the URL is not changing, nor is the whole page
如果我重新开始，O-F-F，请注意 URL 并没有改变，整个页面也没有
flickering.
闪烁。
Just the URL is getting shorter, shorter, shorter.
只是 URL 越来越短，越来越短，越来越短。
And if I really go shorter, there it is.
如果我再缩短一点，它就在那里。
Officer, now I have only this many bullets on the screen.
警官，现在我屏幕上只有这么多子弹。
There's no more below the break.
断行下方没有更多。
So how can I do this?
那么我该怎么做呢？
Well, let's try to infer a little bit here
好吧，让我们在这里尝试推断一下
and be demonstrative of how you can infer
并演示如何推断
how a third-party websites are working.
第三方网站是如何工作的。
If you want to-- if you want to mimic their behavior
如果你想——如果你想模仿他们的行为
or just learn better how they work-- so let me do this.
或者只是更好地了解它们是如何工作的——所以让我这样做。
Let me open up developer tools.
让我打开开发者工具。
Let me open the Network tab.
让我打开网络选项卡。
And let me search for O. And watch what happens in my Network tab
让我搜索 O。观察我的网络选项卡中发生了什么
even though the URL of the page is not changing.
即使页面 URL 没有改变。
O. Apparently, an HTTP request was sent from my browser to this URL,
O。显然，我的浏览器向这个 URL 发送了一个 HTTP 请求，
which is essentially representing /search?q=O.
它本质上代表 /search?q=O。
Notice that the response was 200.
请注意，响应为 200。
And what is in that response?
那么响应中是什么呢？
Well, let me click on that row.
好吧，让我点击那一行。
Let me click on response.
让我点击响应。
And, very interestingly, notice what came back.
非常有趣的是，请注意返回的内容。
It's not a whole web page.
它不是一个完整的网页。
It's just a bunch of li elements, which you can kind of infer
它只是一堆 li 元素，你可以推断出来
are probably the ones that are getting snuck into the page dynamically.
它们可能是动态添加到页面中的元素。
So if I go back to the top, there's no ul here.
所以如果我回到顶部，这里没有 ul。
It's just a bunch of lis.
它只是一堆 lis。
And watch what happens this time.
看看这次发生了什么。
Let me close that panel.
让我关闭那个面板。
Let me search for O-F without even hitting Enter.
让我搜索 O-F，甚至不用按回车键。
Here we go, O-F. Now there's a second request.
好了，O-F。现在有第二个请求了。
And
并且
If I zoom in, there it is, q=OF.
如果我放大，它就在那里，q=OF。
If I click on that and zoom out, you'll see a whole bunch of lis.
如果我点击它并缩小，你会看到一大堆li。
But let me claim there's fewer of them now because fewer strings match O-F.
但我想说，现在它们的数量减少了，因为与O-F匹配的字符串减少了。
And if I finally type in office, let alone the office,
而且如果我最终输入office，更不用说office，
notice now, at the very bottom of this, every time you're
请注意，现在，在最底部，每次你
doing an autocomplete, it's sending an HTTP request, HTTP request,
进行自动完成功能时，它会发送一个HTTP请求，HTTP请求，
HTTP request.
HTTP请求。
Back in my day, you'd have to click Submit.
在我那个年代，你必须点击提交。
The whole page would reload, and you'd see the list again and again.
整个页面都会重新加载，你会一遍又一遍地看到列表。
This is more modern.
这更现代。
And this is an example indeed of what's called
这确实是一个被称为
AJAX, Asynchronous JavaScript that's getting you more data
AJAX（异步JavaScript），它会为你获取更多数据
and slipping it into your existing web page.
并将它插入你现有的网页中。
So how does this work?
那么，这是如何工作的呢？
Let me go to VS Code here.
让我到这里的VS Code。
Let me open up a new terminal.
让我打开一个新的终端。
Let me go into src9 shows2.
让我进入src9 shows2。
And let me open up, for instance, the index
让我打开，比如，index
template, which is the entry point.
模板，它是入口点。
Everything at the top is sort of boring.
顶部的一切都相当无聊。
Here's the head of the page.
这是页面的头部。
Here's the input.
这是输入。
I didn't even bother with the whole form because I'm not even
我甚至没有费心处理整个表单，因为我甚至没有
submitting a whole form.
提交整个表单。
So I don't need an action or a method or anything like that.
所以我不需要动作或方法或任何类似的东西。
I'm just using it as a dumb input box only.
我只是把它用作一个简单的输入框而已。
But notice that it is indeed an input of type search.
但是请注意，它确实是一个类型为搜索的输入。
Here, now, is an empty ul, initially.
这里，现在，最初是一个空的ul。
So this is why, when you visit the page, you see a text box but no bullets
所以这就是为什么当你访问页面时，你会看到一个文本框，但没有项目符号
because the list is empty.
因为列表是空的。
And, in fact, watch this.
事实上，看看这个。
If I click on elements in the Developer Tools, click on body, expand the body,
如果我在开发者工具中点击元素，点击body，展开body，
there is the ul.
那里就是ul。
If I zoom in, there's nothing inside of it yet.
如果我放大，里面还没有任何东西。
That's why we see no bullets.
这就是为什么我们没有看到项目符号。
But if I go back to the template, here's some JavaScript code,
但如果我回到模板，这里有一些JavaScript代码，
which we haven't spent much time on, but you
我们没有花太多时间在上面，但你可以
can start to wrap your mind around this line by line as follows.
逐行开始理解这句话，如下所示。
Give me a variable called input.
给我一个名为input的变量。
Set it equal to the element from the DOM, the tree in the computer's
将其设置为DOM中的元素，也就是计算机内存中的树，
memory for the input element, so that rectangle from our pictures
用于输入元素的内存，也就是我们上周图片中的那个矩形
from last week.
来自上周。
Then listen to that input for the input event.
然后监听该输入的输入事件。
I showed briefly last week a list of like dragging and clicking and mouse up
上周我简单地展示了一个拖动、点击、鼠标弹起
and mouse down and key up and key down.
以及鼠标按下、键盘弹起和键盘按下。
And input just means generally inputting into a text box.
而输入只是意味着一般地输入到一个文本框中。
Here, I'm calling a function.
在这里，我正在调用一个函数。
It's an asynchronous function in the sense that there--
这是一个异步函数，因为
it's going to get back to me eventually.
它最终会回复我。
If the server is slow, it might take a moment or two.
如果服务器速度很慢，可能需要一两分钟。
But, inside of this function, give me a variable called response.
但是，在这个函数里面，给我一个叫做 response 的变量。
Go ahead and fetch the URL whose path or route is /search?q= and then
然后，获取路径或者路由是/search?q=的URL
concatenate onto that whatever the user's input that is the value of that
将用户输入的值连接到上面。
input.
输入框。
Then create a variable called shows, go into that response from the server,
然后创建一个叫做shows的变量，进入服务器返回的 response
and get its text value.
并获取它的文本值。
So we're not going to spend much time on this.
我们不会花太多时间在上面。
But fetch is a function that comes with browsers today
但是，fetch 是现在浏览器自带的函数
in JavaScript that lets you make an HTTP request.
在 JavaScript 中，它允许你发送 HTTP 请求。
Fetch more content from the server.
从服务器获取更多内容。
And you essentially pass it in the URL that you want to fetch or get.
你需要将你想要获取的URL传递给它。
This function here response.text just grabs the text
这个函数 response.text 只是获取文本
from that response, which means if I go to the Network tab and I type in O
从返回的 response 中，这意味着如果我去网络标签并输入 O
as before and I click this, response.text is all of this stuff
就像之前一样，点击它，response.text 就是所有这些东西
that we manually looked at earlier.
我们之前手动查看过的东西。
So you're just getting all of the text that came back from the server that
所以你只是获取从服务器返回的所有文本，
happened to be lis.
碰巧是 lis。
Lastly, go into the document, the DOM, select the ul element,
最后，进入文档，DOM，选择 ul 元素，
go into its inner HTML, and change the inner HTML to be that text, aka shows.
进入它的内部 HTML，并将内部 HTML 更改为文本，也就是 shows。
And so what's happening here-- and watch this now when I-- let's
所以这里发生了什么-- 现在看着我-- 让我们
reload the page.
重新加载页面。
Let me show you the Elements tab.
让我给你看元素标签。
Let me highlight and zoom in on the ul element.
让我突出显示并放大 ul 元素。
In the bottom of the screen, nothing's there yet but watch.
在屏幕底部，还没有任何东西，但看着。
As soon as I type O, and I get back all of those lis,
当我输入 O 时，我将返回所有这些 lis，
and they get crammed into the inner HTML of the ul, watch the ul as I type O,
并将它们塞入 ul 的内部 HTML 中，当我在输入 O 时，注意 ul，
there's now more stuff there.
现在那里有更多的东西。
And, indeed, if I expand it, there are all of the lis.
事实上，如果我展开它，那里有所有 lis。
That is the inner HTML that just got automatically populated.
这就是刚刚自动填充的内部 HTML。
And if I type in more, officer, notice that if I scroll down,
如果我输入更多，警官，注意，如果我向下滚动，
there's only so many of them.
只有这么多。
And if I just type in nonsense, notice it's back to 0
如果我只是输入胡说八道，注意它又回到了 0
because there's no text coming back from the server.
因为没有文本从服务器返回。
This then is an example of the beginning of an API.
然后这是一个 API 起始的例子。
And I've used this term over time, but an API is an Application Programming
我已经用了很长时间这个词了，但是 API 是应用程序编程
Interface.
接口。
And it's a standardized way, generally, of getting data
它通常是一种标准化的方法，用于从
from someone else's server or service into your application.
其他人服务器或服务获取数据到你的应用程序中。
Now, in this contrived scenario, I am both the web developer,
现在，在这个人为编造的场景中，我就是网页开发者，
and I'm the author of the API.
我也是 API 的作者。
But they're implementing-- they're being implemented in the same application.
但是它们正在实现-- 它们正在同一个应用程序中实现。
But you could imagine, actually, querying amazon.com for actual books
但你可以想象，实际上，查询 amazon.com 以获取实际的书籍
and actual prices and actual photographs thereof
以及实际价格和实际照片
from their servers instead of your own.
从它们的服务器，而不是你自己的服务器。
And so they might very well send to your server
所以他们很可能会发送到你的服务器
those kinds of responses by just sending you a whole bunch of text that, again,
这些响应类型只是向你发送一堆文本，再次强调，
might just look like all of these lis.
可能看起来像是所有这些列表标签。
But the lis is a sloppy way of sending information.
但列表标签是一种发送信息很糟糕的方式。
Nowadays, it's not common to use HTML, nor something called XML
如今，使用 HTML 或者 XML 发送数据已不再常见，
to send back your data.
用来发送回你的数据。
Rather, it's more common to get back something
相反，更常见的是收到一些
called JSON, JavaScript Object Notation.
被称为 JSON，即 JavaScript 对象表示法。
And odds are, for your final project, if you do anything with an API,
而且很有可能，在你最后的项目中，如果你使用了 API，
you'll encounter this in the real world.
你将在现实世界中遇到这种情况。
And JSON looks very, very similar to what a dictionary and a list
JSON 看起来非常非常像 Python 中的字典和列表
looks like in Python.
的样子。
The syntax is almost the same as you've seen.
语法几乎与你之前见过的相同。
However, in the world of JSON, JavaScript Object Notation,
然而，在 JSON 的世界中，即 JavaScript 对象表示法中，
you have to use double quotes around your strings.
你必须在字符串周围使用双引号。
You cannot use single quotes.
你不能使用单引号。
And, generally, it might look like this.
而且，通常情况下，它可能看起来像这样。
So here, for instance, is a response from a more modern version
所以，例如，这是一个来自更现代版本的响应
of a server that's not sending back li tags and a messy bunch of HTML.
服务器，它没有发送回列表标签和一堆混乱的 HTML 代码。
It's sending back something that's more machine readable.
它发送回一些更适合机器读取的东西。
So this text, ugly as it is, is much easier for a JSON parser, a function
所以这个文本，虽然看起来很丑，但对于 JSON 解析器，一个函数来说，
to read, because it's all standard.
更容易读取，因为它都是标准化的。
It's all square brackets, curly braces, quotes, colons, and all of that.
它都是方括号、花括号、引号、冒号等等。
And, even though it looks like a mess on the screen,
而且，即使它在屏幕上看起来很乱，
it's very standardized, unlike li tags which
它非常标准化，不像列表标签，谁知道在美观上会返回什么？
who knows what might come back in those aesthetically?
由于有如此多的 HTML 标签，更不用说 CSS 了。
Since there's so many HTML tags, not to mention CSS.
所以让我们在这里做一些修改。
So let's make a change here.
让我回到 VS Code 这里。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我关闭这个标签并退出这个版本的应用程序。
Let me close this tab and quit out of this version of my application.
让我通过进入 shows 版本 3 来展示 shows 的最后一个版本。
And let me show one final version of shows by going into shows version 3.
在这个版本中，我要这样做。
And, in this version, I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要打开 app.py。
I'm going to open up app.py.
在 app.py 中，我要从 Flask 框架导入另一个函数
And, in app.py, I'm going to import one more function
名为 jsonify，它不一定是
from the flask framework called jsonify, which is not necessarily
一个技术术语。
a technical term.
它只是意味着将某些东西转换成 JSON。
It just means turn something into JSON.
这是什么意思呢？
So what does that mean?
注意，这里有一个看起来像这样的搜索路由。
Well, notice that, down here, I have a search route that looks like this.
但在我们查看它之前，它将以这个扰流器结束，
But, before we look at that, which is going to end with this spoiler,
就像 jsonify 一样，让我实际做一下。
like jsonify, let me actually do this.
让我从 shows 版本 2 中打开
Let me open up also from shows version 2,
之前的版本，它看起来像这样。
the previous version of this, which looked like this here.
这是 app -
This was the app--
之前示例中的搜索路由。
the search route from the previous example.
这就是我获得 q 的方式。
Here's how I got q.
这就是我使用通配符对用户输入进行转义的方式。
Here's how again I did the escaping of the user's input with the wildcard.
但请注意，我还做了这件事。
But notice that I also did this.
If the user got back no results, then I just gave it an empty list instead.
如果用户没有得到任何结果，我就直接给它一个空列表。
But let me show you two from last time. search.html looked like this.
但让我展示一下上次的两个。search.html 看起来像这样。
And shows2 in templates, shows.html--
以及模板中的 shows2，shows.html--
whoops.
哎呦。
search.html, what you'll see here is the very simple template
search.html，在这里你会看到非常简单的模板
that generated all of that text, all of those lis just again
它生成了所有这些文字，所有这些列表，再次
and again and again.
一次又一次。
So we're going to get rid of that template
所以我们要摆脱这个模板
in this third and final version here.
在这个第三个也是最后一个版本中。
So if I go into shows3, notice I'm doing the same code as before.
所以，如果我进入 shows3，请注意，我正在使用与之前相同的代码。
I'm building up a Python list of shows that results from that SQL query.
我正在构建一个 Python 列表，其中包含来自 SQL 查询的结果。
But, instead of passing it into any template,
但是，我没有把它传递给任何模板，
I'm just jsonifying that text.
我只是将文本转换成 JSON 格式。
What that means is that what I'm essentially
这意味着我本质上
going to send from the server to the browser
将要从服务器发送到浏览器
is literally something that looks like this here on the screen.
实际上就是屏幕上显示的这种内容。
So if I go back to VS Code here and run flask run in this final version,
所以，如果我回到这里的 VS Code 并在这个最终版本中运行 flask run，
and I go over to my other tab here and reload,
然后我转到另一个选项卡并重新加载，
I have the same response as before.
我得到的是与之前相同的响应。
And it's actually going to work the same.
实际上它将以相同的方式工作。
Office is going to still work the same.
“办公室”仍然可以正常工作。
But if I undo that and go to inspect and go to my Network tab here
但是，如果我撤销操作，然后去检查，并进入我的网络选项卡，
and now search for O, same paradigm as before.
现在搜索 O，与之前一样。
There /search?q=o, let's click on that.
那里 /search?q=o，点击它。
But notice-- and let me make this even bigger on the screen--
但是请注意，让我在屏幕上放大它，
this, even though it looks more verbose and it is, it's way more standardized.
虽然它看起来更详细，实际上也是，但它更标准化。
And this is the, quote, unquote, "right way" to send data over the internet
这是在互联网上发送数据的“正确方式”，
when you want two pieces of software to generate and consume it respectively.
当你想要两个软件分别生成和使用它时。
Here, now, we have not only just the titles of the shows,
现在，我们不仅拥有节目的标题，
but I've even been generous and sent the number of episodes,
而且我还慷慨地发送了剧集数量，
the unique ID, the title, the year, I've essentially
唯一 ID，标题，年份，我基本上
sent the entire SQL database in a standard, portable, textual format
以标准、可移植的文本格式发送了整个 SQL 数据库
that my code can now use.
我的代码现在可以使用它。
So, when you think about most any modern application, we come back to Gmail.
因此，当你想到大多数现代应用程序时，我们回到 Gmail。
When you access something like Gmail in your browser
当你使用浏览器访问 Gmail 时
and you are waiting and waiting and waiting in a new email comes in,
你一直在等待，直到新邮件到来，
what has happened?
发生了什么？
Tonight, for instance, open up the Inspector.
例如，今晚打开检查器。
Watch the Network tab.
查看网络选项卡。
And, odds are, every few seconds, every few minutes,
而且，很有可能，每隔几秒钟，每隔几分钟，
you'll see some kind of response coming from the server, maybe JSON, maybe
你会看到来自服务器的某种响应，可能是 JSON，可能是
some other format, containing your email,
其他格式，包含你的电子邮件，
including at least its subject line because that's
至少包括它的主题行，因为那是
what's adding more and more HTML to the browser.
不断向浏览器添加更多 HTML 的原因。
Indeed, if you open up the Elements tab and just watch it
实际上，如果你打开元素选项卡，然后一直观察，
in the most watching-paint-dry kind of situation,
就像看油漆干一样，
you'll see probably more and more emails appear in the underlying DOM
你会看到越来越多电子邮件出现在底层的 DOM（文档对象模型）中
or document object model inside of the browser.
或者说浏览器内部的文档对象模型。
So I can't stress enough that, even though we've
我再怎么强调也不为过，尽管我们已经
spent just a few weeks on SQL and the HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
只花了几个星期学习 SQL、HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript
and now Flask together, that is how the web works.
以及现在一起学习 Flask，但这正是网页的工作原理。
That is how all of today's modern apps work and, hopefully,
这就是今天所有现代应用程序的工作方式，希望
you too with your final projects.
你们的最终项目也能做到。
That's it for today.
今天就到这里了。
We will see you one last time next week for the end of CS50.
下周我们将最后一次见面，庆祝 CS50 的结束。
[APPLAUSE]
[鼓掌]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]